Chapter 469

“So this must be the place…”

After dumping off the wizard’s apprentice Zhang Dong finally arrived in the electrically charged dead zone. The area was quite intense, if he didn’t possess his current cultivation level he felt that his body would have been torn to shreds a long time ago. Even then he was not at the center part.

“This lightning energy is somewhat different…”

Thanks to his expertise he was able to distinguish everything that concerned the Dao of Lightning. His field was in heavenly lightning that was at a higher tier but this was something on par. As he recalled it was theorized that an immortal had ascended from the area which created this torrent of energy that was able to last through many thousands of years.

“This is a lot more than I expected…”

He had gone through absorbing a large lightning storm before in the other empire but this one was many times more chaotic. What he was looking at was a giant downpour of lightning bolts that almost made everything look like a constant blue pillar of light. The clouds producing this torrent of energy were in a constant state of movement, it looked as if a god was quickly stirring the heavens.

The more he approached this spot the larger the lightning rods became. Yet this spot was devoid of any as they had probably been melted by the sheer power of this lightning phenomenon above him. The earth beneath them was shiny and clear as all of the sand had been melted from getting constantly barraged by the electricity.

Laws of physics didn’t apply here, the air was filled with the Dao that his lightning core wanted to absorb. Even now when Zhang Dong was approaching towards the middle he could feel his core crying out for more energy. Luckily for once, it seemed that he would be able to progress with his cultivation of freedom.

This place was hazardous, without the lightning core that required a vast amount of energy he could perish. Even for him someone that was at the level of a nascent soul master at the pinnacle of their power this was not easy. Even now his body was constantly hit by bolts of blue energy.

Thus he advanced forward towards the center where the pillar of light was. The earth below was devoid of any life, the rocks that looked like a polished bronze mirror were reflecting all this blue light which made it look as if a large lake was underneath him.

‘T-this feels different…’

He had absorbed many energies with his other cores and even with this one yet this time he was experiencing a bottleneck. As soon as he entered the torrent of energy he attempted to open his lightning core to let the energy flow in. But to his surprise, it was having trouble dealing with all this energy that had a peculiar variation to it.

“ARGH…”

For the first time after attaining these three cores, he started feeling pain. It was similar to the moment he had achieved his breakthrough into the core formation stage yet the pain was even worse. It was as if his body was being torn away from within, his lightning core was unable to contain this energy fast enough.

‘Shit…’

Zhang Dong didn’t falter as he knew that any mistake could cause a cultivation backlash. He had already plunged himself into the torrent of energy so it was too late. Thus he quickly placed his hands together to form a makeshift triangle. While holding his palms this way he brought them towards his dantian where the entrance to his lightning core was.

With a large shout, he forced the chaotic torrent of energies towards his hands. Through them, he would slow down the invasion of these lightning energies and allow his core some breathing time. Yet this was a double-edged sword as while his core was able to absorb everything at a slower rate his hands were turning dark.

He was being injured yet he needed to continue. Even when his hands became pitch black he just forced his holy energy into them to boost his healing factor. What followed was a process of destruction of resurrection as his body started crumbling. This process brought massive amounts of discomfort onto him which was fed by the constant new waves of energy hitting his body.

However, as the process continued the lightning storm above him continued to get smaller. His sacrifice was paying off but his body was being torn apart. Without his holy energy that was able to mend him over and over, he would have already perished. This was truly a foolish way to cultivate and not something that anyone besides him could stomach.

Only a combination of his lightning core that could absorb vast quantities of lightning energy along with his enhanced refined body and his self-healing abilities were allowing him to last through this for so long. Yet he had to do it, to protect his family and friends he needed to sacrifice his body. The enemies he was going to face had not revealed themselves yet so if he could get any sort of advantage, he would do it.

The swirling clouds above became even more hectic and with them brought along an even harder downpour of energies. Yet he lasted through all of it, his lightning core slowly growing in size and soon enough reached the same size as its two counterparts.

With a last one thunderous roar that was followed by a giant explosion, the clouds were pushed to the side. The ever darkened lands that had not seen sunlight for many millennia were finally illuminated by the reddish hue of the rising sun.

What was left behind was a practically naked Zhang Dong that was left panting while slowly floating down to the ground. Even though the lightning storm was gone the energy that characterized it was still there. These blue arcs continued to slowly crackle all over the place while colliding with Zhang Dong’s injured body. Yet the more they hit it, the more they started to change from pale blue to deep gold.

“No rest for the righteous huh?”

He let out a sigh as he felt that his body was changing on the inside. All of the three cores had been satiated and it seemed that the time for another change was upon him. Normally what would happen was that the seed would absorb the energies from all the cores and grow larger yet this time around it was different.

A strange suction force was being exuded by this pea-sized seed. This gravitational pull was somehow forcing the three cores to come together, it was as if the seed wanted to either combine itself with them or absorb their power.

Zhang Dong found himself in unexplored territory that was not discussed in any cultivation book. His system would also not give him any answers, he could only rely on himself for answers.

‘Cultivation abnormality detected, some features of the system will be unavailable until the abnormality is eliminated.’

Bob his Ai gave him some bad news about his system bugging out again. This strange transformation halted some of its features that he wanted to activate. This of course was his teleportation feature that would allow him to flee this place if he needed to.

Thus it was finally time to push his cultivation into another direction, would this make him stronger or cripple him instead? He did not know but with his future in mind, he had to take that step when the chance was given to him.

If this was truly the next step and he was able to push himself towards an alternate nascent soul realm he might become an existence that could not be stopped. Yet this would probably bring out the hidden administrator of this world as it did in the other. But these thoughts that clouded his mind were quickly pushed to the side as he needed to focus.

The seed was demanding more energy but he theorized that he couldn’t just force it in. Perhaps if it was an emergency then he would need to force it but for the time being, he was alone here. Would that remain that way though? He had managed to evade being detected by the sect ruling these lands and the golden knights. But now after the storm had cleared up visitors were probably on the way.

This was somewhat according to his plans as he had calculated the distance to the closest settlement. After taking into consideration the speed of the average nascent soul master and flying ship he had about one or two days before someone arrived here. Perhaps longer if the sect decided to prepare a larger force so examine this case.

Even if that sect sent a few people they would probably leave him to his cultivation. Attacking monstrous cultivators while they were busy reaching another realm was a delicate endeavor. Some sects would attempt robbing this soon-to-be expert when they were vulnerable while others aided them in hopes of rewards.

When they saw him here they would probably not recognize him. To the natives gaining favor from an expert was important but robbing them was also a way to achieve greatness. That was the riskier move but he was in their territory which might push them towards that decision.

But what he feared more than the native sect were the golden knights he bumped into the day before. They would attack him the moment they saw him and would not think about it twice. Before they got here he needed to focus and get this over with as there was nowhere he could hide in this desolate area.

If he moved too much he risked failing his transformation process. Thus for the time being sitting down was the only option. He could only create a haphazard protective formation while he could still somewhat focus on the outside world. Without being able to teleport back to his sect to push through in freedom this was the only option he had left.

Thus he centered himself while focusing on the slowly growing seed inside of him. The closer the cores moved towards it the more it reacted. The process needed to be slowed down as another bout of chest pains was forced upon him. It was as if this world was trying to deny him from getting this seed to sprout.

But he continued on while in a state of disarray. Time began to pass and soon enough people appeared around him. Many curious gazes, some with malice mixed into them were appearing to watch the strange master go through with his advancement what would become of it, no one knew.

Chapter 470

“Elder, you have arrived!”

A small group of cultivators bowed their heads before a long-bearded man. All of them were wearing similar robes with a white dragon on their back. They were members of the Lightning Dragon Sect that kept order in these lands.

A day ago they had all witnessed a strange phenomenon. The large torrent of lightning energy that had existed before any of them had been born, was no more. It was an inhabitable land that none of them could visit so only when the spiritual energy faded did they start to notice.

While this area still had a lot of residual energy left, it was nothing they couldn’t handle. Even a foundation establishment cultivator would be able to walk into the center. This center all of them were looking at as there was someone there.

“Have you identified this cultivator?”

“We can only speculate, but there aren’t many masters that are able to control lightning to this extent, we fear that it might be the Emperor’s brother that has been seen active…”

“Long Dong? This complicates everything…”

The old man looked at the strange thing that was circulating at the spot where the energy pillar was. Instead of the pure lightning energy they were used to it was composed of some strange mixture.

The elder could detect the Dao of Lightning that he was a student of himself but it was a lot purer than he was used to. Then there was a radiant golden glow that was giving out a warm glow that was making his skin tingle. It was as if some of the old wounds that he had suffered through his five hundred years of battles were being slowly healed.

It was clearly the Dao of the divine yet there was a third energy that he could now decipher. It was not something he was familiar with but even when he couldn’t see it he could tell that it was there. It was pulling at his nascent soul as if wanting to absorb it.

“If this is truly the brother of the Azure Emperor then we can’t disturb his enlightenment yet if it is an enemy then…”

The Lightning Dragon Sect was not unaware of the strange happenings in their lands. People had been disappearing that were even nascent soul masters. These events were mostly accompanied by divine energy that was left behind at the scenes.

This aura here was similar, the person responsible for the disappearances could be the man before them. They had a chance to strike, during the period of cultivating a person would be unaware of their surroundings and unable to protect themselves. If they wished to strike this would be the best chance but it could cost them dearly if the person here was really related to the Azure Emperor.

“... Everyone spread out, we will create a protective array for the senior…”

Everyone else looked at each other and quickly nodded. All of them could feel that the person inside of that spiritual bubble was someone tremendous. Even being this close was making their own cultivations throb out of embarrassment. Striking the person in there could fail as the difference in powers was large and even if they failed in cultivating that wouldn’t mean that they would die on the spot.

Thus all of the people gathered here spread out in all directions. While they were missing the large torrent of lightning energy that was once here, it wasn’t all gone. It was as if the person here left some of it behind so that they could contemplate its Dao and get stronger.

This was actually a great boon for them as now they would be able to turn this into a cultivation spot where they could study the residual laws of this greater Dao. Previously the lightning torrents made the innermost lands inhabitable but now they would be able to expand. They knew that if they dug into the ground here they would be able to mine out various treasures as well.

The biggest reason for helping was as always self-interest. This elder was unsure of being able to contend with the being who was before him. Each time he tried to measure that area with his spiritual sense he couldn’t feel anything. It was as if the gap between him and the thing in there was inhumane. He could not see himself winning with that powerful being and this is why seeking favor with them instead was the most logical conclusion.

Soon more cultivators were pouring in, some were from the same lightning sect but others were just curious to see who was responsible for this spectacle. It was inconceivable to everyone here that someone was able to remove this lightning storm that plagued these lands for so long. Was there a trick involved or was the one responsible for it a master of never before seen proportions.

Yet while most that gathered here were waiting for the man in question to be done with their cultivation journey, there were a few others that didn’t belong. They were wearing golden suits of armor and riding on white horses with wings.

“Inform the Knight Commander, that we have found him.”

….

‘Almost there…’

Zhang Dong was floating up in the air while surrounded by a thick layer of his own three energies. At first, they were very chaotic but soon they began to slowly react with each other. It was as if the purpose of separating the three cores was to later bring them together and fuse them into one.

This was just the process he found himself in now as all three of his cores were slowly fusing with each other and the seed in the middle. The most difficult task was to keep everything at an equilibrium, whenever something was out of line a sharp pain would attack his body. Without his body refining at this level, he would have already failed but thanks to it he was allowed enough retries without his body crumbling into dust.

‘I can’t heal myself during this process but my guests don’t seem to be hostile, at least not for the time being.’

While he was concentrating on his development he had also noticed that he was surrounded by multiple unknown cultivators. He could only feel the ones that were the closest, some of them were nascent soul masters that should not pose a problem if he was in a rested state. If after this core fusion he would advance further or be tired was still unknown to him.

The ascension he was going through was unknown to him. His system could not even identify the name of it nor was it able to help him with its progress. This made him believe that it was an unknown variant that the person that created this system didn’t know about. Yet there could be another reason if the creator of the system did not want the system holders to know about it. Either way, if he managed to progress further and had to challenge this godly being then this unknown cultivation realm could be his only way of victory.

‘It’s almost there…’

Soon enough after a few failures, he had managed to stabilize all three cores that started to slowly fuse with the white seed in the middle. The first effect of this fusion was represented by the seed’s growth from something that was pea-sized into a walnut-size seed. Yet even with the size increase, there was something wrong, he did not feel that much of a power increase.

The seed had multiplied in size by quite a lot but his all-around spiritual energy reserves did not. Instead of this feeling like a proper large realm breakthrough, it felt like he had gone through a few years of training. But this wasn’t quite over as the seed started to change its color.

From a pale white into a deep blue and quickly into a transparent gold. It continued to switch between the coloring of his three previous cores until it settled on a yellowish pattern. This wasn’t all as from the top it started to slowly open up, perhaps when it sprouted the real realm shift would commence pushing him into a higher state of being.

However, instead of the expected change the seed never sprouted. Instead, little golden whips of light shot out from within and made its way towards his middle dantian. Through it, the small ball of light escaped and started increasing in size. At the same time, the energies that were surrounding his body exploded causing everything to be bathed in white.

On the outside, the cultivators had quite the scare as the person the phenomenon they were all watching violently exploded. The formation that Zhang Dong created himself took the brunt of the force but quickly exploded. A wave of spiritual energy was forced outside in all directions and towards the defensive array, the people from the other sect created.

Even though the blast had been lessened in its destructive force it still went through the barrier as if it was made from paper. The people that were sustaining it started coughing up blood while using all sorts of defensive talismans to save their life.

But just as soon as this devastating wave of spiritual energy traveled through everything leaving injured in its wake, their misery was short-lived. A warm glow appeared soon after that quickly cured everyone’s wounds. This glow was accompanied by a strange low pitched roar that sounded like some kind of powerful beast.

“W-what is that?”

“It really is the Golden Dragon!”

“It is… but what is that strange small creature next to him?”

‘Strange small creature?’

Zhang Dong had to take a moment to gather himself. When looking inside of his spiritual sea he could see the enlarged seed that looked as if it was about to sprout into something. Yet it still didn’t, it looked like it was frozen in time. Even with the cores now gone, he could still feel all three of the energies pulsating from the seed but the progress was halted.

Now the other peculiar thing was that light that shot out. At first, he didn’t notice it but there was something familiar about that small light. When he opened his eyes he was surprised to see a somewhat familiar-looking creature before him. The first noticeable thing about it was the golden pattern to its scales and the two wings it was using to keep itself afloat.

“Are you… my soul beast?... but why do you look like that?”

“Purrr!”

What he was seeing was a rather cute baby dragon that was about the size of a large dog. It was floating around him while making cute sounds. It looked like a smaller version of the golden dragon that was once his soul beast. But there was something different about it, the connection was different. Instead of it being part of his soul it felt like a separate being with a similar energy as his, as if it was made from his soul but not part of it.

‘Interesting…’

Zhang Dong placed his hand on the creature's head. The cute dragon baby reacted by fluttering its wings and purring like a cat. While his cultivation breakthrough didn’t go as planned he had gained something else, his soul beast had returned and the spiritual energy that was coming from it was not low at all.

Chapter 471

‘Familiar existence detected, please give the familiar a name.’

“A familiar?”

Zhang Dong was now looking at something that reminded him of his old soul beast. But instead of the giant dragon that he could use to blast everyone to kingdom come there was a small baby dragon.

“You want me to give this guy a name Bob?... Well, it is a dragon… So how about Bahamut?”

His soul beast was a part of him, even when he gave it pet names then it was a bit silly. The creature was like a third hand that he could use without even talking but this one was different. While there was a connection between their souls he knew that this being was a separate entity. He could not tell what it was thinking as he could with the previous one.

Name:

|

Bahamut [ Sealed ]

Type:

|

Heavenly Golden Dragon [ Legendary ]

Realm:

|

!@$DSF#%

The first thing that he noticed was the legendary status of his familiar. It was as if he was some kind of monster tamer. This creature even had a spot for its power level but it was giving him the strange error text that was the same when he tried to examine his own realm.

“Perhaps it's the same realm as me? But what is this sealed status?”

When looking at this small dragon that was strangely purring at him he frowned. His old soul beast felt a lot stronger than this child but perhaps it was because of this sealed status. Would it show him its true might when it became unsealed? Could he order it to do it right here or was there some special requirement.

“Is this a list of attacks? But why are they grayed out?”

Golden Breath

|

Holy-based dragon breath known to burn through any evil creatures.

Golden Magma Burst

|

A massive surge of holy magma.

Divine Barrier

|

A barrier of holy light that can protect its user from attacks, can protect from many status alignments.

He read through the first few before stopping as this list continued for a while. It didn’t seem like a low leveled monster would possess this many attacks right after birth. Some of them sounded like the old attacks of his soul beast but there were some new ones. Most of them were grayed out which he could only attribute to the sealed status or to this dragon just being born.

‘So instead of getting a power increase, I got this little guy?’

When looking at the cute creature he was not sure what he should feel. Would it be able to contend with tougher opponents or would it be one-shotted? There was also no way of knowing what would happen if it died. His old soul beast could be regenerated as long as he retained his own nascent soul. This dragon on the other hand had his own working soul that was very similar to his own.

‘I guess I might have to find out soon…’

The people that were looking at him from afar didn’t go unnoticed. While most of the cultivators were blasted into the distance after he was finished with absorbing the lightning energy there were ones that didn’t. Even from his location, he could see that they belonged to the people he escaped from.

Now here came the problem, when he was absorbing his cores he had used up quite a large chunk of his system’s spirit points. He had gone through most of his spirit point reserves as he hoped to reach a higher form of existence. Yet his plans didn’t work out as instead of a large power-up he was given this dragon instead.

‘If I flee will they leave these people alone, probably not…’

Then there was the problem with hundreds of cultivators coming to this place to watch him. Now they put themselves between ten powerful holy knights and one somewhat tired Zhang Dong. The knights had clearly waited for everyone to gather as he could feel all of them approaching from all sides, their intent probably to kill him along with everyone that was here.

‘Hey Bob, is the system bugging out on me again?’

‘Multiple system failures, please wait.’

He was not sure what was happening but ever since returning to this world his system was not working as well as it did. Even now if he gathered enough spirit points teleporting away would probably be impossible, which left him with either staying or bolting it towards another hiding place. Perhaps after some time passed Bob would be able to fix everything to allow him to port back to his sect where he could evaluate his cultivation in peace.

“GRRRRrrr”

“You can sense them too?”

Zhang Dong looked at his small dragon that started growling in the direction that the most powerful enemy was coming from. It was Lucius that after their little exchange he placed slightly above the horned tribe demons he had faced before. Yet together with the nine other golden nights, he was far more dangerous.

Even now he wasn’t sure if he would come out victorious if he faced all of them. The only reason he managed to get away was thanks to his teleportation feature. His enemies did not show their true strength either. He was lucky enough to be in their camp where they probably didn’t want to be destroyed along with the many silver knights there. Now on the other hand in this desolate land that was devoid of life they could let loose.

“There you are, treacherous cur!”

They were like a blazing star, their speed was truly tremendous and they were coming right for him. A decision had to be made, would he run away in hopes of his system springing back to life or would he face these ten knights here. After the transformation, he felt slightly stronger but also drained.

Then there was the whole problem with him not having any more core formation cores. During his travels, he was absorbing energy left and right with them but now he felt full. The larger seed didn’t seem like it would be able to take in more energy which required further examination.

‘ probably won’t be able to absorb their holy attacks like before, I have to actually beat them the hard way now and then there is this guy..’

Bahamut that had been named was floating around him while looking towards Lucius that was on a collision course. If his new pet just died after being born then he would be a laughing stock to any cultivator. How could he have gone through all of this trouble to have this familiar of him get killed. The small dragon didn’t look like it could take even one hit, its wings were small and its head was large.

“I guess running is the only option, unless I figure out how to make you bigger you’ll just get in the way.”

Zhang Dong commented while reaching out towards this small creature. Yet as he was about to grab it and make a run for it there was a change. For some reason, the familiar reacted to his words and started glowing. Its body started giving out a radiant glow that started expanding in all directions and finally created the shape of an egg.

The golden knights that were charging toward him like jet planes quickly evaded to the sides. This golden egg was clearly radiating massive amounts of spiritual energy that were not much lower than Zhang Dong’s.

‘Wait, is he evolving already?’

Without Zhang Dong’s input, the egg started to hatch. First, a small crack formed at the top, it was followed by a loud cracking sound that caused the ground to shake. Soon a large four-digit lizard-like hand burst through the top of it. The shell of this giant egg started to crumble quickly yet the parts when touching the air burst into tiny energy bubbles.

From within the egg emerged an adult dragon that was practically identical to the old soul beast that Zhang Dong was using. The biggest difference was the amount of energy this monster was radiant that was even above a great circle nascent soul master.

“They should grow quickly… but he is a bit smaller than my old soul beast.”

The previous golden dragon could reach truly tremendous sizes. This Behemoth on the other hand didn’t go over fifty meters in length. While everyone else was stunned by the emergence of this golden dragon, his master floated onto his head.

“Well, I guess this equals things out…”

The mounts that the golden knights had were the most problematic part of their strength. Their speed was slightly above his and when they came from all sides he had no chance to counterattack. Now on the other hand he had gained his own mount and it seemed Bahamut was ready to eat some ponies.

While he could not directly control his new familiar there was a sort of connection between their souls. Bahamut could tell what Zhang Dong wanted him to do and without waiting for a spoken command it opened its large toothy mouth. Within a matter of seconds, a burst of golden flames showered the incoming knights that were forced to quickly dodge in various directions.

This large breath attack would normally open the dragon to a counterattack as its enemies were much smaller and quite agile. Regretfully for them, Bahamut was not the only one there, Zhang Dong was standing on its back and quickly followed up with his own finger arts that shot out many tiny beams of energy towards the knights that attempted to attack some of the blind zones.

“Everyone quickly flee!”

The huge dragon took off which produced a stormy wind. All the cultivators that were here quickly began to flee as they noticed that a battle between powerful beings was taking place. Some of them remained even when risking their own death. To them, the sight of the huge dragon batting away winged horses was something legendary. They could not pass up the chance of seeing this all play out.

Yet this would also cause their deaths as the parties that were fighting did not pull any punches with each other. The chaotic burst of various glowing projectiles rained down on these empty lands which the ones that weren’t able to escape would call their resting place.

“So even after consulting with Argus you still wish to kill me?”

“Shut up barbarian, I don’t know what you and that wizard talked about but you are too much of a threat to be left alive! Braves to me, together we will eradicate this monster from the face of this world!”

“Hah, you really want to paint me as the bad guy here, don’t you? Have it your way then!”
On one side was a man with his dragon on the other a small group of golden knights. Both of them started charging up for the next large attack and when they clashed everything would be turned to cinders.

Chapter 472

A clash of unprecedented proportions was taking place above this once desolate land of lightning. The once cloudy sky above was pushed back by the shockwaves that reached all up towards the earth below. With each wave of energy, the once mirror-like ground started to crack until it finally shattered into many smaller stones.

“We must escape!”

“Don’t get caught in the fight, flee!”

At first, the onlookers remained in place, for them, it was a chance to see two strong parties fight each other. Soon after the clash started they realized that a mistake was made. They didn’t know what was worse, the huge golden dragon that could melt them with one breath or the mounted knights that could compete with it.

‘Some idiots have stayed behind but that’s not my problem anymore.’

Zhang Dong was riding on his new dragon companion that he named Bahamut. The experience was not the same as with his soul beast. This being was not a part of him as the soul beast before it. Bahamut was a sentient creature with its own thought pattern. Its soul was very similar to Zhang Dong’s but he could not control the familiar directly.

This made the battle a bit harder at the start but slowly he was getting used to his new companion. While there were cons to Bahamut not being his soul beast as he could not direct it personally, there were some pros as well. The main reason was that he didn’t need to concentrate on giving orders, it just reacted of its own accord.

The original soul beast was still a part of him and there was always a little pause before it carried out orders. This delay was minuscule but during combat could cost the cultivator dearly. The user always had to concentrate at least a bit to control their soul beast to do their biddings which could affect their own response times. Now without that problem, he could fully concentrate on the battle without spreading his mind thin.

It took the two a bit of time to click at first but the longer the battle continued the easier it was to foresee what their partner would do. Probably after a few more fights Zhang Dong and Bahamut could iron things out but for now, they would probably need to approach things a bit more independently.

“Hey partner, can you take care of those guys while I go for the leader?”

Bahamut roared out in anticipation while glowing in bright golden light. In a fraction of a second many bolts of energy appeared around his body that quickly rocketed towards the mounted knights. They were like heat-seeking missiles but much faster, their flight paths were erratic and seemingly random which caused the targets to spread apart.

Zhang Dong used this chance to push himself off his dragon. While occupying his back gave him free rein to fire of ranged techniques as well, it was not getting him anywhere. The opponents were far too fast if this battle continued like this his spiritual energy would be drained fast. Thus he needed to bring the knight commander down towards the ground where he could face him in a more direct battle.

With so many of them buzzing around like flies around them this was a hard task. It was clear that these knights had fought in a group for a long time. Whenever one was in a bad position there was another to help them out, only if he could block part of that teamwork would he be victorious.

Even now with so many golden projectiles flying around towards everyone they were keeping each other safe. If one was in danger of getting his then another swooped in with a glowing shield of light to repel the projectile. But there still remained some space to improve, these people were not without fault and some openings were there.

There was a difference in power between the knight commander Lucius and the rest. Which made them easier targets for Zhang Dong. Thus instead of doing the obvious thing and going for their leader, he propelled himself towards one that was defending a stray golden bolt from Bahamut.

“I have you…”

Zhang Dong shouted while holding a white sword above his head. The timing was calculated in his brain to hit the man from behind when the rest were busy with their own evasive maneuvers. None of the nine would be able to react in time but there was one that could and this was what he was aiming for.

On his steed, Lucius appeared from Zhang Dong’s left flank. The knight commander had a long silver spear in his hand and a shield in the other. It was radiating massive amounts of energy and if it actually landed Zhang Dong would be pierced through. Even his body refining would not be able to take this attack without receiving any damage.

But he observed his enemies for a long time to plan this clash out. The position that Lucius would be forced to take was one of them. As the lance of light drilled towards him instead of attacking the other gold knight, he turned to face the charge.

With a quick shift of his body, he evaded a hit towards his torso. This made the attack graze his right side on which he was already clamping down with his arm. This arm quickly clamped down on this spear that was only able to slide in halfway before coming to an abrupt stop.

“Urgh…”

Pain was felt by him, this holy based attack was not something he could just shrug off. His whole right side was on fire as his robe was ripped apart and flesh was scraped. Without his core formation cores, he was unable to just absorb these energy attacks anymore but he did gain some strength in return.

Lucius clearly was not prepared for the abrupt stop in mid-air and neither was his mount. The arm he was holding the spear with was jolted back and almost instantly dislocated. While the knight on top of the horse was pushed back the horse he was sitting on flew further. Finally, after sacrificing some of his flesh he was successful in dismounting this man.

Yet even with a dislocated shoulder, the knight continued to hold onto his weapon. This allowed Zhang Dong to chuck it towards the ground along with the man holding onto it. Lucius shouted out some profanities while being forced off his horse but was unable to call it back. The moment the pegasus attempted to go back to its master it made contact with some dragon claws.

“That’s it, keep them busy.”

Zhang Dong on the other hand had been assaulted by a few other knights but was quick to evade their now more obvious flight patterns. While they were fast there was a limit to what they could do while riding large flying horses and throwing spears of light at him.

“Protect the commander!”

“How about you worry about yourself first.”

While Lucius was recovering in mid-air his men panicked. They clearly never saw their strongest warrior ever being forcibly dismounted like this. Thanks to this they were open to some well-placed kicks and palm attacks that Zhang Dong unloaded on them while also descending toward his intended target.

“Don’t worry about me, I am more than enough to defeat this savage.”

Lucius on the other hand was still confident in his victory. Even though his horse was unable to come back to him, this didn’t mean that he was unable to fly. Just like the other golden knights, he was able to produce wings of light to allow him flight. There was a small change though as this man actually had double the number.

“Four wings huh? I guess you aren’t the leader for nothing but maybe if you listened we could still resolve this without anyone getting hurt.”

“Silence you swine, that Wizard might have believed your lies but I won’t.”

After popping his hand back into place Lucius’ lance started shifting in shape. It was replaced by a legendary-looking sword that could only belong to a paladin. With the sword in his right hand and a glorious-looking kite shield in his left the man charged. The ensuing clash between the two holy energy users caused a resounding explosion.

They were finally embroiled in a proper one-on-one battle. On one side was Zhang Dong using a very attack-heavy twin sword stance. On the other side, Lucius with his shield was very hard to damage. Even when the flurry of fast attacks came his way, he could just turtle up to take them. Just as fast as the clash started it was over and the two enemies flew past each other to land on the ground below.

“Not bad for a posh little prince.”
“Hmph.”

Zhang Dong’s landing was accompanied by a large crater that blew up some dust. Even though he taunted his opponent his words didn’t seem to go through. While this man seemed to be a spoiled brat he knew how to fight. Any attempts to shake his concentration, make him rage out, and seize victory after he made more mistakes didn’t bore any fruit.

“I guess trash-talking won’t work on you but… I won’t need something like that to win this fight. If you don’t want to see reason then I can only answer you with violence.”

For a moment he had believed that there might still be a chance to work together. Yet the man was proving himself to be very stern, he clearly did not believe that this savage could offer him anything of worth. Zhang Dong was holding himself back slightly but now was the time to let loose.

Thus he called upon his swordsmanship, his opponent was not someone he could defeat by large-scale attacks. Instead, he would only utilize his sword arm to outperform his opponent. His aim would be the left side that Lucius was protecting with his shield. He would slice it apart with all of his might before the counter came.

Zhang Dong dropped the sword that he was holding in his left hand. When the weapon was free it turned into a myriad of glowing lights that combined themselves with the sword in his right palm. This sword he held above his head in a cleaving position that was quite easy to read.

“I’m sorry but I can’t afford to lose here, there are too many people at stake.”

“...”

His opponent didn’t reply, he was also a seasoned warrior and he knew that something big was coming. Time seemed like it stopped for the two warriors, they just looked into each other's eyes as if for an eternity.

Soon the sword started falling without making a sound. It was as if the air around them was being split apart as the attack took shape and the two clashed with each other for one last time. Would the sword split apart the shield along with the person behind it, or would it fail to give the knight a great chance to plunge their weapon into his opponent's chest? No one knew but the exchange would be decided in a fraction of a second…

Chapter 473

“I must give it to you, I didn’t think you would still be standing after that one, but…”

Zhang Dong rubbed his neck where he was grazed by the enemy's longsword. The gash was quite deep but not something deadly for a cultivator like him that defied human physiology. While his wound was now healing at a rapid rate the one he delivered to the knight commander was not.

The man was surrounded by magic armor and various relics of power. He was not naturally resistant to damage, if the magic behind his items was broken he was at around the level of an early foundation establishment practitioner. This was already above the other golden knights but at a large disadvantage when going against Zhang Dong.

By how one achieved victory in the high leveled battles in this world was not really by causing injuries to the flesh. Instead, it was by inserting a large amount of spiritual energy or mana into that wound to not allow it to heal itself. Lucius’ body was now being invaded by Zhang Dong’s Qi that was ripping it apart. The difference between was too high for the man to be able to contend with it after it got past the armor, the battle was over.

“No, this is impossible, h-how could I lose to a barbarian…”

Lucius’ shield had been slashed in half along with his upper chest that was behind it. The wound was radiating golden energy that did not belong to the knight but to his adversary Zhang Dong. It was slowly eating away at his vitality and soon the man would succumb to this wound.

“Perhaps if you listened to your Wizard friend you would have survived.”

He started approaching his enemy that was trying to stand up. His legs were shaking, the body and magical energy the man was so proud of was not helping him out. Even when he tried to activate his damaged armor it was not able to dispel this spiritual energy that was of a higher caliber.

“N-no this can’t end like this, I need to complete my mission… e-everyone is waiting for me…”

The man soon collapsed on the ground while speaking out loudly. At first, Zhang Dong thought that Lucius would just continue to lash out at him but instead, he started talking about his own kingdom. It seemed that he also had people that he wanted to protect and that were waiting for him back home.

“C-celestine…”

This name was unknown to him, perhaps it was his beloved or child. It did not bring joy to Zhang Dong to kill this man but it was a war that they decided to go through with. Perhaps if the times were different he could afford to let this man go but as it stood he was too dangerous. If he recovered many more people would die, the only thing he could not do was to send this warrior off to the great beyond.

Thus he approached him with his sword raised in the air. The energies that he inserted into the wound would keep eating away at the man’s vitality for a while. His death would be long and painful as his body fought to stay alive.

“Commander!”

“GUOHhhh!”

The cavalry in the background was shaken by what they had witnessed. Even when their commander was tossed from his horse no one expected him to lose so quickly. They expected him to at most be equally challenged with the savage he was fighting. Instead after one fast exchange, it was already over and he was slowly fading away.

All of them started panicking as they threw themselves toward the ground. Even with the large dragon in their way they wanted to risk being injured to help their leader. Bahamut wouldn’t let them as he was adept at large-scaled energy attacks and was able to stall them long enough for his master to deliver the finishing blow.

Yet the master in question was hesitating, his sword arm was already raised. He only needed to quickly slice downward to finish what he started but he was hesitating. The shouts of the men behind him combined with the last words Lucius was spouting was making this difficult.

This was not the same as killing one of the evil cultivators that never showed any remorse. But he had no choice, just as he tried to shape this world into what he believed was right, so was this world doing the same to him. The man that didn’t take lives was being drowned out the longer he continued to battle for his sect and family.

“I wish there was another way but you left me no choice…”

Finally, the decision was made, the time his familiar gave him was up and the other knights were getting closer. If he didn’t deliver the final blow the difficult enemy that was standing in his way could escape. With how good these people were at long-range teleportation he would probably not be able to chase after them, he needed to act now.

With his mind made up, he went for the kill, at least he could give his enemy a swift death. However, as his sword was ready to go for the kill he noticed something.

“Please I beg you, stop!”

“Everyone stop, if you move a muscle your commander will die instantly…”

Instead of decapitating the man, his blade halted against his neck. Some of the other knights had managed to get past his dragon but when they saw the blade at Lucius’ neck they instantly stopped. In front of him appeared an illusory image of the Wizard’s head, it was clearly a long-ranged spell that was being performed.

“What do you want Argus, I gave this man a chance but he refused…”

“I am aware of that but if you kill him now there will never be a chance for a peaceful resolution. Unless we foster good relations now it will be too late to go back! I implore you, I can see that you are a good man, let this not be the beginning of the end.”

Argus continued to shout while focusing on Zhang Dong’s good-natured self. It was true that if he could then this type of act would be below him. Killing was not something that he enjoyed and he had tried to convince the other cultivators that there were other ways.

“Hm…Celestine was it, is that your wife? Fiance maybe?”

“Ugh…F-fiance…”

Zhang Dong asked Lucius’ that was fading in and out of consciousness. The sword of his remained at the man’s neck for a while before he finally pulled it back.

“Tell your fiance that she saved your life on this day.”

This man had been through many things to arrive at this moment. He had others that he cherished and even people like this Argus here were willing to speak up for him. Would he be any different than the other power-hungry people if he killed him here? Perhaps he would regret this decision down the line, but what if there really was a way to go around this problem from another angle.

Lucius was taken aback by the sword being pulled back, even Argus that had come in the form of an illusion was surprised that Zhang Dong listened to his words. He did not know that the silver-haired cultivator was already on the fence here. With a little shove in the right direction, he was more than willing to spare the life of this man.

Thus after the sword was gone what only remained was to tap Lucius on the forehead to remove his Qi from the wound. Instead, he even caused it to heal up enough for the knight commander to stand up. Without knowing what was going on the golden knight quickly jumped back while examining his chest wound that was now being slowly healed up.

“Why did you…”

“What do you mean, didn’t you hear the old man’s monologue?”

Zhang Dong pointed towards Argus that was floating to the side.

“I told you that this man was not our enemy but an ally, I hope this is enough for you to understand Lord Lucius.”

He nodded while the two continued to converse but as he expected a problem arose. Four of the nine knights had managed to appear around them and the other five weren’t far behind. The technique he used took out a lot from him, the large chasm that was created behind them was the proof. He had put everything into the attack to finish the fight early and if this continued further he would probably not be able to recreate the clash.

“No, this must be some kind of trick…”

“What trick? Do you think I wasted my chance to kill you just for some grander con? Don’t flatter yourself, the only reason you are alive is that I do not wish this war to continue. Do you really want us to go at each other as mindless berserkers? Who is the savage here now?”

Lucius had taken the sword back into his hand but even he started thinking hard. Zhang Dong had won the exchange, there was no reason for him to be alive now. It made no sense to this knight commander to leave an enemy alive that is unless he really wanted a less bloody resolution. The possibility of this being a trick was there but it would be immensely hard to pull off.

“Lord Lucius!”

The knights jumped off their horses while switching from lances to longswords. They were clearly not thinking about ending this battle just yet. Probably if their leader decided to continue with the struggle they would.

“Put your swords away.”

“Commander?”

“I will not repeat myself, do as you were ordered.”

“Yes, my lord.”

Surprisingly Lucius decided to stop, he even put his holy sword away into its sheath while ordering everyone to stand down. The knights were confused at first but after hearing the stern words they were quick to back away.

“Behemoth you too, come back.”

It seemed that the situation was being resolved, without a need to battle the knights in the air the large dragon returned to its master. The large form turned into many tiny bubbles of holy energy as it transformed into the small cute baby version instead. Soon both parties were facing each other with the wizard’s illusion being in the middle.

“Do you trust this man Argus?”

“I do my lord, I’m sure you can feel it too.”

Holy energy was a measure of divinity in this world and also for righteousness. There was no one above Zhang Dong when it came to this type of energy. The proof was before him and his actions also showed them that he was willing to talk. Now it was up to his diplomatic skills again to see if he could convince this thickheaded knight that they could work together.

Chapter 474

“Well then, I will excuse myself please keep your promise and I will keep mine.”

Zhang Dong was looking at Lucius, who had somewhat changed his tune. After having a life and death experience where he recalled a loved one he finally understood that perhaps rushing towards his death might not have been the wisest option. The man seemed to have a superiority complex that was shattered by Zhang Dong’s might but luckily he was taking it well.

After the battle was over Zhang Dong along with Argus and Lucius had a little talk. With a ceasefire being agreed on they could discuss future actions. His biggest victory was that they agreed to cease their further invasion for a month. This would give him some time to gather information about this Lightbringer.

While it was good that he managed to even bargain up for a month, it didn’t give him much time to search for it. This Empire was huge and if he traveled by flight it would take him days or weeks to travel between some locations. The month wasn’t much but it was a start, it would probably save a few lives of the cultivators that valued their honor above their own wellbeing.

“I must thank you.”

Argus bowed before him while his illusory figure started to vanish.

“It’s fine, just keep your word.”

“A knight always keeps their word!”

Lucius on the other hand didn’t have a very pleased look on his face. Losing to someone in battle was probably not something he was used to. Zhang Dong would not be surprised if this was the first time he lost to his peer. Luckily the man wanted to live and seemed grateful that he didn’t get his head chopped off.

‘I’m sure that he still thinks that I’m screwing with them.”

The trust between these two parties was very shaky. The only thing they could go off is him sparing the life of an enemy. But sparking or helping your enemy was a basic tactic of subterfuge. In their eyes, he could have just been aiming for a better opportunity to get into their stronghold.

This was the more believable option. They might even be expecting him to try teleporting his forces inside of their side if he was ever able to visit it. Thus he would need to converse with them at a distance, how long he could keep them from attacking the empire sects was debatable but there was also another option.

‘The Emerald Phoenix Empire should have their citadel north of where these guys are situated, perhaps they could aid us with them…’

The area was attacked from all sides but this didn’t mean that all the people coming here were on the same side. The Emerald Phoenix Empire and the Kingdom of Avalon didn’t have anything in common. If they met each other out in the open they would probably start battling which would help his cause immensely.

‘Should I lie and tell them that the Emerald Phoenix Empire has the Lightbringer?’

If he went with this option then he would be risking future peace. If the magical kingdom actually discovered the true location of their legendary sword they would feel used. They would probably resume their invasion once more and any future diplomatic talks would be impossible.

‘Would be nice if those guys actually had it, first I have to find it, and then I’ll make the decision.’

“How about you Bahamut, got any ideas?”

“GAO!”

“Is that so?”

While the small baby dragon didn’t know how to speak, his master somewhat knew what it wanted to tell him. The cute little sound it gave out was a resounding ‘No’. The fight was now over but the war was still continuing. He had made some new acquaintances that he was not sure about. Argus seemed like someone willing to communicate but it could also be a ruse.

Perhaps he only did it to help out Lucius and get more information about the sword. Then when Zhang Dong delivered the item or information about it he would be disposed of. Probably the next clash between him and the Knight Commander would go differently. Now he knew that he could not use that shield to block everything so he would alter his battle tactics.

‘I furthered my cultivation and got them to back off, for the time being, this does seem like a victory but will this be enough.’

Zhang Dong poked the seed inside of him with his spiritual sense. The thing didn’t seem to want to open itself up. Without his core formation cores now he was not sure what this realm could be called.

‘The seed realm? What will this seed turn into, a tree? Perhaps a flower?’

He was missing something and his system could not identify what he was transforming into. Feeding the seed spiritual energy through it was still possible but it would probably be a tremendous amount. This seed was composed of three Dao’s that he specialized in now, perhaps this was the true method of getting it to sprout.

‘Do I need to reach a higher understanding in the Dao of Heavenly Lightning, Holy Divinity, and Soul energy for it to react? Or perhaps combine the three into something instead?’
There were a few possibilities floating around his mind which leaned towards those two answers. The seed was filled with a lot of energy that just needed to be released. It wasn’t opening up because he didn’t understand what it fully was.

Getting enlightened would probably be the way out but for someone like him who once heavily relied on the system, this was no easy matter. There was no spirit point counter that he could just farm away and press a button. Everything was more vague and the roads led in many directions. It was no wonder why people spent hundreds of years cultivating as the guidelines were nonexistent.

‘If I had time I would lock myself in my cultivation chamber but I need to find clues regarding this Holy sword’

With that in mind, Zhang Dong opened up his system window to contact Zhang Kuo. His retainer would be tasked to use their spy network and find if there were any mentions of any holy blades.

“Yeah, anything related to holy swords of divine power… they could be sealed away, check out old legends that could be hundreds of thousands of years old. This blade should be on the level of a half step immortal or pinnacle heaven grade.”

“Yes Patriarch, it shall be done!”

Was the usual reply that he got but to his surprise, there was a question posed.

“Patriarch… if I may…”

“Speak.”

Zhang Dong replied while wondering what this was about. Normally all cultivators shied away from asking him questions as the social hierarchy was still something very real.

“T-the Matriarch has been asking for you…”

“Oh, she did?...”

“Yes, will you be returning to the sect soon?”

“Uh, I don’t think I will, for now, I need to find this old relic within the month, I’m not sure how long this will take but I’ll probably visit the Long Clan to check for some clues.”

“The Long Clan? … Could this Zhang Kuo make a proposal?”

Kuo asked the strange question that caught him from a leftfield. For some reason, the man was very chatty today. Was his wife causing trouble in the sect or something?

“Go ahead?”

“Then I would propose that you bring the Matriarch along, this will foster good relations with the Azure Emperor!”

“Good relations?”

Zhang Dong had to think, most of the time he just popped in and out of the Long Clan without talking to anyone. His standing there was quite shaky as the only person that he had a good relationship with was the Emperor himself. This was probably the only one he cared about besides the Queen that he might be inclined to get closer to as she did sway his brother’s decisions.

“Would she be willing to leave though, I’m not sure if…”

“She would be my lord and letting the young master and mistress meet the Emperor’s family would be a show of goodwill!”

“I see…”

Kou really seemed to want to get Liana out of the sect ground. But it would show that he trusted the Emperor if he actually brought along his kids for a visit. It would bring the two families together and perhaps the Emperor’s children whom he had ‘bonded’ with would like his own kids.

If they didn’t he could always give them a few smacks and with enough system points, he could always just teleport out of there if there was anything suspicious going on. Yet the capital city was probably the safest location in the entire Empire. It was protected from all sides and the Long Clan had many nascent soul masters patrolling the area.

Even the other empires would not be able to invade without sustaining many losses. The floating castle also could probably change locations at will. It was a safe zone that survived even through the previous war. He believed that it was something that the system wanted to keep even if all the other lands were destroyed.

“But wouldn’t the preparations take a few weeks? I’m not sure I have the time to wait…”

“Give me three… no two days Patriarch! With access to the Empire’s teleportation gates, we can transport a small force!”

“Ah… sure, then I’ll ask my wife if she agrees?”

“Don’t worry Patriarch, I already had my people do it, she is already getting ready for the trip!”

“Oh…”

Finally, the call ended while he was left in the desolate lands alone. For some reason, he had a suspicion that this was not Kuo’s plan and that someone was forcing him to ask about this visit. The only three people that would probably dare something like this were his grandfather and his wife. Huo Qiang was the last one but he didn’t really care about these type of things so it was between those two.

‘Big family get together huh?’

He could only recall things from his old life where he was dragged by his parents to visit. Most of the time he was left alone in the corner just hoping that he could leave after eating his share. Fostering relations with his new family would be beneficial to both sides. With how he dealt with the vampires and the golden knights he had some time to relax.

‘I guess now I don’t need to think about an excuse to meet my brother, I’ll ask him about the Lightbringer when we get there.’

With that thought in his mind, he decided to visit the nearby sect. There he would ask for some information about the relic before going back towards another location. While everyone prepared he would use the time to gather more intel and perhaps with some luck he could get the magical knights on his side.

Chapter 475

“Isn’t this thing a bit too tight?”

“Have you gained some weight, it should fit you perfectly…”

“Well, I did get a bit stronger…”

Zhang Dong lifted up his arm to flex his biceps, the moment he did he could feel the ceremonial Patriarch robe he was wearing being strained. Soon enough the fabric not meant for battle gave out and ripped as it was not able to contain his well-built physique. After the seed had been formed his body had been reinforced and along with leveling up his body refinement he found himself being more of a beefcake.

“Haha, daddy is being silly.”

“Who is being silly now?”

While he was looking at the torn biceps part of his robe his daughter jumped at his arm. She started hanging off it like a little monkey while he started to swing it around. While this was happening his son started posing just like his dad but pouted after seeing the lack of muscles on his own arms.

“Don’t worry Jun’er if you continue to train and eat your spirit vegetables you will be just like your daddy in no time.”

“Do I have to eat those… can’t I just eat the spirit fruit instead… it tastes better.”

“Hah.”

Zhang Dong laughed while his personal maids started panicking. Soon he had taken off the robe that he was wearing so that they could fix it up. His wife moved over to place her hands on his chest as she was the one that gave the tailor his measurements while he was out adventuring.

“If you get much bigger you’ll start looking like that red monkey.”

“You two need to start getting along…”

While his physique did progress slightly he wasn’t as large as Huo Qiang. It was more of an optimal look that took speed and physical strength into consideration, an all-around good body.

“and even when you say that…”

It did not go unnoticed that after he had disrobed and was now just standing around with a bare chest and his pants on, Liena was sticking close to him. The way her delicate fingers felt on his skin were making him feel all tingly inside. If his kids weren’t in his room he would have probably tackled her down to the ground already.

This was not the time for that as they were getting ready to visit their other part of the family at the Azure Empire capital. While he was not that bothered by the visit the people that were coming with him were on the edge. Just as Zhang Kuo proposed he would be taking his kids there as a show of faith but there were many other people coming with them too.

One of these people was Zhang Jin, his grandfather. Normally the old perverted man was always eager to visit new places where potential beauties were located. Now on the other hand he was nervous as they were going to the very top of the empire. Zhang Jin was an old cultivator that had the empire's hierarchy drilled into his bones.

It was unfathomable that he could meet the emperor in his lifetime. At this very moment, he was pacing back and forth while mumbling something. His wives were also a problem with so many he couldn’t take them all and if one came then the rest would feel disgruntled.

“Should I perform a full bow or just clasp my hands? The emperor is my senior but he is also Dong’er older brother… Does that make me his grandfather?”

Zhang Dong was sure that his link to Long Qing the Azure Emperor was artificially produced by the system. Yet from the standpoint of the denizens of this world there had to be a bloodline connection. This was made by someone he was related to and Zhang Jin that spread his seed around the world was the most probable cause.

“Stop yapping you old fart just don’t cause any trouble, if you run into some old crush don’t cause any trouble.”

“Trouble, me? I never cause any trouble… but uh Dong’er.”

“What? Stop looking at me like that.”

“If perchance… only theoretically I do meet an old acquaintance… you will protect your lovable grandfather, won’t you?”

Zhang Jin looked at Zhang Dong with puppy dog eyes which made him recoil in disgust. There actually could be a woman that he had a fling with that might harbor some malice towards him. Her causing trouble was probably not something probable as Zhang Jin was still the Golden Dragon’s grandfather. He did not think the Long Clan would seek trouble with him after all this time.

“Well as long as that theoretical acquaintance doesn’t kill my lovable grandfather then it should be alright? I’m sure you’ll be able to handle yourself, I’ll jump in if it gets too rough.”

“How could you!”

While he would not allow anyone to kill his grandfather he would not go out of his way to protect him. If he made some influential women mad at the Long Clan he should be able to handle some punishment. If they beat on him a bit then maybe he would finally learn to change his ways.

“Hey get off me…”

“No.”

Apparently, he would not as Zhang Jin went for his grandson’s thigh and started hugging it. The man was a nascent soul master that was supposed to be in the 0.01% percentile or even lower. If people saw him shamelessly hugging the Patriarch’s leg while pleading for health they would surely reconsider their view of masters like him.

“Fine, just stay close to me and I’ll help you, just don’t go causing any trouble!”

Zhang Dong held himself from clobbering the old fart over the head but his wife wasn’t so restrained. The moment she saw the old man interfering in their bonding time she delivered a hit to his cheek with a closed fan.

“Oh no, the Matriarch is mad we must run! Come children we shall flee towards the kitchen where we have some ice cream!”

“Ice cream!”

Zhang Jin was quick to back away before any more hits came his way. Then he even managed to get the two kids to follow him towards the kitchen. Zhang Dong had to give it to him, while the man was a hornball he at least knew how to treat his family well. With the kids gone the robes could be fitted in peace.

“How do I look?”

“Like someone named the Golden Dragon, I still can’t believe that you are the younger brother of the Azure Emperor, my husband”

He stood tall wearing a mostly golden robe to fit his new image. There were many dragons embroidered into the cloth that cost a fortune. Various other jewels and gems glistered around to make him feel like he was trying too hard to look like some type of Christmas tree. But it had to be done, the wardrobe was handpicked by his wife and some consultants to fit the occasion.

They were taking this a lot more seriously than him. If he could put on sweatpants and a shirt he would be fine but that certainly would bring shame to the sect’s name. The Patriarch needed to be seen as some kind of godly creature, an unwavering rock in a sea of uncertainty. His people needed to look up to him and be proud to be part of the sect.

“I think no one could have known that but now here we are.”

He nodded while smiling at Liena who continued to play around with the tight collar around his neck.

“I need to get ready now, I will see you later.”

“Don’t take too long, we are on a schedule.”

“I know.”

The two separated as he left the room. Liena needed to get her own dress ready before leaving, his disciples and many others would also be coming to join the Long Clan’s best. However, this was not what was on his mind now, what he needed to find was the holy sword. His spies brought him various legendary tales of relics and locations of potential hidden tombs and secret grounds he could visit.

“There are just too many of them and as it stands I can’t task my people to search for them either…”

The war with the vampire tribesmen had calmed down but they were still out there. He could not order his martial masters to go search for treasures at this time. Within a month's time, he would need to report to the magic knights and stall if he was unsuccessful.

“But if I go by the setting then it should not be in one of the obvious locations that anyone can discover…”

When he considered this world to be some kind of game on a timer then the sword should not be appearing any time soon. Considering that the other empires would be able to push themselves into the Empire’s outerlands with relative ease, the item would not be there. If he considered that it just left a few places that it could be at.

“Could it be somewhere in the Long Clan lands or in those two sects…”

In his opinion, the sword could be hidden away in the lands belonging to one of the big three. Now they had turned into the big two after the Soaring Dragon Sect was eliminated. He would probably be able to examine those lands with some pushback. The problem would be the Heavenly Crane Sect which would probably not let him snoop around in their backyard even though he was the golden dragon.

Those three territories were the prime suspects but they weren’t the only ones. There was also the region with the demonic cultivators where Wang Long was hiding away. At this moment the area was cut off from the empire as it was taken over. Landmasses, where the other empires created their strongholds, could very well have the holy sword of legends.

“I guess I can only take things one at a time… maybe I should have researched some of those clone techniques and made an army of myself…”

After giving out a sigh he vanished towards his sect ground. Time began to pass and soon everyone was gathering in the Argonaut, their main flagship. With permission of the Long Clan, they would be able to directly teleport to a nearby city. From there they had the permission to fly towards the capital without being shot down by the Long Clan’s defenses.

“Everyone, I expect all of you to show respect to the Azure Emperor. We are going to meet the most prestigious cultivators from these lands so don’t start any fights, is that understood?”

“Yes, Patriarch!”

There were many people here that he only knew by name but they were now part of the sect’s elite. The once small clan had grown to giant proportions and they could now hold their heads high.

Chapter 476

“Is that it? I never thought I would be able to lay my eyes on such a magnificent city…”

“What do you mean you old crow, our Spirit Spring City is much grander…”

Zhang Jin along with Maling started shouting at each other while standing on the ship’s deck. They were slowly being escorted towards the flying city which not many people in this empire could have the honor to see.

This was also the first time for Zhang Dong to go with the scenic route. It was much slower than going through the various teleportation gates but apparently, the large gates that could bring ships like the Argonaut over were only activated during war times. They were deactivated by default and even if someone captured an outside gate they would not be able to teleport inside.

“Quiet you two, you have been arguing for the entire trip. Aren’t you already old enough to move past your past history? You will live for another five hundred years, learn to get along and yes this is an order from your Patriarch!”

While at first, it was funny to see the two old farts at each other's throats. After seeing it a hundred times it started to grate his ears. His words carried a lot of weight here, even people that were of the older generation had to listen to him. Even his grandfather had to and with everyone from the sect looking he could not act out as he always did.

“Yes, Patriarch.”

Both of them clasped their hands and went on their way. Zhang Jin returned to his two wives that he brought along on the trip while Feng Maling returned to her granddaughter. When he raised his voice the entire place became deathly silent. This was his sect where he ruled supreme and with the exception of some family members, no one dared to go against him.

“Daddy, big bubble!”

“Yes, isn’t it big?”

Zhang Xiu pointed out at the ‘bubble’ which was in actuality a large protective barrier. From this side, it looked like a large soap bubble. There were also others like it surrounding small floating islands that looked like they were ripped out from the mountain ranges below.

First, the land that this Long Clan was occupying was truly lush. The concentration of spiritual energy was even higher here than back at his sect where he found the spirit vein. Large forests with many spirit beasts, fruits, and cultivators of high power. It seemed that reaching the foundation establishment level was even easy for the teenagers here.

This was the real difference between them and the other sects. With all these natural resources even without training their people had a higher floor and also a higher ceiling. Through the years their bodies were absorbing the bountiful Qi that was radiating from everywhere.

Its source was beyond that large wall that reached all up into the heavens. It segregated these lands into three parts but after one of the major sects was eradicated it could split up between the two instead. While the Long Clan had the smallest force they made up with the quality of their cultivators.

Even now he could feel the hundreds of nascent soul masters looking their way. They were everywhere, with this many they would have no problem in wiping out all of the medium-sized sects that mostly had about ten active nascent soul masters each and then s few hidden ones at their main bases.

‘Perhaps if all of the medium-sized sects banded together and made a push they could do something? But the quality also counts…’

The Long Clan clearly focused on pumping their resources towards the nascent soul masters. They were mostly above the early stage as well and had superior technique over the others in the lower regions. When comparing them to the demon-like tribes and the magical knights he could see the Long Clan being able to defend themselves.

‘Even with so many monsters on their side they don’t do anything, unless the enemy arrives at their doorstep they won’t see it as a threat?’

These people had ruled the lands for at least a hundred thousand years. They had clearly grown accustomed to being the best even the Heavenly Crane Sect was not seen as a proper opponent. If they had acted instantly then this war would have probably never happened.

The forces that were coming from outside were beatable by him and he was far from invincible. If the Azure Emperor rallied all of the sects and forced them to defend the bridges victory would have been assured. The invaders had limited space to maneuver and with defenses built up previously, they could just constantly barrage them with spirit bullets.

‘It’s a bit strange, Long Qing knew that this would happen. Did he not think that they could defend the bridges or was there another reason?’

In Zhang Dong’s eyes, the invaders were strong but they were not invincible. With years of preparations on their hands, the Long Clan could have made some preparations. They could have spread a prophecy that would make the other clans set up defenses beforehand but they did not.

‘Could they think the other sects are just too incompetent to do anything? I guess bunkering up in these lands seems like the safest plan if they can’t trust others…’

If he thought about the nature of the cultivators then it made some sense. The Long Clan would need to share their resources to bolster the outside troops and make preparations. Sharing cultivation resources was not something any cultivator would do with outsiders; only their own blood relatives or disciples would gain their trust.

‘That’s probably it… wish these idiots learned to get along with each other…’
“Xiu, Jun stop running around.”

Liena called out which forced the kids that were running around to quickly return to their mother’s side. While to the young ones this was an interesting adventure where they could see many wondrous things, everyone else was on edge.

The Long Clan was the strongest family in the entire empire. They could not offend anyone but they could also not tarnish their own good name. It would be a balancing act for anyone that wasn’t directly related to him. People bumping their heads was not something he would like to see, even though he was the emperor’s brother he had no pull in the city.

Sometimes people would approach his people out of bad faith to make them look bad. If it was not directly related to him it would be unwise to act out. While he didn’t follow the usual cultivator decorum others did. It would look bad if he had to baby the members and resolve each little fight.

‘Hope those guys aren’t feeling too vindictive after the last time…’

While thinking of a certain trio it was finally time to dock. The protective barrier started opening and their ship just had enough space to squeeze through. While they flew in, the ships that escorted them remained outside and would wait there until they returned. Not even a second passed and the large hole had closed itself behind them.

‘The defenses seem capable.’

Zhang Dong did not have the chance to observe the flying city fortress from this vantage point but from up here it looked like something out of a fantasy book. Vast amounts of green, springs filled with spirit water, and various oriental-styled buildings and some that he did not recognize.

This whole place had levels to itself with many smaller floating islands spinning around the main city like moons. While the city was stationary it seemed to be able to move by itself. It was something that supposedly survived the previous war; it could either move itself to evade being invaded or had vast amounts of defensive capabilities.

The floating islands that surrounded them weren’t all. Many cannons that were the size of the Argonaut's main cannon were everywhere. If the Long Clan so wished they could probably atomize this whole ship without even firing off all those cannons. Even he couldn’t see himself being able to deflect all of them at once.

“Welcome uncle…”

After they arrived they were told to halt in advance. Soon a woman’s voice entered his ear that sounded familiar. When he looked at this person that was floating in the air he recognized her as Long Yanyu, the Emperor’s only daughter. The beauty drew in curious gazes, one of them being Zhang Jin that looked to be up to no good.

‘That’s the Emperor’s daughter, don’t even think about it…’
Zhang Jin twitched after receiving the secret message that only they could hear. Even he was not dumb enough to get involved with the Emperor’s daughter. His life would be forfeit if he was caught going after her.

“Well isn’t it my cute little niece?”

The girl’s bright smile turned into a frown for but a moment after she was referred to so closely by Zhang Dong. For some reason, he felt compelled to tease these young masters that were brought up with a golden spoon.

“Please don’t joke around uncle, my father and mother are awaiting you, they wish to see your side of the family but I’m afraid that every one that isn’t related to the long clan will have to remain here…”

“I see…”

Zhang Dong turned to some of the elders that had come on this trip. They had hoped to be at least let into the city to examine it but it seemed they would have to remain on the ship instead. This didn’t mean that he could wedge some of them in there, he was the Golden Dragon and his name was spreading through the lands.

“I do need a few servants, my disciples are like my own children so they will obviously be allowed to come in, right? Then there are a few people from my lovely wife's side, I’m sure my brother won’t mind.”

He shrugged while handpicking some people and beckoning them over towards his direction. Normally if he followed Long Yanyu’s words only he, his kids, his wife, and perhaps Zhang Jin being his grandfather would be allowed to come in.

The group was now closer to twenty people and while Long Yanyu didn’t seem happy about it she could not talk back to her uncle. After the face slapping, he delivered to the three children of the Emperor they were certainly unwilling to go against him. The oldest brother was even taking some lessons in swordplay and changed his tune afterward.

“This should be enough, shall we go then…”

“Very well then but some of them will have to remain outside the Palace.”

“That’s fine with me, I’m sure they will be glad to see the sights the city has to offer.”

Soon the group of cultivators was flying up into the sky. While this was just a family get-together he was here for a different reason.

‘Bob, make sure to scan for anything that could be a holy relic.’

‘Affirmative’

Chapter 477

‘So how many potential hidden holy swords have you found.’

‘Currently, there are … 0 … matches for the specified criteria, do you wish to change the criteria?’

‘No we tried that already… just keep on searching.’

‘Affermitife’

Bob replied while Zhang Dong walked through the lush corridors of the castle that the Azure Dragon lived in. While he had been here before, his family was not. Thus the trip was a lot longer as everyone took their time to look around. At each corner, there was something fascinating and if they had cameras they would probably be taking all sorts of photos.

Long Yanyu was their guide along with a few other beauties that were sent over to greet them. While more than just his family members left the ship they had been divided into two groups. The one he was in only had his kids and his wife as the others were not allowed to enter the innermost palace where some secrets were hidden.

Zhang Jin was more than happy to be guided by some other beauties that were not related to the Azure Emperor. With his silver tongue, he hoped to have him foster some good relations with the Long Clan members. What Zhang Dong was interested in was his image with these people.

Being the golden dragon gave him a certain amount of power as he was in line for the throne. While normally the Azure Emperor’s children would only have that privilege his younger brother was a close second. If per chance the current Emperor died in battle he could take over depending on how the other clan members saw it.

If they only considered his combat prowess then he was more than qualified as the three royal offsprings were not his equals. Yet this was not a small clan or a sect with ten nascent soul masters, there were hundreds of them here. If they all banded together even his power would not be enough to get him the throne.

On the other hand, the clan members would probably not wish to antagonize him in such a way. If a battle broke out then the only ones that would be winning were their enemies. The more infighting in a clan the more it would be weakened. Outsiders such as the Heavenly Crane Sect could then use this as a chance to invade or take away some of the undefended lands.

His motivation didn’t align with the current Long Clan as well. If he was the Emperor now he would already be storming the border regions to take out the enemies and find Wang Long. He knew that the more they waited the more their enemies would build up their strategic advantage.

However they didn’t see those lands as worthwhile, they knew that the war would only take about a hundred years. For cultivators hundred years was nothing, if they could just wait here then it was fine.

‘Why risk your life if there is nothing to gain or lose huh? Would be nice if I could just tell everyone about the system and the other worlds but not like they would believe me… at most they would think that I’ve gone crazy or that someone altered my memories.’

There were techniques to make others spill all sorts of information. Thus there were also ones developed to counter them. One of them was altering the memories of the person after they were captured. If someone tried prodding their brain for knowledge the hidden technique would trigger to alter their memories. The person would not even know that they were changed and give wrong information.

Of course, there were other arts that allowed people to counter these altered memories before they were triggered. It was a delicate procedure that could turn the interrogation target’s brain into mush. Thus he believed that even if he was put under such a technique they would believe that his memories were probably altered instead.

‘I guess I can only slowly build up my trust with these people. I just hope that it isn’t too late by that point…’

“Welcome my precious brother!”

“I have arrived, my older brother.”

While he was thinking about getting his so-called brother on his side they arrived at the dining area. It was still strange to call this man his sibling as he knew well that they were not really related. Even if this body had the same blood as the Azure Emperor, the person controlling it came from a modern earth with no relations to anyone in this world.

The dining area had large doors through which someone that was ten meters tall would not have trouble stepping through. To the sides were many veiled beauties similar to the women he met when he teleported to the Emperor’s hidden villa. They were to the sides just standing there with their hands behind their back.

Long Qing and all of his children were already sitting next to their father and mother. The dining table was really long and reminded him of the over-exaggerated tables nobles used in the other world he was in. In his opinion, these types of furniture were not very intimate as they placed his side of the family on one end while the Emperor’s on the other.

All of the people here were ones that he knew, Long Shen the oldest brother that was looking a bit strangely in his direction. Probably after showing his swordsmanship the youth was eager to show off or ask for some pointers. Long Fengge the youngest was too afraid to meet his gaze after the previous encounter and the sister that escorted them here.

They all sat around their parents while his side did the same. Liena was to his left while his son was to his right. His little rascal of a daughter was next to her mother and already looking over the various dishes that were on the table. Zhang Dong was not much of a cook so whatever the chef made would be served at their home. The Long Clan had a long history so the food would probably be made with the best ingredients and taste accordingly.

“I’m glad that you have decided to bring your family along, I’m sure my children will get along with yours, isn’t that right?”

“Yes, father.”

All three replied in an instant as if they were afraid to go against their father’s wishes. He did notice that there was a little bit of tension in the Long family. The children respected their father a lot but there was also a hint of fear in there. When he looked at his own kids, this was not present. At least not in his daughter as she quickly abandoned her seat to sit in his lap. His son on the other hand was much more reserved.

“Xiu’er, you can’t be doing that in front of the Azure Emperor…”

Liena’s brows furrowed as she tried to wrestle her daughter away from Zhang Dong’s lap. The young girl wanted to have none of that as she clung to his lap. Jun on the other hand was just looking at the plate of food before him that he wanted to dig in.

“Yanyu used to sit in my lap just like that…”

Instead of being mad, the Azure Emperor seemed to be brought to the past when his kids were younger. For a moment he looked at this daughter that turned her head down while blushing. It was as if he was trying to tell her to sit on his lap as she did in the good old days.

All of them looked kind of awkwardly at their father who started laughing out loud once more. Each time Zhang Dong was here the Emperor seemed to get livelier. Perhaps after many years of being the top cultivator in the world had caused him to be bored of life but now with his brother around he had something to focus on once more.

“I see that your youngest is interested in the roasted seven-star duck, why don’t we have a chat after we are done eating?”

“I agree.”

Zhang Dong replied while nodding his head at Jun who could finally get some food into his body after the long trip. Before arriving here he had already used his spirit sense and system to see if there was any poison or drugs in the food and discovered no foul play.

Soon everyone was eating and he had to give it to the Long Clan, their food was superior to the one he used at his sect. He was not surprised that Long Qing’s children were so strong at their age as this food has just the right amount of spiritual energy to make everyone progress through their realms fast.

“Brother, you must give my regards to the chef, this food is just too good.”

“Hah, did you hear that, he likes it.”

To his surprise, Long Qing turned to his wife who started smiling.

“Oh, did sister-in-law make this?”

“It was nothing.”

She replied while they were finishing up with their meal.

“Finally, let us withdraw. There is something I wish to show you, my brother.”

“Oh?”

“How about we leave our wives to tend to the children, I’m sure they could exchange some wife pointers!”

“Wife pointers?”

He was not sure what he meant but he could not refuse. This was Long Qing’s city and even he as his brother couldn’t refuse him without having a good reason. Just like before no secret relics were found in this place but he did not give up.

“Yes, Liena take care of the little ones while I talk with my elder brother.”

They have already discussed some safety measures before arriving here. With the system, he could instantly teleport his Liena and his children to his own location or do the reverse. She just needed to insert some spiritual energy into her ring to signal if there was something wrong. Even if she was not able he had his faction mode that could monitor her status and alert him to any foul play.

“Come, come then!”

After the two parties split he was left going through more wide corridors through the palace.

“You left before I could show you the rest of your ancestral heritage.”

“There was more?”

“Of course there was! Do you think he would only leave you with one crummy casket?”

He had bolted to chase after Wang Long previously and Long Qing didn’t mention anything else. Thus he assumed that there was nothing else that was worthwhile for him here. Perhaps there he would find something useful for the current problem he was facing.

“Yes, you are the Golden Dragon, and just as the Azure Dragon your birthright is deep!”

Finally, after going around the corner he got a good view of that heritage that had remained hidden from him, a large palace made of mostly glistering gold that stood next to the Azure Palace…

Chapter 478

“How does it look, magnificent isn't it? Before you received our ancestors' inheritance this place was nothing more than a ruin but now it has regained its old luster!”

“It's… quite shiny isn’t it?”

Zhang Dong was now looking at a glistering palace that looked a bit tacky. It looked like something out of a fairytale. First off it was separately floating up in the air right behind the Azure Palace which was the bigger of the two. There must have been some kind of barrier placed on it as he did not feel the divine energies coming from it that he was feeling now.

“It was nothing more than a relic from the past floating behind the Azure Palace behind a mirage formation. Only I, the Azure Emperor, was allowed to know about it.”

Long Qing commented while they slowly floated towards the glistering structure. Even now the mirage formation was keeping anyone from being able to see it. Zhang Dong realized that this was only keeping people that were further away from peeking inside. Only when someone was really close to it would they be able to see anything. Without anyone besides the royal family able to venture to these parts the citizens were unaware of its existence.

The first thing that he noticed when he stood on the small floating island was that this palace was a bit different than the Azure one. The architecture here was composed of tall columns, intricate details, symmetry, harmony, and balance. It looked more that he would find in an old pantheon from Greek culture than the more eastern themes this world was composed of.

Yet the height of the palace was much greater than what the Greek architects of old were capable of. It looked like a mix of an old fantasy castle that was surrounded by many columns and arches of various shades of gold. To the sides, there were aqueducts that continuously shoved water out to the sides. The water did not go down all the way to the ground as it vanished after traveling for about a kilometer downwards.

‘Did someone really put an intricate teleportation formation beneath it just so they could have a fountain?’

It was clear that this flowing water was going back into the source it came from. It was a very pricey fountain system that recycled the used water by sending it back via a teleportation gate. The usage of spiritual energy must have been quite high to keep this thing running. Then there was the problem of it mostly being made of some sort of golden alloy.

After landing he approached one of the columns that looked to be made from this shiny yellow metal. From the outside, it did look like gold but after touching it he realized that it was something a lot rarer.

“Spirit Dragon Gold?”

“I see that you have a keen eye, yes this whole place is made from that precious metal, and to think that it was falling apart recently, not soon after we visited the old tomb that this palace started revitalizing itself!”

“Spirit dragon gold can retain its past luster if it absorbs a large quantity of divine energy, is there something inside that caused it to be restored?”

“Well that I would have to leave up to you, this ruined place has been closed off to anyone for millennia, not even I the Azure Dragon could enter it.”

“Not even you?”

“I could have of course forced my way in but that would be like spitting on our great ancestors!”

Long Qing laughed while looking at the large radiant gate that was before them. There was a giant golden eastern style dragon etched into it that looked like a variant of the more prevalent Azure Dragon. Zhang Dong could feel that there was some type of connection with this place and it was quickly confirmed by his Ai companion.

‘New domain discovered, do you wish to add it to your faction?’

The robotic text to speech like voice echoed through his head while a prompt appeared before his face.

Accept the ancient golden palace as part of your domain? Yes/No?

‘I see, so this is really something that was left for me the original system owner. Perhaps Wang Long could have also accessed it or he had something similar waiting for him at the Soaring Dragon Sect?’

There was no reason to refuse this large floating castle. After losing his previous home during the skirmish at his sect he had hoped to rebuild. This was a very high-quality estate made from precious metal that could easily take a hit from a nascent soul master without sustaining any damage. Perhaps he could move it at will after interfacing with it further, this he quickly pressed yes.

Long Qing was a bit confused at Zhang Dong who was pointing toward the large gate. To someone that couldn’t see the system prompts it was quite the oddity. Yet the moment the finger pointed out the whole floating island started rumbling and the gate had been closed for multiple millennia.

The moment a tiny crack opened up the two were greeted by a large gust of wind. This was no simple wind as it pushed these two powerhouse cultivators back and forced them to use their spiritual energy to stabilize themselves.

“Hoh, I think that this place is rejecting me…”

Long Qing called out as the initial hit from the wind had stopped when colliding with Zhang Dong’s body but continued to push the Azure Emperor back. The new owner of the palace was unsure how this place worked but it was probably rejecting anyone that was not him.

“Don’t worry my brother, I will retreat for now, perhaps after you have managed to acquaint yourself with this relic of time past, you will be able to invite me in.”

The man blasted off into the distance after surrounding himself with a deep blue aura of might. It was probably possible for him to force his way inside but he did not. Zhang Dong had to give it to his older brother for not taking it as a hit to the face. Some other cultivators would have probably seen this as some kind of hit to their prestige but this Azure Emperor did not.

“I will.”

He just nodded while turning towards the gate, the cold wind that surrounded his body quickly evaporated into tiny sparkles of gold and he was allowed to step forward. The large gate soon slammed behind him and the inside of the ruin laid bare.

“Hmm… So is this supposed to help the system holder to win the war or something? The outside looks grand and all but the inside is kind of…”

While before entering this place he had his hopes up when he saw the actual inside of it his mind quickly changed. There was nothing in here the spirit dragon gold had managed to regenerate itself but the rest was in tatters. The floors were covered in dust and dirt, and crumbled furniture and decorative pieces were on the floor everywhere.

It looked like a tornado went through this place about fifty thousand years ago and destroyed everything. Only the walls that were composed of this fantasy metal looked to be in good shape, the rest would need to be cleaned out and replaced.

On the other side of the palace gate, there was a wide staircase that went up. To the sides were many golden columns that helped up a very high ceiling. The stairs led up to a higher floor and to a corridor that was the size of a tennis court. It felt like many people gathered here before venturing forward into the rest of this palace.

As he continued he also managed to find the source of water along with the large golden statue in the middle. It was a large fountain depicting a man who was probably the previous Golden Dragon before him. Around his body, he could see a large dragon that was probably his soul beast. The water was shooting out from the dragon’s mouth and then flowing to the sides and out through some kind of drain.

“I guess this guy really liked gold, almost everything is made from it…”

He continued with his exploration while also checking his faction tab in his system window. It was listed under the Ancient Dragon Palace and had a percentage number floating above it.

‘Thirty-four percent? I guess this place really needs some renovating but will my dear brother allow me to bring people from my sect to tidy up? Hm, but do I really need to ask him for permission?’

Considering that the Azure Emperor was not allowed to step into this place without his approval he might be able to just teleport his faction members inside now.

‘If that tacky fountain uses a teleportation formation for the water then perhaps there is a room fitted with the proper equipment.’

While the throne room was in an obvious direction he decided to check out the smaller ones before moving to it. Just as he had theorized he found many interesting locations, one was a treasury that was mostly filled with precious metals and another one was an armory. While most of the weapons had degraded by a lot, some of the higher quality items could still be used or reforged into something close to the original.

“These flying swords aren’t too bad… and there are a lot of them…”

It seemed that his predecessor was a sword fanatic as he found large quantities of heaven grade swords made from the same metal the palace was composed of. Thanks to this he just needed to feed them some of his own holy energy and he would have a large swarm of them aiding him in combat.

Regretfully while the spirit dragon gold was bountiful he did not find any spirit stones that he could use for more spirit points. Now after being unable to harness the elemental energies to increase his cultivation level he needed them to hatch this seed of his.

‘Can’t have it all I guess… the library is also nothing more than dust and the palace seems to be powered by that thing…’

At the end of his walk, he ended up in the ‘engine room’ of this flying castle. There he found a large spirit artifact that was radiating massive amounts of divine energy. There was a lot of juice left in it as it had probably been on energy saving more through the years of no Golden Dragon being around. It took the form of a large golden egg with various patterns, for a moment he thought it resembled an oversized Easter egg when he saw it.

‘Was this an egg from some kind of immortal beast? I can’t imagine it being from a nascent soul being, the holy energy would have not lasted this long…’

While he could not feel any life from within the egg, the immense holy energy it was giving off was somewhat constant. Without him being able to absorb it anymore it would probably remain here to power the castle at least until he found a better use for it.

‘I guess I should go to that throne room now, that’s probably the focal point of this palace…’

Chapter 479

“The carpet seems to have survived at least…”

The throne room was quite large, there was a large red carpet going towards a large throne made of more golden metal. It was a lot more radiant than the columns on the sides that spread out into more empty space.

“There is a spatial formation at work here, the castle didn’t look as big from the outside…”

After wandering for half an hour through the entire place he figured out that something was amiss. The corridors stretched for many hundreds of meters and the courtyard was larger than several football fields. The palace was large and all but it after coming inside it was the size of a whole village.

The throne that belonged to him looked to be missing some gems. There were sockets on the sides that were emptied out. Gray dust was everywhere but some of the fabric that was dangling from the chandeliers and ceiling was still there.

“Maybe I could give it to the weave masters to make some good robes? If this material has survived a hundred thousand years then it has to be special.”

Behind the large golden throne, there was a large stained glass window. The color was a bit faded but it was depicting several scenes involving warriors and dragons. It was the only light source for now but he could see similar windows frames on the upper floor but they were not letting any sunlight in.

“I guess this is the focal point of this palace?”

Finally, after walking down a small flight of stairs he arrived at the throne. The armrests looked like two golden dragons that were immortalized in this costly chair. It was not the same as the Azure Dragon throne, it seemed that the two brothers had different tastes. For once the Azure Palace was much larger from the outside while this one with the spatial formation was just as big on the inside.

‘Establishing direct connection with the new domain…’

After placing both his hands on the sizeable sparkly throne his system window instantly popped up. Bob started informing him about various modifications to the new ‘domain’ he had established here. Previously it was nothing more than a few words on the screen with some basic stats but now it was transforming into a detailed holographic image.

“So this is the whole palace? I could probably fit every core disciple into this thing if I wanted to…’

As with everything in this world, there was enough space to fit around five thousand people without experiencing any problems in housing them. There was a larger barracks and many luxurious rooms spread through the entire palace hidden away by various formations that constricted it.

Then he also had the dimensional regalia which was a small pocket dimension of its own. If he combined the two he would have a mobile flying fortress that was a lot sturdier than the one he created himself. Almost instantly he wanted to have his sect members come here to start with the renovating process. This palace was on a higher level than what he could create himself but it needed repairing.

In the treasury, there were some relics that had managed to survive along with more spirit dragon gold to go around. With him in the castle and with that golden egg to power everything this flying island could become an important asset in beating the other empires. If he managed to restore the defensive systems and bring over some powerful cannons then perhaps he could use them to take back some of the lost lands.

“Will the Azure Emperor complain if I take it outside his lands?”

That was one of the main problems, Long Qing accepted Zhang Dong as part of his family yet he still wished to confine himself to his own lands. This golden palace was an old precious relic that he and the long clan might want to keep inside their territory.

“Do they have the right to stop the Golden Dragon though? I bet some of the people from the Azure faction would love it if I just took this thing and just went away never to return.”

On the other hand, he had no support in the Long Clan. Probably if Long Qing wasn’t supporting him as his long-lost brother the rest of the Long Clan would have turned their swords toward his neck. He was nothing more than an eyesore as he could contend for the throne, he had a whole heritage of the Golden Dragon, someone equal to the Azure Dragon lineage.

“Getting ahead of myself, first I need to get this rust bucket operational. Bob, I assume that all this red and orange isn’t anything good right?”

“Affirmative, discovered multiple failures and errors in the new domain, immediate repair required, do you wish to use spirit points to repair the damaged structures?”

“So I can repair it just like that?”

Zhang Dong leaned back in the uncomfortable throne room and started clicking at the holographic picture representing the golden palace. After fiddling around for a moment he started getting the hang of it. Firstly he zoomed in on the room that he was in now, even this room was mostly destroyed and showed up in yellow.

“These shouldn’t cost that much…”

With his finger, he pointed at the destroyed chandeliers that were dangling from above the ceiling. While the usage of spirit points to raise his cultivation was tremendous it wasn’t the same for the subsystems like this. The chandelier’s repair wouldn’t cost him that much and he could even alter their looks. He had various options available as it allowed him to pick from designs he had at his main sect.

“Let’s go with the default one for now…”

After clicking the confirmation prompt the closest chandelier started shining brightly before regaining its former luster. Various colorful gems appeared around the previously empty golden frame and started giving out light. This light could be changed at will to fit any color and brightness he desired.

“Isn’t there another way to do this? I still need those spirit points…”

There were never enough spirit points to go around. While his evil counterpart could slaughter living beings for them he could only absorb spirit stones or other unconverted sources of spiritual energy like spirit veins. There was one under his sect that he could devour but it would destroy his sect that relied on spiritual power.

He also knew about the much larger one that was here, as the Golden Dragon he might have even been able to visit it. The Long Clan would certainly go after him if they realized that he was draining them of their most precious resource.

“What is this though…”

Yet there was something new after he received this base, his passive spirit point income had more than doubled after gaining this relic of old. This palace was granting him a large number of points just for its base version, if he repaired it and then perhaps upgraded it further could it triple or quadruple his passive income?

“Hey Bob, will my spirit point intake increase if I repair this fortress.”

“Affirmative, the new domain will generate more resources after being repaired, user can also create structures to further increase resource acquisition.”

“Oh, really?”

He almost jumped up in glee when he realized this. Soon he began scrolling through the whole palace and looking for such options. This thing was like a little mobile game, he just needed to wait for a while until the structure was created and it would start to generate him spirit points. The more he mends the place the more he would get in return. The best part about it was that he could do it remotely and his sect members could also hasten the process by cleaning everything up first.

“This is great… if my calculations are okay, this will outpace slaughtering multiple nascent soul beings every day with just its passive income…”

It seemed that this was really an end-game item that was meant to be received when the war was well underway. The faster he got this place in order the faster he could focus on feeding the spirit points into his seed. This place was also connected to his system so he would actually be able to spend spirit points on armaments for his people. It was truly a fortress made to grow his faction and profit from it.

“Hah, can I give this thing a name? Calling it ‘new domain’ every time will be annoying. If I still had my old naming sense I would call it something ridiculous like ‘Golden Dong Palace’ but luckily I have also matured past that, now I bet there is a naming option somewhere here…”

Before he could access that function though he heard his AI assistant call out to him in that robotic voice.

“Domain name has been updated to Golden Dong Palace.”

“... Abort! Cancel!”

He shouted loudly while watching a few characters appear above the stained glass window. It was the exact thing that he just said and a large banner with the words ‘Golden Dong Palace’ appeared.

“Bob, stop it, I want to update the name again!”

After a short pause, he started shouting at this AI companion. The name apparently was now being etched into some key locations; he could even see it appearing on the main gate where everyone could see it.

“Can’t change the domain’s name at the moment, the user has to wait twenty-four hours before attempting again, changing the name will require spirit points from now on.”

“Hey… what is this pay-to-win model?”

The number of spirit points that he would need to spend was also not low. He compared it to the number he spent when repairing the chandelier and it was more than a hundred times above it.

“Screw it then… Golden Dong Palace it shall be… not like anyone will care…”

Zhang Dong slumped his shoulder forward in defeat. He was unwilling to spend such a ridiculous amount of spirit points to just change a few words on the wall.

“I guess it could have been worse…”

He had other creative names floating around in his head that would have made him look even worse. Luckily in this world, the word dong that stood for his name didn’t mean what he was thinking. The people that lived in this world would not find it strange that his name was there, they would probably expect it to be there.

“I should probably return to my dear old brother, he will probably be surprised that my name appeared above the gate…”

With the golden palace now safely stored in his faction window and a teleportation point setup he was free to come back here without many spirit points wasted. Yet before he could step outside his AI reacted again, now informing him of another spicy find.

“Item fitting description has been found…”

Chapter 480

“It should be in here… was this his bed chamber?”

Zhang Dong was about to leave this place to go check on his family but was pulled away by his Ai’s prompt. Bob had discovered an item that fit the description of the sacred blade. Yet on the domain window, he could not really see anything of worth nor could he feel any strong holy energy from this place.

Behind the throne room, there was another set of corridors that led to some private quarters. It seemed to have been connected to the Golden Dragon’s private rooms. There was a mostly destroyed study with no books, a private washing chamber with still working water, and then this last area with a large golden bed in the middle.

“Could old Bob have become senile?”

He was not sure what from here could be the secret relic that the magical knights were willing to go to war for. It was also strange that Bob had only now detected the item and not instantly when he arrived in the now named Golden Dong Palace.

“Perhaps all of this golden metal is making his sensors go haywire? Where is that item anyway, you just said that it's in this room can you be more specific?”

“Negative, the signal is faint and distorted, the system has managed to reduce the search area to this chamber.”

“Fine then… I’ll just quickly go through everything, at least I won’t need to smile at those old farts from the Long Clan.”

While his position in the new clan was shaky that didn’t keep some of the cultivators from sucking up to him. All sorts of people appeared before him, some even offered their daughters up to him to garner good relations. He on the other hand did not want his wife to see any of this or he might have some explaining to do.

“I should get a move on, there is much work to be done…”

When stepping forward he could hear the pieces of dust crunching under his feet. The ceiling had crumbled and there was rocky dirt everywhere. Mostly anything that was not made from that special metal had mostly deteriorated. The floor was certainly made from some sort of panel that had broken apart in many places. Without the framework of the gold the whole structure might have already collapsed.

The first thing that he noticed was the golden bed in the middle. The fabric that covered the mattress was somewhat intact but it looked really dusty. The golden dragon patterns were everywhere here but whatever he tried to pick up almost instantly crumbled.

“I can’t even tell what this was…”

The fabrics crumbled and even some of the golden items started disintegrating before his eyes. The wooden furniture that from afar just looked dusty evaporated before his eyes whenever a little gust flew their way, soon enough there was nothing left for him to look through besides the large golden frame of the bed.

“I guess this was the most important part of this room?”

Thus he decided to touch the bed but as he had thought there was no holy sword here. Bob was not reacting but even then reminded him constantly that the item was in this very room.

“It’s not the bed then what? Do I need to dig underground or could it be on the ceiling?”

He started looking around but there was nothing on the walls, ceiling, or ground that looked promising. After circling around the room he decided to take a little break by sitting on the golden bed frame. Yet when he did that, the whole bed quickly collapsed. Luckily thanks to his quick reflexes he did not tumble down to the ground along with it.

“Damn it… hm? Wait, what’s that?”

After the little accident, he noticed something. The four legs holding up the bed had snapped quickly after he tried sitting down but one of them remained intact. When going closer to that part he attempted a small test by pushing the bed down with some force. To his surprise the bed wasn’t budging and when he increased the pressure even when the bedframe started bending the leg did not.

“Did the golden dragon turn the relic into a leg of his bed?”

With the help of his spiritual energy, he levitated the whole golden frame up and flipped it over. When checking all the other corners and this one he could see that this one remaining leg was a bit different. When straining his eyes he could tell that it had been attached later and did not originally belong to this furniture piece.

After identifying which was the added part to the frame Zhang Dong pointed out with his finger toward the bed frame. From his finger, a tiny beam of light escaped that was used to slice this golden egg from the rest that now fell down to the ground.

“So this is it?”

“Affirmative, item matching specifications identified.”

The item that he was holding looked like a peg leg that he could stick on a pirate. There was nothing special about it but it did seem to have been coated with some of that spirit dragon gold that the palace was filled with. Thus carefully he started to slowly remove the layer of the strong metal. At first, he was worried that he could have destroyed the item inside but quickly he noticed that the thing inside was incredibly hard.

“Hoh… so this is it?”

What he was looking at was a handle, it fit into his hand but had no blade coming out from it. There were some symbols on it that he could not understand. They did not belong to the empire’s language or any that he knew. If this was from the magical kingdom that belonged to a different system setting this would make sense.

“Could this be it?”

There was no crossguard but the hilt was thicker at the top part. It was nicely crafted with some blue and golden tint to it. Yet there was something missing, at the top of the hilt there seemed to be a small round spot with a slight indentation. It was as if he could put something in there, like a small orb or gem.

“Hm…”

After examining everything with his spiritual sense came his system, there another oddity arose. He could not identify the item, his system was showing him nothing but question marks as it could not rate the thing he was holding. The metal was also unknown to him but it was certainly sturdier than the dragon gold that was here.

Before making any assumptions he performed one last test. He was someone versed in holy and divine energies, perhaps if this sword was meant for a hero it would react to them. Thus his hand started glowing golden as he tried to prod the relic into life.

“Hoh?”

To his surprise he could see the hilt starting to react, it was as if small wings wanted to form. He could see an outline forming that took the shape of a crossguard and was composed of divine light. Yet they quickly started to fade away and when trying to continue with the test he noticed his spiritual energy being drained quite fast. Even when he tried to inject some mana instead it did not help, it was as if this blade was out of focus and could not present its full form.

‘It might be missing something but perhaps that something isn’t even in this empire…’

If this was really a blade from the other empire then perhaps they had something to unlock its properties. Perhaps a new system holder was needed for it and neither he nor Wang Long was ever qualified to wield it. He might need another source of energy besides his holy aspect as well, perhaps this sword required high knowledge in wind elements of water which he was not a grandmaster in.

“Even if I can’t activate it… or know if this is the actual sword that they are looking for, it should be enough for now.”

The main reason for searching for this relic was to stall the invasion and get some allies. If he could present them with something close to their fabled sword then perhaps they would put some trust in his god will. If they allowed for conversation then at least some lives would be saved and there was hope for the invasion in that area to stop. This would at least turn one aggressor into something more neutral and let him focus on other things.

“Found anything else interesting in here Bob?”
“Negative.”

“Good.”

Zhang Dong nodded while throwing the sword hilt into his spatial ring. Now that he had the potential holy blade he was feeling much better. Yet he still needed to be vigilant, this could be something not related to the knights. Perhaps he would need to figure out a good speech to prolong their good relations.

“Would be nice if they just understood my good intentions but I’m not sure if that Lucius guy won’t change his mind after having some time to think…”

After rummaging through his new Golden Dong Castle he finally bolted for the exit. Thanks to his system he would be able to return here at no teleportation cost. He wanted to start spending his spirit points already but this was not yet the time. Cleaning this place came first as it also used up a lot of points that he did not want to waste. His sect members could be called soon but first, he needed to check up on his family.

‘Everything should be fine right? I’ve been gone for like an hour… just smile a bit and survive…’

This reminded him of some old family get-togethers where he was mostly sitting in the corner and trying not to talk to people. Here on the other hand he had his own wife and kids with him that he needed to pay attention to. The gates soon slammed open and he went out, where his older brother was waiting for him.

“I see that you have mastered the Golden Palace already! But I think I should call it the Golden Dong Palace from now on! Now even those old masters will have to accept you.”

Long Qing was all smiles, it seemed that some people were still on the fence about his identity. Now on the other hand he had been accepted by the castle the ancestor lived in and even his name was on the entrance. No one could deny that he was part of the Long Clan and was accepted by their old treasures.

“I guess I am…”

The name rang in his head but at this point, he was already used to being called things like Dong’er and Long Dong. This was nothing out of the ordinary and thus he just floated back towards his brother while smiling.

“Yes, my new home needs some renovation but I will be sure to invite you in after it's been renovated!”

“Hah, I will hold you to that. Now come, let us go back!”

“Yes, let us.”

He nodded and soon the two descended back into the palace where everyone was waiting for them.

Chapter 481

“You dare!?”

“What if I do? I will not let you speak ill of my master!”

‘What the hell is going on here…’

After returning from the golden palace Zhang Dong was greeted by a display of animosity between two young men. One of them was his own disciple Zhang Liu and the other was a young man around the same age. Both of them were staring at each other with rage in their eyes, behind the unknown youth he also spotted one of his nephews that for some reason was grinning.

‘Husband, you might have to intervene.’

Liena was quick to send him a message that only he could hear and give him the shortened version of what happened. Apparently, this young man was a disciple of Long Fengge the youngest son of the Azure Emperor. He had continued to badmouth the sect's name in a roundabout way, mostly mentioning how it was below the Long Clan's prestige.

‘So he insinuated that I should pack up and get my ass over here?’

‘Ah yes, something like that…’

Zhang Dong and Long Qing had just arrived in this large open courtyard of the Azure Castle. It was even larger than the one he had in his own castle and was also bustling with people and various other creatures. Fountains filled with deep blue fish that possessed a strong Qi signature, beats that looked like a mix of lion and horse were trotting around while everything was happening.

It seemed that his disciple couldn’t take the back talking of this other young master. Judging by the fact that this other young man was a disciple of Long Fengge that was almost at the top of the totem pole probably didn’t help. His life was probably met with little backtalking and resistance so when he got called out it was impossible in his head that he might have said something wrong.

“Ha ha, are the youngsters getting along already?”

The Azure Emperor’s laugh resounded through the whole courtyard and brought attention to him and Zhang Dong that was floating next to him. Even the two arguing youths had to bow their heads and stop fighting before these two world-class cultivators. While they mostly only respected the one dressed in blue, the golden one was slowly gaining some traction.

“Excuse me father, my disciple sometimes gets into heated exchanges like this.”

“It’s good to be passionate, perhaps the two want to exchange moves with each other to further their bonds?”

‘What is this idiot…’
Zhang Dong just wanted to grab his family members and get on with the get-together without causing a scene. When they arrived the two had quieted down but were clearly glaring at each other. It was already a miracle that the two youths were allowed to be here together with the Azure Emperor’s inner circle.

“That’s a great idea father, how about it Enlai are you up for a friendly spar?”

“I am master, but I’m not sure if my opponent will agree…”

Zhang Dong could see the young man’s status, he was a year older than Zhang Liu and their cultivation level was very similar as both were at the core formation stage. Their Qi pools were very similar which would put their skills to the test. It was clear that Enlai was confident in the Long Clan’s superiority here and not afraid to face off against the country bumpkin from the United Element Sect.

Even if cultivation realms and Qi were very similar this didn’t mean that the fighters were equal. Mastering various battle skills could create a large gap between the fighters that were of similar stature. Zhang Liu’s opponent was clearly of this mind as he was not afraid of challenging the unknown fighter.

“Is that so, well we from the Long Clan are not bullies and we don’t want to offend our esteemed uncle so I propose that we just continue with our chat instead?”

While Long Fengge seemed to want to de-escalate the issue, the words he chose had venom in them. It was clear as day that he was insinuating that Zhang Dong’s disciple was inferior to his and would lose miserably embarrassing his master in the process.

While just ignoring those words would have probably been the proper way of doing things, cultivators were filled with unrivaled pride. Before Zhang Dong could send a message to his own disciple Liu jumped forward to accept the challenge.

“I accept!”

There was a large grass field the size of a football field that was devoid of any structures. It was the perfect stage for the two to battle it out and was probably created for this very reason. Cultivators liked to fight and show off, it was also the main way of handling any disputes. The one with the bigger fist and backing was always right.

‘Master don’t worry, I will teach this scoundrel a lesson!’

Liu looked toward Zhang Dong while sending him a quick voice message himself. It was as if he was ordered to go protect the honor of his master along with the sect. It also seemed that Xue, his sister was of the same mind as she was staring daggers into the other young man that was also quite handsome.

But this was an obvious trap that Zhang Dong was convinced of. He had already embarrassed his brother’s children when he was here the first time. They could not get to him so the next best thing would be to target his family and friends. Disciples were a reflection of their master so when they failed it would tarnish their reputation. If Fengge’s disciple came out on top it would be like he was getting slapped by him directly.

“Wait, father!”

“Oh, would you like to stop the sparring match Fengge?”

“No father, I just thought of a better idea, why don’t we use a more accessible arena where more of our youths could witness their senior brothers exchanging pointers!”

“That’s a great idea!”

‘Damn, that guy is really trying to push it…’

It seemed Fengge took losing his clothes quite badly and now wants revenge. Instead of having the two battles in this small area he wanted to have everyone from the Long clan witness the fight. They even had recording devices that could store this sparring match for future generations to watch. It was clear that he wanted to immortalize Zhang Liu’s failure and along with it cause a big blow to Zhang Dong’s prestige.

‘He is older than me but acting like a ten-year-old brat, hard to get past that young master mentality.’

He could only shake his head while shrugging. Fengge was still a young master to the core that had probably never had anyone besides Zhang Dong cause him this much grief. All the best techniques and resources were handed down to him along with the best teachers so he could rise up above the others.

Yet he did not see those as privileges gained by his own birth, it was his god-given right to be above others. It was very similar for the other cultivators that towered over others and were unable to process any blockades that were put before them.

“Or do you have something against it brother?”

Finally, they decided to ask him, the one responsible for one side of the predicament. He could have ended it here and told everyone to calm down. This would of course be considered weak behavior, similar to running away from the fight. He would lose face from not allowing his disciple to continue even when he had agreed and Liu would be considered inferior as even his master was unwilling to let him fight.

“No, go ahead, you have my permission.”

“That’s great to hear!”

Fengge was a bit surprised that Zhang Dong replied quickly while glancing his way. In actuality, he was also interested in seeing how the techniques he upgraded would fare against the ones produced here. Both of the fighters were confident young warriors that were able to bring out the most out of their battle techniques.

‘While this guy is only thinking about his little revenge he doesn’t realize how much face he could lose. Liu is still the underdog no one expects him to win this fight but if he wins it all then Long Clan’s methods of schooling their disciples will be questioned…’

The Azure Emperor clearly didn’t care one way or another but the other elders were furrowing their brows as all of this was happening. They all knew that they would suffer quite the blow to their prestige if an unknown disciple toppled one of their own. They were of similar age and realm which meant that only their skills would be pitted up against each other.

“Big brother Liu looks mad.”

Zhang Xiu commented while pulling on Zhang Xue’s dress.

“Is elder brother going to be okay?”

Said Zhang Jun while next to his older sister.

“Don’t worry, your elder brother is strong, he will be victorious!”

“Yay~”

His two potatoes cheered towards their elder brother, it was actually quite sweet to see his disciples act as older siblings to their children. The relationships that masters and their students had were considered as deep as being related by blood, sometimes they went even deeper than that. He was glad that in his absence his children found some people to bond with.

“Then it is settled, let us prepare!”

Long Qing clapped his hands which roused various cultivators from the distance. The order to prepare a venue for the two disciples to have their fight was carried out quickly. Within ten minutes the large arena was cleared out and they were already sitting down in the VIP booth that overlooked all the other seats.

Various Long Clan members came from the skies to fill out the area. Everyone from the younger generations wanted to see a battle between what seemed to be two top disciples. Others were just enticed by the Golden Dragon that the disciple carried the name off.

It was actually quite impressive, in the distance, he could see cultivators on swords pulling along advertisements for the event. There were strange slogans such as ‘Golden Dragon’s strongest disciple vs Long Clan’s young hope’ flying around. It painted his disciple as some kind of villain coming to destroy their peace. Thus it was clear that no one was cheering for Zhang Liu but the other handsome youth that was all smiles and waving at all the beauties that batted their eyelashes at him.

“Young master Enlai, please look this way!”

“You are the best young master Enlai, show the upstart what the Long Clan is made of!”

“Don’t listen to them Liu!”

Replied Zhang Xue that seemed to be without any help with cheering on. Her voice was blocked out by all the shouts from the various onlookers. Soon the battle was starting and both of the combatants made their way towards the stage, who would win no one knew.

Chapter 482

‘They are really into it…’

Zhang Dong was surprised to see the many cultivators that had gathered in this large venue. The quality of the experts housed here was probably enough to bulldoze through the entire empire if they set their sights on the smaller sects. It put the original size of the Zhang Clan in perspective as even one core formation expert from here would probably be able to eradicate it themselves.

In actuality, he was not that interested in defending his honor or the sects. There were more pressing matters at hand but due to the Long Clan, he needed to do it by the book. Even if Zhang Liu lost this fight he would not care much as he was confident in his own skills. Perhaps his disciple would be depressed for a bit but it would give him some room to grow.

‘Seems like Liu wants to prove himself to me after my absence, there are no opponents for him in the sect in the same age bracket either and Feng Nuana keeps him on a short leash too.’

This was a good opportunity for his star disciple to spread his wings. Without a certain ball and chain attached to his leg he could finally breathe. It was actually interesting to see what the people around him would do without him giving out orders for once. The fight would also be good training so he did not bother to stop them. Yet if he saw any foul play he would instantly act even if that meant that he would be insulting the Azure Dragon himself.

‘I wonder if I’m stronger than Long Qing…’

While his thoughts were clouded by various things he was brought back to reality by a loud gong.

“Ladies and gentlemen, let me introduce you to Zhang Liu, most of you might not know him but he is a disciple of our long-lost Golden Dragon, Long Dong!”

“Long Dong!”

“It’s really the Golden Dragon, Long Dong!”

“Uhhh…”

An announcer flew out on a flying sword and his voice boomed through the whole arena. Zhang Liu hopped onto the stage when his name was called but all of the attention was focused on his master. The moment everyone started chanting his updated name Zhang Dong wanted to crawl under the stage. It was a bit funny but when so many people were cheering it started getting uncomfortable for even someone of his status.

“The next person doesn’t need an introduction, he is Lord Long Fengge’s star disciple, Long Enlai!”

Luckily the announcement quickly continued and everyone looked to the other handsome young man hopping onto the stage. His height was over six feet and his facial features made him quite alluring to the ladies. Even though everyone here was from the Long Clan it didn’t mean that they had close blood ties and thus various young women started shouting to get the young man’s attention.

“Today these two young masters will clash in a friendly sparring match, will the yet unknown Zhang Liu be victorious or will Long Enlai claim another victory!”

By how the announcer was speaking it made it seem that this type of flashy combat was common. Zhang Dong could only attribute this to the lack of much entertainment around here. The cultivators were on top of the world without any enemies. No one in their right mind would be willing to challenge a person from the Long Clan. Thus they probably could only challenge each other to friendly matches and make a large spectacle of it.

‘Don’t worry master, I will show them that our techniques are superior!’

‘Ah yes, make me proud.’

Before the fight started Zhang Liu sent a message to Zhang Dong that could only cheer his disciple on. While he could not learn much from the fight himself he was still interested in some of the techniques that these Long Clan members used. The fights that he previously had had ended quite fast so he couldn’t really put his own lightning skills against them that well.

Enlai was a disciple of someone from the royal family. He was probably in possession of some hidden skills that the Azure Emperor was using. While the stronger arts were reserved for direct blood relatives some of them should be similar.

‘The Azure Dragon, as I remember, also had some folklore behind it. I think it was also called the blue-green dragon and its domain was rain.’

Finally, the two young men took up their stances. They were fighting barehanded with no weapons which could put some of them at a disadvantage. It was also just a spar and with sword energies flying around a head could come off quite easily.

While deep blue lightning surrounded Zhang Liu’s whole body, Enlai produced a fainter bluish aura that resembled clear ocean water instead. It was as if an enhanced Zhang Clan member was fighting with his disciple which also raised a few questions about his background. Could there be a direct relation between his old clan and this one, both of them used water techniques but one was clearly inferior?

‘I guess this whole scenario had deeper ties that were supposed to be connected in the future, I messed everything up by getting cut away from the system.’

Zhang Dong was not sure what the main scenario of this world was supposed to be. Was he supposed to live through that difficult expedition as someone that barely had any training in the core formation realm? Or perhaps the main plan was for the Zhang Clan to fall instead. Then while he adventures through the lands he would discover his real background that connected him to the Long Clan.
“What’s this, the challenger has decided to make the first move, what a loud movement technique!”

Zhang Liu was like a past version of himself, the movement art that he used was an improved version of the Thunder Movement Art that came together with the system. It produced a loud booming sound and made it look as if the user was sliding on the ground at an astonishing speed. The after images left by this art were quite dense which could confuse an inexperienced enemy, regretfully the young man was quite experienced.

A palm strike was the first attack, it carried Zhang Liu’s understanding of the Dao of Lightning. If he was fighting any other cultivator from any other sect then this one attack would probably have ended it. Yet Enlai countered with a palm strike of his own, when the two palms collided with each other a class of Qi occurred and was followed by a roar.

“Ladies and gentlemen, what is this! The young master\s Azure dragon palm is being held back by Zhang Liu’s own palm! Two dragons are fighting for supremacy!”

Enlai’s palm strike produced an illusory image of a water dragon. It was coiling around his hand and trying to devour Zhang Liu’s palm. Yet a similar technique was used by his disciple but instead of a dragon made from water it was made from blue lightning energy. Even though it was up against water the electrical discharge wasn’t doing much damage to Enlai’s body.

It seemed that the young man from the Long Clan was confused about something. The technique he was using was probably considered to be a staple around here. He had clearly cultivated it to a high degree but it was unable to overpower the lightning art that Zhang Liu was producing.

Soon the two blurry before everyone’s eyes and start blasting each other with their palm attacks. It was as if both of them wanted to prove that their palm technique was the superior one as they weren’t using anything else. Yet even after a hundred exchanges, there was no winner and both of them were forced to retreat to evaluate this tactic.

“For a country bumpkin, you aren’t that bad.”

“Finally stopped underestimating me?”

“Hah, I haven’t even shown you half of my true power!”

“Well, I haven’t even used a quarter of mine!”

Both of them had realized that they were somewhat evenly matched. The little exchange of moves was there to prod for an opening and now they would reveal their teeth against each other. In Zhang Lius a sword of pure lightning energy appeared which was also an improved version of the Thunderlight Sword Zhang Dong used to use. While the technique mostly fell in contrast to proper armaments when there was none it could easily slice an opponent in half.

In response Enlai produced an unknown technique of his own. Multiple water dragons surrounded his body while also producing a large water puddle that traveled in all directions. The water soon encompassed more than half of the arena while the previously visible dragons jumped into it to submerge themselves.

Liu was right at the edge of this body of water and could tell that his legs would quickly sink down into it if he stepped forward. Only when surrounding his feet with a protective layer of Qi would he be able to move forward.

‘Interesting technique, I bet the moment Liu tries to dash forward those water dragons will try to tear him to shreds, it’s like creating an area of influence. I bet if he falls into that puddle he won’t be able to get out either a good technique if your opponent can’t use a flying sword but will it be enough?’

It didn’t seem that Liu was taking the bait of jumping toward his opponent but he would need to make up his mind fast. Even after taking over half of the stage the puddle of water continued to expand in all directions. If he continued to stand there without doing nothing he would need to step onto the watery zone.

Yet Liu didn’t move, he just held his lightning sword over his head while concentrating. This was another take back to his old fighting days, a sword technique that could cleave through almost everything. While it would be weakened by not having a proper sword, the one made from lightning energy would still make it work.

Thus before the entire area was consumed by water Zhang Liu moved his hands down to cleave. The moment the place connected with the approaching water it was cleaved apart along with the stage below it. Though his opponent was not weak, multiple water dragons tossed themselves at the sword energy to absorb the blasts. The attack continued to approach Enlai that was just standing there but right before reaching him the energy was halted.

Enlai grinned while opening his eyes, Zhang Liu was already charging toward him while the large basin of water was forced to the sides.

“I have you now!”

“Think again!”

Both of them shouted at each other, Liu with his sword raised as he charged forward and Enlai with his hands performing a grasping motion. The water that had been parted started swarming back as a concentrated blade of azure. Would it reach Liu before he delivered the final blow or would Zhang Dong’s disciple be the first to strike…

Chapter 483

‘Well, I was not expecting this…’

Long Enlai along with Zhang Liu were now separated from each other. Both of them were bleeding out after their techniques collided with Liu being in a slightly better situation. Thanks to being a dual cultivator with what seemed to be a better body refining technique he had managed to survive through more hits than his opponent.

Yet victory was not assured yet, each of them had a bit of spiritual energy left in them for one final attack. A victor would surely arise if they continued for longer but this also could cause a long-lasting injury to the both of them. Zhang Dong could see that the two youths were set on even burning their own lifespan to make their masters happy.

When looking at Long Fengge he saw a man too concerned about his own face than anything else. He was the poster boy of a cultivator that could not take any criticism and would allow his disciple to suffer long-lasting injuries if it meant that he would regain his honor.

‘Does he really not care or believes in their life-saving arts enough to heal his disciple from any sustained injury…’

The Long Clan had superior technology and resources to any other superpower in the empire. Their size was also smaller which allowed them to concentrate their assets in a smaller elite force. Perhaps even if the young man’s arms were cut off and he was maimed they would be able to restore him to full health. Even then it left a bad taste in his mouth, he could heal his disciples from critical injuries as well but just standing there twiddling his thumbs was not something he was willing to do.

“Daddy?”

“Sorry, daddy needs to take care of something, go into mommy’s lap instead.”

“Husband?”

Zhang Dong had his daughter sitting in his lap while watching the fight. It was a bit strange to have the children look at the bloodbath but not like he trusted others to keep them safe without him or his wife around. After placing the potato in Liena’s lap he started to stand up which did not go unnoticed.

“We shall leave it at that, stand down Zhang Liu, and you Long Enlai. You both did a great job but I fear that you both risk injury if you continue. This will be a draw.”

His voice boomed through the entire arena which was taken by surprise. This was not his sect and he was only an outsider with a title. Normally as long as the Azure Emperor was here he would not have the right to stop the fight. The people here didn’t see him as anyone above the elder generation and certainly not equal to the emperor.

“What do you mean by a draw? My disciple can still continue and is willing! Isn’t that right Enlai?”
Long Enlai looked to Zhang Liu who was now focused more on his own master than the fight and then back to Long Fengge. Zhang Dong could see the young man clasping his hands and quickly nodding as if it was obviously so. Yet he had seen the disciple feel relieved after he had spoken out but he could obviously not go against his own master, an order was absolute.

“See uncle, my disciple wishes to continue but if you wish to forfeit then…”

“And you call yourself a master? Would you allow your student to sacrifice his future to satisfy your hubris?”

“H-how dare you…”

“It’s us to the elders to lead our disciples yet your dispute with me has clouded your judgment. If you wish to see this as me forfeiting then let it be so.”

Zhang Dong just shrugged while talking back to Long Fengge who seemed taken aback by how his uncle was acting. He could only look towards his own family members for some words of encouragement but as this was happening Zhang Liu had already begun walking away from the stage.

“You dare to do this in front of my father, you are being rude!”

The whole place had become deathly silent as no one was willing to offend the royal family. With the mention of the Azure Emperor Long Fengge had taken this fight to the next level though. Zhang Dong seemed to be going against the wishes of the current ruler by just forcing the event to a close. Normally the Azure Emperor with the highest status should be the one to do that and his younger brother wasn’t even asking.

“Your father?”

Zhang Dong looked towards Long Qing who was just smiling like this was not his problem. He could not figure out this man that did not take anything seriously. If he offended him would he need to actually battle it out? Would he even be able to? He couldn’t see the Azure Emperor acting himself as there were many people that could do it for him.

“What about Long Qing? He is my brother, not above or below me, we are equals but you on the other hand don’t seem to know your place.”

“What? How…”

Long Fengge was clearly confused as he had not expected a response like this. Zhang Dong was sure that whenever Fengge brought up Qing’s name everyone instantly folded and dropped down to their knees. Who in their right mind would go against the Azure Dragon? Yet he was not talking with a regular cultivator but with Zhang Dong.

Long Qing had already shown that he was trying to be an ally even than normal cultivators would still distance themselves into a subordinate role. From everyone's perspective, Long Dong was the inferior of the two and should act as his position required him to. Yet there he was, calling himself equal to the Azure Emperor.

“That you are alive and well now is only because you are the child of my brother, don’t ever forget that.”

Zhang Dong’s aura exploded in front of everyone that was there. Words were just words, he needed to reinforce his statement with actions. He could not go wild and attack anyone here so he decided to do the next best thing. This was to act as an offended elder that was being disrespected by a junior.

After his seed had consumed the three cores his aura had become even heavier. He did not know the full scope of his brother's capabilities and now was a good chance to measure it. Long Qing was a relaxed person but even he needed to act in a situation like this due to the fact that the two elders that were meant to protect them were being pushed down to their knees by Zhang Dong’s overbearing aura.

“W-will the two dragons fight?”

“But if two pinnacle masters clash then we will be affected as well…should we escape?”

“How will we escape if we can’t even more!”

The tremendous amount of Qi that Zhang Dong was generating was making the whole area rumble furiously. The lesser cultivators were instantly knocked out with only a few remaining that were at least at the later stage of core formation.

“My child seemed to have offended you, my brother!”

Long Qing finally made his move, he was sitting on a large throne that was clearly made for him. Even after the elders were pushed down to the ground he remained unaffected by Zhang Dong’s oppressive aura. Even now he was able to protect himself along with his wife and his kids that quickly retreated to their father’s side.

“But don’t you think that you are taking things a bit too far?”

Zhang Dong was really curious about this Azure Emperor. He seemed to be hiding his true motives, the fact that he could be part of the system still existed. Like the human king from the magical world, he was in a similar position.

In a sense he mirrored that man, his position and power was about the same. He was forced to remain in the area even though he could probably solve the empire’s problem before it started. It would make sense if he was just an arbiter watching from the sides and only when there was an imbalance in the scenario he would act.

But he could also be one of the many denizens of this world that had no clue about the shadowy scenario playing out in the background. In a sense, Zhang Dong felt that the Azure Dragon was meant to fall during this war of the empires and the person with the system would become the new ruler.

People were expecting the Golden Dragon to be forced into a defensive position. Everyone believed in the Azure Emperor’s might that was unmatched on this planet. Yet even as he stood up and continued walking forward Zhang Dong didn’t falter.

“How…”

Long Fengge along with his two other siblings were flabbergasted by the scene they were seeing. Their father, who they saw as a god among men, had released the full brunt of his oppressive aura and was focusing it against Zhang Dong. However, instead of seeing him going down to at least one knee to apologize he just stood there with his hands behind his back and waited.

“Am I going too far? I think I’m well in the right of my current position…”

Soon the two men were facing each other, Zhang Dong was a little bit taller than his brother dressed in blue. Both of their eyes were now focused on each other which caused the space to warp around them. The two were giving out spiritual energies that would have knocked even nascent soul masters out instantly.

Yet even though Zhang Dong was managing to hold out he was dead even. This was quite surprising as he thought of himself as someone slightly above the nascent soul's great circle realm. This put the Azure Dragon really like someone that was able to break through the limits of this world but it was not to the extent of taking a step into the immortal realm just yet.

“Well then, I will have to ask that you look past my son’s offense and that we can look past it as brothers!”

“If my dear brother is asking me to look past his hopeless son then what else can I do? Let us consider this water under the bridge!”

Both of the men started laughing while constant sparks of energy erupted and continued to make the whole arena shake. Luckily for the people gathered here the oppressive air of conflict soon subsided without a battle between experts breaking out.

‘Scared me for a moment there…’

He was relieved but didn’t show it on his face. Even though he might have been able to contend with the Emperor in a one-on-one battle he would not be victorious here. Enemy elders, grand formations, and lack of weapons, he was just ill-prepared to further a conflict here. In reality, he was already hovering with his hand over the teleport prompt that would get him and his whole family out of here.

‘Now, I need to get this over with and rebuild that golden palace…’

A note from Kuropon

Thank you for reading!

Don't forget to follow, favorite, rate.

Donate | Discord |

Chapter 484

The little incident was over, Zhang Liu clasped his hands before his opponent that seemed dejected. While it was only a draw to the young man from the Long Clan it was closer to a defeat. He was not able to defeat someone that he considered to be trash from a rural area. The fact that Zhang Liu was the disciple of the man that was equal to the Emperor was the only saving grace.

During the staredown between Zhang Dong and Long Qing, both the disciples were shocked. Each of them believed that their side was the mightier one but after the auras clashed it came out to be about equal. They were only core formation experts but even they knew that if a fight between these two elders broke out there was no set winner.

Yet Long Qing was still the favorite as he had the home advantage. With the help of the Azure grand formation, the Emperor’s powers could apparently be boosted even further. In their long past, the Azure Palace had never fallen and the name of the Azure Dragon had not been challenged in what seemed to be forever.

Luckily for everyone involved both of the elders reached an agreement. Both Zhang Dong and Long Qing backed away after putting their energies up against each other. Yet the silence remained and it was obvious that the people were left speechless.

‘I guess their perceptions of me have been shattered…’

Zhang Dong pointed out with his finger towards Zhang Liu around whom a bubble of golden energy appeared. With a little wiggle, his disciple floated right up to the VIP booth where all the other people close to him were.

‘I bet their little cultivator brains can’t process what had happened. It looked like Long Qing had backed off, some of them probably think that indicates that he is wary of my power and unwilling to confront me…’

This was not an outlandish claim, they were both top experts with miraculous powers that were not confirmed. Long Qing’s behavior worked in Zhang Dong’s favor as it indicated that he was indeed strong enough to make an expert like his brother to think twice before attempting something.

In this world, it was common for the party that was challenged to retaliate. Only when both parties were at similar levels of power the conflict would cease. Thus Long Qing’s actions could be taken as the Azure Dragon accepting his brother's strength before all of these people. With this revelation, his worries would actually decrease as everyone would think that he was at a similar level as their Emperor and perhaps even above him in some ways.

“Well then my brother, I shall return to my Golden Palace, I’m sure my wife and children would love to see it. It’s not part of the Azure Palace so I will also invite the rest of my retainers that are waiting for us outside.”

“Is that so? I wished to guide you through some of the sights but restoring the palace is probably the most important issue on your mind but don’t be a strange, if you need a helping hand I will be here.”

“That is indeed reassuring, I promise to invite you and your family into the Palace after I go through it. I think it’s not quite safe for the kids and it needs a lot of cleaning.”

Long Qing didn’t seem to be mad about the little wrestling match they had with each other. Long Fengge on the other hand looked pale in comparison. The youngest son of the emperor was probably stunned after his father couldn’t overpower his uncle whom he disliked. Even he would now be afraid to speak in ill will against Zhang Dong which made things easier.

Zhang Dong’s main priority was to get his people off the streets. While his brother was acting cordially he was not sure why. Long Qing was too relaxed and didn’t seem to care about his face as much but why was this so? Could he truly be a good brother or did he have some ulterior motives?

‘There is that Goliath thing they have talked about but I haven’t been shown what it is… Feels like there are some restrictions on activating it that have something to do with me and now perhaps also the palace.’

He had a small idea of what this thing could be but to be sure he would need to restore the flying fortress that he had received. Perhaps after it was operational he would be given a clue but for now, there was a lot of work to do. The first thing he needed to get in order was a teleportation gate to allow his people to get into the golden palace.

Normally this would be impossible without strict permission from the Azure Emperor and his people. Their grand formation blocked all possible teleportation techniques from piercing their shield. Yet after the Palace was fused with his system it recieved a slight boost. It was seen as a domain connected with his main sect ground. This meant that he could circumvent the outside grand formation to let his people in.

‘It’s impossible to see what is happening inside the palace…’

Luck was on his side again, the outside of the palace was covered with that miraculous metal. With that ‘engine’ room that was powered by the golden egg working well the exterior was now even shinier. He could even surround it with a smaller barrier that resembled the egg.

‘Was that design intentional? Doesn’t matter, thanks to that I can just get my people over here without the Long Clan finding out.’

Zhang Dong didn’t trust his dear brother quite yet. The man was still a cultivator from this world that could throw him to the wolves if something happened. His ancestor the previous Golden Dragon apparently gave up his life during the last war but was this the truth? Could his brother have anything to do with it? There was always a possibility that after everything was over Long Qing would bare his fangs.

‘Better safe than sorry….’

“Well then, we will excuse ourselves, we won't need an escort. I know my way around here.”

Finally, it was time to take his leave, there was a lot of work to be done. After leaving the arena he could hear many people burst out in shouts. Some of them were flying into the distance probably to tell about what transpired during the fight.

Even though he had said that he didn’t require anyone to show him around the city, that didn’t mean that people weren't watching. He could feel some nascent soul elders trying to hide from his spiritual sense but doing a bad job. It was clear that he would not be allowed to just wander around without anyone shadowing him.

“Liena, we need to call gramps over and the rest of the elders that went along with him to the city.”

With the family, dinner being over and a lot of time already wasted he just wanted to move along. Yet without knowing anyone in this place it would be hard to get around. Even now people evaded his gazes and no one showed up to help them. The show of force was not enough for people to go against the reigning emperor. Everyone was afraid to associate themselves with someone that could usurp the throne.

“Do you know where he is? Should we go together or split up?”

“It would be better if we remained together, don’t worry I know where all of them are, just give me a moment.”

Luckily he had his mapping function that allowed him to pinpoint the location of his faction members. Zhang Jin’s loyalty level was quite high so it was even possible to teleport to him directly. With the added bonus from the golden palace, this would not even burn that many spirit points as they could be now quickly recovered.

“Come, he is together with everyone else, follow me.”

With the location on the map, he took up into the sky along with his entire family and disciples. They were in neutral territory where they needed to watch out but this didn’t stop everyone from looking. The whole city in the skies that they were in now was truly beautiful. Various flying creatures and spiritual treasures were flying around making it look even more astonishing.

Just as he expected the nascent soul masters that were shadowing them slowly followed after them. Shaking them off was an option but then he would probably irritate the grand elders that probably sent them to watch his movement. Luckily after grabbing his people this would not be that easy anymore.

“He should be in that hotel?”

Where his map pointed him to was a large building with many floors. It looked like a luxury hotel for rich cultivators and a resort of some sort. Even though the Long Clan kept to themselves they still had members that visited from outside.

“This… yeah this is where he would stay…”

Even before entering he could see some ladies hanging out close to the windows to look as alluring as possible. There was soft music playing that sounded somewhat sensual, it was clear that this place was somewhere that Zhang Jin would like to spend his time. Yet other elders were together with him and spread out throughout the entire establishment.

“Liena, take care of the children I’ll go get him…”

Both Zhang Xue and Liu started blushing as they found themselves before the building. This was probably the red light district of this city. He hoped that perhaps the Long Clan members were above such things but it seemed that the oldest profession survived even here.

‘I bet that horny old fart could not help himself to see it… but did he bring his wives in there as well?’

That was the surprising part as the delegation that he brought along to talk business with some of the Long Clan members seemed to be in there as well. Was this just a horny outburst of an old man that regained some of his youth or was he doing something else? He couldn’t imagine both of his wives being fine with their husband going to a whore house when they were around.

‘One way to find out…’

With many questions on his mind, he took a step towards the large red building from which he could smell all sorts of scents. When stepping closer he could feel that the music playing and the air around here was not simple. Everything carried a certain dao that could lower a person’s defenses.

‘I hope he isn’t getting brainwashed by some vixen inside…’

Chapter 486

“So this is a relic left by the ancestor of the Long Clan? Miraculous.”

“Yeah, now it’s ours but as you can see it needs a lot of work…”

“And a lot of cleaning.”

Zhang Liena swished her finger on the wall that was quite dusty. Zhang Jin was also here along with his grandchildren and both of Zhang Dong’s disciples. All of them were astonished to see the golden interior of this large palace.

“That it does but don’t worry my wife I didn’t bring you here for cleaning, no the only one that will remain here is old gramps over there.”

“You want this old man to stay in this empty palace? Can I at least bring ten of my wives to keep me company?”

Zhang Jin frowned at the idea of having to be alone in this large space with no one else to keep him company. Zhang Dong just chuckled before pointing towards the corridor.

“That’s fine, don’t worry you won’t be alone, you’ll have a lot of our sect members to order around but first follow me, we need to get some of this palace's functions in order.”

There was no time to waste now, he had managed to get rid of the Azure Dragon and his children. With the help of this Palace, he would be able to return to this floating city without the need of making himself known. For this, to work he needed to get the teleportation array operational. Luckily for him, the whole place was now part of his system so he just needed to spend spirit points to make upgrades or to repair old broken down rooms.

“Where are we going daddy? This place is bigger than our house!”

“Yes, we are going on a little adventure!”

Zhang Dong smiled at his daughter who came over to ride on his shoulder. His younger son looked a bit envious at this gesture but was still a bit too shy to ask for a ride himself. Instead, his mother grasped his hand so he could float with her towards their next destination. Thus after passing through various empty rooms and corridors they arrived at a spacious one that was somewhat destroyed.

“Here we are, this should be the transmission chamber…”

“There has not been anyone here in a while… there is nothing here Dong’er, everything seemed to have been affected by time.”

Zhang Jin stepped forward to look around. Besides the golden walls and the crumbling floors, there was nothing here. The ceiling had fallen down to bury something under a lot of rubble, this something was what Zhang Dong was looking for.

“Just give me a moment, you’ll probably want to see this so watch!”
After pointing out with his finger both Zhang Jin and Liena glanced at the destroyed area. They had question marks floating over their heads that soon changed to exclamation marks as they witnessed a strange change. The once dirty and destroyed floor started glowing in white.

“What is happening?”

Liena asked while the strange phenomenon took place. Zhang Dong was just smiling so she did not panic as the whole floor disappeared along with the dirt and broken tiles. They were replaced by the golden metal that lost some of its sheens but was the framework of this whole palace. It continued further as everything vanished into thin air.

“That takes care of the cleanup but now we have to restore it…”

Zhang Dong nodded while his finger swished towards the air. While no one could see it he was just clicking on his system menu. The first part was just to clear out the rubble that was taking up most of the space in this room. After it was finished the area looked like an empty warehouse and not something that would have a teleportation array.

But like in a game the room retained its initial use. In the system, it was listed under the transmission room which indicated a teleportation function. The use of points was tremendous but it needed to be done, unless he spent them he would not be able to get his people over here.

After the cleaning up he actually got an option to dispose of the destroyed debris to gain some of the materials back. These materials appeared as a separate source that was now visible in his construction window.

‘Interesting, so I can lower the spirit point requirements if I procure at least part of the materials, what if I try this…’

At first, he just wanted to show off in front of his kids and spend all of his spirit points to remodel this room. Bob had calculated how much he would need and if he spend 95% of his current spirit points this room would be operational. Yet now after going through the disposing he noticed a new option that allowed him to recycle some of those destroyed columns and floor tiles.

“What’s all of that Daddy?”

“Oh, that’s just something daddy will use to bring this place to life!”

Zhang Xiu called out as she saw her father wave his finger and activate his spatial ring. From the ring, a large number of various materials popped up that he had borrowed from some other locations while going through his travels. It wasn’t much as he didn’t think that he would have a use for regular building materials but with this new feature, he now could.

‘The rates are abysmal as always though…’

After throwing out all sorts of various resources in the form of rare ores and even bricks from buildings he wasn’t able to get the price down by that much. It came out to about 15% of the whole sum that he would need to use spirit points for. Yet this wasn’t that bad, every little point mattered and now he had another way of hastening the process of restoring this floating palace made from gold.

His family and disciples were all there to see the materials vanishing almost as fast as they were thrown out from the spatial ring. His wife was the only one that knew that he was a person from another world but he did trust everyone gathered here enough to show everything that he was capable of. Finally after dumping off what he could spare the prompt to repair the room was pressed. This caused the entire room to glow in white once more.

“Go back into the corridor for a moment…”

Everyone retreated to the hall that the room was connected to. Even the doors leading into it were affected by the change and were restored almost instantly. Zhang Jin started scratching his head at the phenomenon but he had already seen Zhang Dong produce many miracles so this wasn’t that surprising anymore. The ones mostly amazed were his disciples and his children that could not believe what they were seeing.

“And there it is… the transmission chamber but you could also call it the teleportation chamber!”

The once shiny golden room had been renovated. Together with the black tiles on the floor and light blue patterns here and there it looked a lot more lively. The focal point of the construction was the large teleportation gate in the middle. It did not look much different than the ones produced by his sect, the technology from this era was still quite similar to the previous one where relics were cherished and protected.

This was not all as the gate was not the only relic that could be used for teleportation. Behind it was another platform with included stairs leading up to it. It had a honeycomb pattern of golden tiles divided by dark lines made from extremely hard marble.

This was a device to teleport people directly to faraway places and did not require another gate on the other side. There was a corresponding panel to the side where Zhang Dong or one of his people could put in coordinates to where people could be teleported to. It was more similar to the technology of the magical knights he had encountered.

‘From what I can tell that device has a limited range and requires a lot of energy but if someone creates a teleportation formation at the location they want to go to the requirements will be lowered. I can work with that but the most important one is still the gate…’

The teleportation gate was now created but it needed to be tested first. The Argonaut came equipped with a small gate for military purposes. It was a mobile fortress that was able to call for reinforcements from the sect directly. Even if it was attacked by a large force a few nascent soul masters could arrive through the compact gate to offer aid.

“Well gramps, how about you help me test this thing out first?”

“You want me to go through it? Are you mad?”

Zhang Jin was opposed to testing a gate that just popped out from thin air. He did not have the system window before him to assure him of it working.

“Can Xiu do it instead? That looks like fun!”

His daughter ran into the room and started looking at all the strange contraptions. She had never before left the sect or used a teleportation gate before. In her eyes, this was certainly a new toy that she could play around with.

“Daddy was only joking~”

Zhang Dong grabbed his daughter that was poking the teleportation gate. He would certainly not let his child go through an untested gate. If there was a problem with it she could end up lost in the void. Then with the other transmission device, if the coordinates were wrong a person could end up inside of a mountain and very dead.

“We will use something else for the test.”

He smiled while snapping his fingers then out burst his familiar, the small dragon Bahamut. The creature was connected with him and would not die that easily. Even if it perished he could conjure it back up again or that was at least what Bob theorized. Its soul would return to his spiritual seed to slowly be nourished once again and be reborn.

His kids certainly were now more interested in the small dragon that their father created. He had not shown them it yet which caused their eyes to go wide. Bahamut was overjoyed after being summoned and gave out quite the cute little roar. This only caused his kids to be more interested in the friendly-looking creature.

“Oh right, this is Bahamut I guess this is something similar to a soul beast but not quite, he can really get big, I’ll show you after we get home okay?”

His dragon flew over to his children and gave each one a lick on the cheek. While Xiu giggled out of happiness Jun on the other hand didn’t appreciate his face being covered in slobber. It seemed that his familiar liked his kids which was mostly due to them having inherited his bloodline.

“Well then, I’ll contact the Argonaut and see if I can get Bahamut there!”

“GAO!”

Little Bahamut cheered out as if it was excited to go through the gate. It was time to have his people get over here to do some work.

Chapter 487

“Bring it in slowly, hey watch it, if you drop it you’ll have to pay for it!”

“I’m sorry elder!”

Zhang Dong was now looking at a group of people from his sect moving equipment from the Argonaut here. After performing a test with the help of his familiar he was successful in connecting the palace's teleportation gate to the sect’s system. With the coordinates now locked in he would be able to send his people here.

“How long do you think it will take Kuo?”

“As you instructed, I have examined the interiors of the golden palace. It will probably take at least a month to get rid of all this rubble and reconnect all the faulty spiritual connections.”

“Good, prioritize this facility, you have permission to assemble a team, the cost doesn’t matter. Don’t forget to organize everything by worth, I will come to inspect it later. Prepare a storage area where you will transport high-quality building materials from our sect. ”

“Right away Patriarch!”

The Palace was quite big, even with a large group of specialized sect masters it would be hard to check everything. The old materials that this place was made of could be recycled and along with the ones his sect brought along he would have more to work with. A month was a good amount of time for him to gather some passive spirit points as well.

‘I should have enough to get the basics running but will it be enough…’

This flying treasure was a fortress in itself. Even at this moment, no one would be able to get into it while bombarding it with conventional spirit attacks. Perhaps even the Azure Emperor would need to get involved to bust down the main gate. Yet even if this place was so sturdy it was of no use to him here. What he needed to do is to get it outside and use it as a base of operations.

‘I don’t think Long Qing would let me take this old relic outside their borders. He probably doesn’t suspect anything but I don't think I would have enough time to flee without suffering major damages…’

It seemed that Long Qing needed this golden palace for something. For the time being Zhang Dong felt that he was not in any danger. As long as this thing remained here the Long Clan would probably not move either. This left him with one option of taking it out, long-range teleportation to somewhere outside the grand formation.

‘From what I can tell this relic did have such a feature but it will cost a lot of spirit points…’

After going through his system window concerning this golden palace he acquitted himself with all the uses it had. It could be used as a mobile fortress if it was at least 70% operational. Yet for some reason, there were a few options that were grayed out and to which he had no access too.
‘Perhaps if I repair some of the destroyed rooms the function will become available?’

He could only speculate about the requirements of the locked away options but if this was all created to mimic a game system then there were a few possibilities. Either he just needed to continue repairing this place to unlock everything or find some external help. This was what he was afraid of as Long Qing’s closeness seemed a bit strange.

Even though his so-called brother was all smiles he couldn’t shake the feeling that he wasn’t telling him the whole truth. Without being able to stroll through the Azure Palace by himself and researching the past he could not confirm anything. However, this did not mean that Long Qing’s motives could be malicious. He could just be like any other cultivator that was seeking to use him to further some kind of agenda.

‘Well can’t worry about that now, what I need to do now is…’

Zhang Dong tossed the Long Clan problem to the side and focused on another matter. He found something that could be the holy sword that Argus told him about. It was clearly some kind of powerful relic that reacted to concentrated holy energy. Even then Zhang Dong could not activate it with his current knowledge, it was perhaps not something that he could ever use.

‘I need to set up a meeting with them and bargain for something worthwhile.’

He smiled while thinking of the treasures that he could receive from Lucius and his knights. The duke looked like he was loaded and the armors they were using could turn a beggar into a hero. If he could get a few of them then perhaps he could improve on his own designs that were sometimes used.

The one Lucius was wearing was far superior to anything that he created as it increased his power to match a pinnacle nascent soul master. The armor that he once used would not give him that much protection as his body refining skill already gave him enough protection without being bulky.

This didn’t mean that he could not equip some of his sect members with similar gear. Zhang Liu for instance would be a great help if he could acquire that kind of armor. This would give him another way of strengthening his forces without needing to spend spirit points to boost everyone’s cultivations while forcing them into the nascent soul stage.

“Good, I already got the alibi of being in closed cultivation here so everything is ready.”

A few days had passed since he entered this palace. Both his children and his wife had been escorted by him outside the Azure Palace and the city. He at least made it seem that they were leaving while he stayed to contemplate his new treasure. This, of course, brought a smile to his brother’s face and with the help of his teleportation array, he would be able to go back to his sect unnoticed.

“Kuo, I will leave everything in your hands and you gramps also behave, if you need some help you know how to reach me.”

Zhang Jin was left behind as the leader and also as a backup plan. This place should be safe but having a nascent soul master around wouldn’t be bad. The old fart was only willing to help if he could bring over a few of his wives which Zhang Dong agreed to. With that, he finally left by stepping through the teleportation gate and returning to the sect’s flagship the Argonaut that was waiting for him.

“Captain, we are going back home.”

“Aye aye.”

Liena and his children had taken another jump towards the main sect as he did not want them to be stuck in the ship for days. He on the other hand didn’t want to waste more energy on unnecessary teleports and there were still places on the way that he could inspect. While the regions around his sect had managed to push back the invaders this couldn’t be said for the others.

Up in the north where Wang Long was biding his time was his largest problem. The battle-crazy tribes from another empire were constantly pushing into the mainland. News of their horrific murders had already spread through the whole Empire.

Some of the sects were striking deals at this very moment as they threw everything at their borders to not let the invaders inside. Yet just as he had theorized they were all being pushed back towards the middle of the Empire where the Long Clan resides.

‘If this continues then within a few months most of the middle-sized sects will be left decimated and the great leader is nowhere to be seen…’

During his flight, he decided to bring up the large map of the whole Empire while in his private cabin. A large blue hologram covered with some red spots was presented to him. It reflected the current state of the war and how much ground they had lost to the invaders.

His sect was in the southern region and it hugged the western regions. A bit to the north from his lands there were various light red dots that further increased in intensity. The most intense spot was the enemy fortress where the leader of the vampires he faced probably resided. Since their last clash, the intensity of their expansion was hampered but instead of the vampires, other creatures started to appear.

Then there was the northwest region that he had also visited. Even though he had blasted the invaders and destroyed their base they had managed to reclaim it shortly after he had left. The sect that was there could not even last for one day and now it was another crimson zone with many people dead.

Yet when he looked further north to where Wang Long had fled he could not see much movement. It seemed that the invaders were having trouble with the demonic cultivators. Either they were stronger than he had anticipated or the tribes could not pass through the treacherous regions there.

Then there was the region to the south that was populated by the people from the magical kingdom. The part they occupied was quite small compared to the tribe and with some luck, it would only get smaller.

To the east was another large dark circle that was occupied by an empire that he actually was in before. It was the one most similar to this with their Emperor being called the Emerald Phoenix. They had also bitten a large chunk out of some territories by advancing slower than the other invaders. It seemed that perhaps this land of cultivators was comparable to this one.

Then there was the last place in the northeast that the last of the invaders came from. There was not much information about them besides that they came from beyond the deep sea. The north part of the empire was quite large and composed of a somewhat uncharted sea that could not be passed even by flying ships.

‘Could be some water-based creatures, they didn’t really push into the mainland and instead remain in the ocean…’

The red spot seemed to stop when it arrived at the large landmass in the south and was spreading west towards where Wang Long was. The demonic cultivators fled beyond where normal people could reach them and had access to the ocean there.

‘Would be nice if they got rid of him for me but it’s more probable that they would just turn into more spirit points.’

While looking at the map he needed to make a decision. He still had a few weeks until his appointment with Argus. This gave him enough time to visit some places that he could help. With this palace underway and now with an option of transporting his closest family to a safe location even when he wasn’t there he was feeling a bit more adventurous…

Chapter 488

“Kill, kill them all!”

A ferocious scream escaped from the toothy humanoid that resembled a disfigured human. It was about two meters and had crimson leathery skin. Small spikes were coming out of its back and its hands looked more like black claws. Similar creatures like this one descended towards what looked to be a temporary settlement composed of tents.

“H-how did they follow us this fast…”

“R-run, spread out, it's our only hope of survival!”

There were women and children that were only a few months old here. The mothers were covering them with their bodies while running away while the men grabbed their weapons. Yet this did not amount to much, the creatures were much stronger and faster. The small protrusions from their bodies grew out slightly before being shot off like projectiles.

These bone bullets traveled in an arc and descended on the panicking people. They pierced through their legs and lodged themselves into their bodies causing a lot of critical injuries. While the humans cried in agony the monster-like humanoid creatures relished in it. Their grotesque faces had massive smiles plastered over them as they continued to torture their prey.

Yet as all seemed to be lost something miraculous happened. As the projectiles were traveling through the air they suddenly stopped. It was as if time had stopped for the monsters as they could not move a muscle. The men that were still able to stand up noticed the strange phenomenon and quickly realized what was happening.

“A master?”

He appeared from the sky, his spiritual energy washed over the entire area disabling all of the creatures without a single exception. The man was wearing a white robe and on his back, an embodiment of a golden dragon could be seen. When looking closely there were characters of the sect that this man belonged to, the United Element’s Sect.

With just a motion of his hand, the creatures began being sucked into the middle of the encampment. In just about ten seconds a large ball composed of monster flesh was assembled. The monsters that were laughing and parading around were now squirming around without being able to get away.

By pointing up into the sky the ball of monsters was thrown upwards. While it flew there the man started gathering energy in his fingertip. Lightning crackled and was followed by a thunderous roar before the energy attack escaped from his pointed-out digit. A wide beam of energy flew forward, it engulfed the trapped monsters and quickly extinguished their existence.

The people were injured but the spectacle that they had just witnessed made them forget about the pain. The man floated like some kind of diety without saying anything but soon he turned around to open his mouth.

“Tend to the injured!”

“Yes, Patriarch!”

A group of men and women in similar robes and patterns quickly flew in after him. They quickly used some spiritual healing arts on the people that were hit by the bone fragments. The people here knew who the man was, the tales of his generosity had reached far and wide. It was him that they were trying to reach as it was known that only the United Element Sect could turn the tide against the strange invaders.

…

“Just as you have ordered, we have captured one of the demi-humans.”

“Good, did the interrogation arts work on them.”

“Yes, Patriarch, please follow me.”

It was of course Zhang Dong that appeared to save these refugees. After some deliberation, he decided to stick to the border regions where his forces were stationed. With not much time on his hands, it would be best to first lower the danger in his own area of influence. The other bridges between the empires were too far, splitting his forces was also unwise. Only he could handle the tribe leaders that possessed those horns with Huo Qiang having some chances of winning a one-on-one battle if no one else got involved.

Apparently, after he had driven the vampire monsters out they had managed to evacuate a large chunk of the population. There was far too much space to cover though and many settlements that did not believe in the losses that were being reported. This resulted in situations like this with people being unable to escape far enough when the monsters were at their doorstep.

‘The information should have spread enough though, even these cultivators recognize our sect's character…’

His fame was slowly growing as he was the only high level nascent soul master that was willing to lend a hand without asking for anything in return. The legend of the Golden Dragon was spreading slowly but surely. Some recognized him as Long Dong, some as the Golden Dragon and others used his other name of Zhang Dong. One thing was clear though, whenever he appeared the people would cheer and then bow.

“Do we know what tribe this one belongs to? Is it the same one that those pale demi-humans were from?”

Zhang Dong asked the interrogator what was done with hypnotizing the prisoner. Since the monster-like humanoids didn’t have a proper name he decided to go with a popular trope name from novels that he had read before. He already knew that they were just humans that had their biology altered by various body refining techniques which made the name fitting.

“The demi-human claims to be from another tribe, as you have ordered, here are the answers to the questions you requested, Patriarch.”

The member from his clan handed him a scroll where he had written down the answers. Zhang Dong nodded and quickly left as he did not have any time to waste. After going through everything he could see that these people were closely related to the white demi-humans he had managed to force back.

It seemed that their tribes shared an ancestor. They had split off into two tribes that had many similarities but some differences. The prisoner informed them that the two tribes were always trying to prove themselves as the superior successor to their ancestor’s will. It seemed that if they managed to defeat the ‘golden one’ they would be able to prove once and for all that they were the true descendants.

‘I see, they hope to bring me to their emperor after their sister tribe has fallen. They probably still feel that the other tribe was part of them so if they had failed they probably see it as a loss of face due to the similarities between them…’

If he compared them to cultivators it was as if one section of the same sect had been eradicated by an outsider. Even though they were from different factions they were still connected by something.

‘Their movements are somewhat erratic, they have been vigorously pushing closer to our borders, they really are battle-hungry monsters… it's as if they are trying to provoke the battle even if they are suffering losses.’

It didn’t seem that there was much reason and logic in the way these red spiky basterds moved. They were just killing anyone that they came across and throwing bodies against it. Sometimes they were victorious but in other cases, they were eradicated by his own sect members like Huo Qiang that was constantly patrolling these areas.

‘Either they are stupid or … they want to lure me out by killing more people… did they realize?’

Zhang Dong frowned as it seemed that the enemies had figured out that he had a weakness. This weakness was his humanity that he did not want to abandon. If he had the chance he would put himself in danger to save other people of this empire. If they wanted to deliver the golden one to their emperor then by killing civilians they could lure him out.

It was true, while floating away from this temporary encampment he took some time to look at the people that were mostly affected by this war. He had not been able to get here in time and the sobbing of women could not be ignored. Many people had laid their lives down for their loved ones in hope of getting to their lands. To them it seemed to be the only hope as traversing half of the empire to arrive at the lands of the Long Clan was impossible.

Even if they managed to travel to their borders, there was always a chance that they would not be allowed to get past their walls. The Long Clan was known for not allowing people to traverse their lands, the war would probably not change their minds either.
When he was ascending he could see the survivors follow him with their eyes. They were quick to prostrate themselves before him as usual. Yet there was a difference, they were not doing this out of force of habit before strong cultivators. No, they were thanking him for allowing their families to see another day.

‘Those bastards are going to continue killing and enslaving everyone in their path unless someone stops them…’

While he tried to get over his hero complex it wasn’t that easy. He could not see any other cultivators or sects moving towards the battles unless they could gain something. Perhaps if they saw worth in the lands there they would be charitable but he could not see them doing that. These were the lower lands of the empire, resources were sparse and the strongest people living here would barely make it into his sect.

It didn’t seem that unless he acted there would be any change. While his borders would probably be strong enough to block the demi-humans from invading that didn’t mean they wouldn’t continue with their slaughter. They could easily clear out the border regions and continue bringing destruction to the empire.

‘But as the leader, I can’t just send in my people…’

This was the troubling part, he was the sect leader and his people depended on it. If he decided to send his forces out they could be victorious but there would always be deaths. It might be possible to save millions at the risk of losing thousands of his sect brothers and sisters. Even without asking, he knew that his people would agree with anything that he decided on. If he told them to raid the enemy stronghold this instant then they would do it.

‘Sometimes I wish they would question my decisions instead of blindly following every word that I say…’

He gave out a sigh while floating up. His mind was already made up, even though he could go back and wait it out he still thought that getting rid of the fortress where the vampires waited would be the right move. The enemies were still missing their strongest card, the emperor was not here. If he wanted to recapture the bridge between empires then this would be his best chance. While this war did not truly begin he needed to seize victory so that a brighter future awaited all of his people.

Chapter 489

“Take everything.”

“Even the floor tiles?”

“Especially the floor tiles, also don’t forget to keep your eyes open there could always be some survivors.”

“O-of course Patriarch.”

A member of the united element sect clasped his hands while flying into the distance on his flying sword. Zhang Dong looked from afar while a large group of them were dismantling buildings for resources.

‘The only good thing that comes out of these demi-humans is that they don’t care about the treasures at all…’

After arriving at the border region Zhang Dong had decided to push toward the lands behind it. The demi-humans were causing a lot of wanton destruction that he could capitalize on. While he felt bad to rob the previous owners of their heirlooms this was war. These cities were devoid of life with part of the people fleeing into the lands that he owned or perishing.

‘Those vampire bastards are keeping their distance, the only demi-humans we encountered are either these red bastards or those molemen…’

Zhang Dong tried to remember the man named Valentine that whom he had come in contact with. That was one of the more difficult beings to kill as he possessed some kind of life-saving technique. He was clearly the schemer type that didn’t take his opponents lightly.

Zhang Dong was actually convinced that he was the reason that these red boney bastards appeared instead of the vampires. They had a reason to prove themselves to the Emperor after he decimated their sister tribe. This was probably a stalling tactic but what was he stalling for?

‘It’s probable that he is unable to use that trump card repeatedly, he might be trying to recover while pushing the other demi humans towards my lands. I bet he won’t face me until he is sure that he can get away like last time, those cowardly types are always a pain in the ass…’

The monster he was facing was the type to be strong against the weak and cowardly against the strong. Probably even if he decided to storm that fortress the Vampire could decide to flee again. He would do anything in his power to survive, only when those types were assured that their strategy worked would they toss themselves into battle.

‘But sneaking into their fortress alone is probably a bad idea…’

Zhang Dong thought back to the many times that he had tried being stealthy. First, the molemen discovered his location by the soil stuck to his boots. Then Argus’ managed to pinpoint his hiding spot with a spell he was not that familiar with. It was probably that if he went alone he would be discovered.

With his current cultivation level, he didn’t feel like he would lose out to these horned tribe leaders. Even before he absorbed all three of his cores he was more than a match for them. The only person that he could see coming close to his level was their leader, the demi-human Emperor.

‘The leaders shouldn’t be that much stronger than the Azure Emperor but I wouldn’t be surprised if he was the weakest of the Emperors.”

The Long Clan was strong but even they feared the invaders. This was something they had been informed about by their ancestors. The old writings were probably keeping them from being involved. While they might achieve victory if they could wait it out it was fine.

Even if the other sects and clans perished they only needed to last for a hundred years before everything was over. If the invaders remained they would not be able to get any reinforcements either as the connecting bridges would be gone. Zhang Dong was able to traverse through the barrier thanks to his system cheat but he did not believe that it would be possible for anyone besides him or Wang Long to do the same.

‘Long Qing doesn’t really want to talk about his plans, and neither do the elders. Unless I spread my influence there is no possibility of the Long Clan listening to me, killing the current Emperor is also out of the question even though that would probably be the easiest way…’

Zhang Dong knew how this world operated, the best way to gain resources from the Long Clan would be to compete for the throne. If he could defeat his brother in a fair one-on-one bout then the members of the Long Clan would have to listen to him. But he could not see them being quiet while he was beating their Emperor’s face in.

If he went with that nuclear option his hands would be filled with blood. He would have to eliminate everyone that was closely related to Long Qing, this included his children and his wife. After being able to create his own family there was no possibility of him performing such an evil act on someone else. His actions would be no different from what the invaders were doing now and killing people as a means to an end.

‘Can’t attack the Vampire Fortress yet but if I get that Palace to work then perhaps I can force a victory…’

To end this whole invasion faster he would need to take an active part in the war. For that, he either needed stronger forces to battle his enemies or strategic superiority. He could use guerrilla tactics that would allow him to slowly push the larger demi-human forces back. Yet the biggest problem with that approach was Wang Long.

If left alone for too long he would gain too much power. He was the true last enemy and a wild card with a system. The other last bosses or hidden bosses that were created in this scenario were probably balanced to let the system holder win. On the other hand, Wang Long could do anything, even reach the immortal stage if he was given enough time to absorb spirit points from the increasing number of enemies from all sides.

“Why did that damn bastard need to appear, if he wasn’t here…”

Zhang Dong frowned after remembering Wang Long’s stupid smug face. If that bastard was not here he would probably be living a more relaxed life even with the invaders attacking. Now on the other hand he needed to worry about an angry manchild that was taking this world as one big game.

From Zhang Dong’s perspective, Wang Long was mistaken. The people living here weren’t much different than the people in their original world. It was true that the setting was customized behind the scenes but it wasn’t at the level of mind control or mind alteration. The people here thought for themselves, they were just victims of the setting and reacted accordingly.

All of them were taught from a young age how the world worked. With one person being a nuclear bomb in a robe it was normal for their mentality to be different than the modern world that both Wang Long and Zhang Dong came from.

‘It wouldn’t surprise me that if something came to alter the setting, a being like that Demon Lord comes out to bring it back to the original setting?’

He was not sure as he only had one instance to look back to. In the other world after he affected the power balance the being appeared. Luckily he came from a world that allowed him to gain enough strength to face that demon. Which made it problematic, as whoever appeared before him would probably be stronger than the strongest martial master here.

‘I’ll cross that bridge when I get there, for now, I need to get more materials.’

His people were working diligently on ransacking one of the large cities. While most escaping clans took the treasured items with them, the buildings were still there. These would be stripped down to their foundations and sent off to the Golden Palace. Thanks to his faction window he would be able to use the recycle function even when not being there.

For the past few days, he had been escorting his men while they ransacked everything. Small packs of the red demi-humans appeared here and there but they were quickly dispatched. They had a similar way of fighting to their pale counterparts but instead of throwing bone spears, they could turn into porcupines. Their whole bodies would then fire off smaller projectiles that could even explode if the attack was performed by a senior tribe member.

“I don’t like it, it has been too quiet lately…”

Even with the mapping function, these demi-humans that didn’t give out much of a Qi signature were hard to spot. It was impossible to pinpoint their location as the entire area was light red now. His spiritual sense also had trouble with enemy detection which mostly resulted in not much time to react. It also didn’t help that stripping down the buildings was a very slow process. Transporting all these heavy items was only possible due to the replica dimensional regalias that were better at storing such large loads than regular spatial rings.

“I need to contact Argus, the deadline is in a week…?”

While mumbling to himself he noticed something. The map that he had set up to be to the side of where he could see flashed red for a moment. This was a clear sign that something or someone was approaching. By how they have been spending some time traversing these conquered lands he already knew who it was.

“Everyone, take to the skies and retreat!”

An order was given quickly and everyone instantly dropped what they were doing to jump onto their flying swords. This was not the first time that he had warned his sect members of an incoming enemy attack. Now he just needed to raise his voice slightly for his people to follow his instructions. With them being mostly core formation experts they were ill-equipped for battling these demi-humans that had many members that were close to nascent soul masters.

“Patriarch, I am here!”

“Zhang Zhi, there is something coming from below, be careful…”

He was not the only nascent soul master in this area. Together with his number one fan Zhang Zhi, he had been traveling for a week and gathering materials. Most of the time it was actually the samurai that cleared up the enemy encampments or ambushes with him just keeping watch of the weaker core formation sect members.

Zhang Zhi pulled out his katana that was specially made for him. It was a lot longer and had a nicely decorated blue hilt. While holding it above his head he started gathering his true Qi. The black blade instantly became engulfed with blue water energy that took the shape of a water dragon.

Then suddenly a large worm monster burst through the ground. Its toothy mouth opened up to devour the nascent soul master but he was prepared. With one downward slash, the sword energy traveled forward while roaring.

Zhang Dong was watching from the side and felt a bit sorry for the monster that was cleaved in half before it could do anything. Yet it was not over, even though the monster was dead it was just the beginning of the battle as many mole-like creatures appeared from the hole beneath.

‘I guess this was bound to happen…’

Chapter 490

“Watch out, they are hiding below ground, leave them to me just keep them away while I concentrate.”

“It shall be done, Patriarch.”

Zhang Zhi shouted loudly which caused Zhang Dong’s ears to hurt. While he appreciated that this elder was so animated he seemed to be too eager to show his worth. Whenever he asked him to do something he would follow his words to a fault without considering anything else.

If he told him to fetch him something while his child was being born he felt that Zhang Zhi would not even question the order. The man was a true classical cultivator that was overly grateful for being given cultivation resources to get into the nascent soul level. Zhang Dong was like a monolith in the man’s mind that was close to a godly being.

Some of the demi-human tribe members could swim through the earth like it was water. Even with the help of his map system, it was hard to pinpoint their location and then aim for an attack to get them. The hard rocks below were enough to slow down any attacks. This always gave enough time for the mole-like men to move away from danger while also pelting the person attacking them with rock bullets.

But Zhang Dong was not a regular opponent, he had the system with him and even though the map wasn’t perfect it gave him enough information. When mixing it together with his spiritual sense he could lock onto the desired target one by one while concentrating his attack. What he just needed was time and then most of the enemies would be done for.

“I won’t let you interrupt the Patriarch, your opponent is this Zhang Zhi!”

For this very reason he needed some help and Zhang Zhi was the man for the job. While Zhang Dong was concentrating on the map and his spiritual sense the attacks kept coming from all sides. The rock bullets were nothing to scoff at but they were not the only problem. Besides the mole demi-humans, there were the red ones that did not hide but charged straight toward his location.

Even though he was letting Zhang Zhi protect his position he spread his senses enough to know that he could handle himself. If one of the horned demi-humans paid them a visit then Zhang Dong would need to act. For the time being besides Huo Qiang, there weren’t any others that could handle them. Even his wife would probably fare badly that was the third strongest in the sect.

A loud roar escaped from Zhang Zhi’s soul beast which was a water dragon. It produced a large sphere of water around the entire area and protected Zhang Dong while its master pulled out his blade. Soon a battle ensued in the skies as the samurai wannabe continued to cleave his opponents in half.

The watery prison Zhang Dong found himself in didn’t actually hurt him or make it hard to breathe. Each time a spiked bone or a rock bullet came in contact with the water it would lose its momentum. With time there were many of these projectiles just floating around while the enemies continued to attack without successfully hurting their target.

Even though this looked easy Zhang Dong knew that the water soul beast that was producing this barrier of water wouldn’t hold out forever. Zhang Zhi was the only nascent soul master besides him here and they were drawing attention away from the core formation experts. With some regular people in the area, they needed to wait a moment before unleashing more destructive arts than this.

“That does it, remove your barrier Zhang Zhi!”

He called out and his helper quickly followed the instructions. The bubble that was around him burst and while the projectiles that were in it started falling down to the ground Zhang Dong attacked. Above his head, a large orb of golden energy appeared that he guided down with his finger.

Soon the technique took effect by a mass of concentrated beams of light shooting out from it. These guided energy blasts sunk down into the earth at an astonishing speed towards the routes the enemy demi-humans would take. Predicting an enemy's movement was something that he learned through the years of combat he went through and this was nothing different.

The groans of the people underground could be heard by everyone here as the ground beneath turned into swiss cheese. The missiles created from a mix of Qi and mana bent in odd directions as he altered their trajectory where it was necessary. The demi-humans that looked like moles were getting eradicated without being able to counterattack at all, soon enough only one remained.

“Hey, I know you… you’re that one that ran like a coward before I could finish you off!”

It was the mole tribe leader that he previously met with the vampires. That time he had escaped by using his people as meat shields but after what Zhang Dong did there were not enough demi-humans to create a big enough diversion.

“You ruined my stealth run, you bastard! Hope you are ready for the consequences!”

Zhang Dong was still somewhat angry that the soil that he carried out from the camp had done him. This mole man commander was a lot stronger than the minions that he surrounded himself with but he was not the tribe leader. His realm of power could not compare to a trained cultivator like Zhang Dong and the demi-human knew that.

“Oh no, you don’t!”

Before the battle could even start the mole-man attempted diving back below ground. Just like before he was attempting to flee while distracting people with something else. In this case, it were the red-skinned demi-humans that came along for the ride. Regretfully for him, Zhang Dong was not alone and Zhang Zhi was holding his own against the commander of that troop. Without anyone to stop him Zhang Dong had ample time to charge forward to get him.

His palm flew forward and left a giant imprint on the ground that the mole person dived into. How this demi-human traversed the earth wasn’t through pure digging. They were using a special technique that could turn rocks into something similar to mud through which they could swim through.

Yet this also required concentration and the earth elements to be in balance. By constantly delivering large area attacks and infusing the ground with his holy energies Zhang Dong attempted to make things more difficult. His approach was successful as he could feel the demi-human getting stuck in the crumbling earth that it could not easily traverse anymore to the point of propelling itself towards the sky to free itself.

This commander-class demi-human now knew that he wasn’t getting out of this predicament without a fight. Thus he turned toward his attacker, his entire body expanded to a monstrous size and his muscles bulged out intensely. It seemed that he had decided to try a more vicious approach. His body was pure black like obsidian and his hands were more like sharp claws.

Zhang Dong was not impressed though as he casually punched out towards those massive claws that looked like they were made from sharp metal. The increased size that the demi-human achieved was supposed to help him defeat his enemy but when the claws collided with that fist they quickly snapped in half.

“I-impossible…”

The creature's bones shattered into tiny fragments during the collision. Zhang Dong’s level of body refinement was far above what this commander class demi-human was capable of. Even though he had a small horn on his forehead it didn’t amount to anything. After the right arm turned into a wet noodle the next target was the head.

After the transformation, the mole-man had gained a lot more teeth yet even those quickly shattered. There was no possibility of victory as the mole demi-human flew upwards from receiving a clean uppercut to the jaw that was broken as well.

Even though Zhang Dong wanted to deliver the killing blow this was a commander from the enemy camp. The mole person might not have looked smart but he could have some important information for the future.

These bastards were hard to capture by how they could traverse the earth, perhaps his sect masters could examine their techniques and come up with better countermeasures. As it stood there would not be that many people that could soak the ground with enough Qi to disrupt the earth elements that were turning the ground softer.

Thus with a swipe, the mole man made his way inside of his replica medallion. Inside was a large group of humanoid puppets that reached up to the core formation level of power. They were the prison guards that he used to carry off prisoners of war. After they were defeated he only needed to use slave collars that sapped them of their strength so that they could not escape.

“One down… and one more to go?”

While the mole men were taken care of, for now, the red bony demi-humans were still attacking. Zhang Zhi had suffered some minor injuries as their commander class leader was close to him in power and skill. But with the help of his many minions, the tide was shifting in the demi-human’s favor.

“Zhi that’s enough, let me handle him.”

He called out to his retainer that surprisingly didn’t just nod his head and move away. Instead, he just looked at him with indignation in his eyes.

“I see, you wish to face him alone, very well I will set the stage for you just don’t lose.”

“You have my gratitude, Patriarch!”

As always he replied with a lot of vigor in his voice. While Zhang Dong could easily wipe the floor with this demi-human that wasn’t the problem. Zhang Zhi still had his honor as a master, he wanted to prove that he was worthy of being part of the sect.

Thus to accommodate that request all the small fries need to be exterminated. Thus by gathering his Qi he surrounded the area around Zhang Zhi and his red opponent so that no one could come inside. It was a ring created for just the two of them. The red minions weren’t happy about this though as they tried attacking the barrier. When they did, their bodies were electrocuted and turned to ashes in almost an instant.

“You red bastards have other things to worry about than your master…”

The air around Zhang Dong started crackling as lightning bolts appeared. There was no one here beside him and Zhang Zhi now could truly let it lose. By clapping once with his hands he surrounded his entire body with a thick layer of Qi. The demi-humans turned to face him, their disfigured faces for the first time showing dread as they knew that their opponent was far above them.

“Let’s dance…”

Chapter 491

“That’s about it, how is Zhi doing?”

The red demi-humans that were similar to the ones he met in the north were decimated by his attacks. Even though some of them were at the level of nascent soul masters they could not contend with him at all. His power had certainly increased and was close to the pinnacle of what this Empire had to offer.

Zhang Zhi was also showing some promise as he was able to hold out against a tribe leader with a lesser horn. Yet the fight was a lot closer than Zhang Dong would like it, both of the fighters were exchanging blows and taking a lot of damage. If this continued for too long he feared that Zhi would lose as his specialty was not body refinement that gave a cultivator a lot more stamina.

‘I feel that he will be depressed if I just jump in to save him… but I can’t have him die here…’

The blade that Zhang Zhi was holding was unable to cleave through his opponent's taught skin and bones. It was obvious that the demi-human was faster and stronger than Zhi yet the cultivator was still able to contend due to his fighting sense. His fighting style was somewhat similar to Zhang Dong who liked to predict his opponent’s movements before dodging with minimal effort and Qi use. This allowed him to hold on without utilizing his Qi for defenses but there was still a limit to everything.

‘He needs to deliver a critical blow, all those flesh wounds would be able to take a normal cultivator down but this demi-human’s healing abilities are over regular body refiners…’

There was of course a limit on how many times the red demi-human could heal himself. Zhang Zhi’s attacks also injected small amounts of his Qi into those gashes which slowly ate away at the opponent’s stamina. It was a true battle of attrition that was shifting in the favor of the humanoid monster.

‘To win this fight he will have to take a gamble…’

This was what Zhang Dong was afraid of. Zhi clearly could tell that he was slowly losing, if he didn’t alter his tactic there was no coming back. What he could do was gamble his life on a risky maneuver that would strike down his enemy. By sacrificing some of his flesh he would be able to strike down his opponent's bones in theory, but would the demi-human risk it?

He was not about to let one of his strongest sect members just die but he at least needed to give him a chance to improve. It would be easy to jump in but he felt that Zhi would feel some resentment towards himself for not being able to be useful to his favorite Patriarch. Thus instead of jumping in directly he decided to fiddle with the lightning barrier that was keeping both of them in a makeshift ring. If there was a danger to Zhang Zhi’s life he would activate a massive discharge to save him.

‘It will be close though…’

Finally, the exchange between the cultivator and the demi-human reached the final act. The first one to act was the demi-human, he was the more aggressive one throughout the entire battle. Zhang Zhi placed his katana into the scabbard while taking up a quickdraw stance. It was the technique he was most familiar with and the one he intended to finish it all.

The monster-like human’s claws expanded, they looked very sharp and were made from white bone. Its entire body was covered in them for protection and it was also the largest problem for Zhi that could not cut through them in one swing. It seemed that he was risking his life to finally cleave his opponent, either he would succeed or die.

Zhang Dong moved a bit closer as he got nervous. He did not know what was going through the man’s mind precisely. Not once did he look for help or even pay attention to Zhang Dong while he was clearing out the trash around the area. The trust for his patriarch was unshakable but the man in question wasn’t sure if he liked that. This put a lot of weight on his shoulders, if he did falter then the trust of his people would be misplaced.

He was prepared to electrocute the demi-human instantly but he allowed Zhi to have his way. The man was hard-headed but he was a warrior who deserved to get a chance if they decided to risk their lives. Thus when he saw what was transpiring he jolted forward, the clawed hand connected with the side of Zhi’s neck, and took a large chunk of his shoulder out almost instantly.

Yet he stopped himself from stepping in as he saw the katana leaving the sheath at a tremendous speed. Zhi had offered up his left side to allow him to get in this one final attack. The sword left the scabbard while being covered in a blue light that was concentrated on the sharpened cutting edge.

A loud thunderous roar that was similar to a dragon followed soon after the blade collided with the demi-human’s neck. Sparks flew as the sword was resisted by the creature's bone plates that were covering its neck for protection. It was a momentary pause as the edge slipped in through a precisely seen weak spot. The head of Zhang Zhi’s enemy flew upwards as the clash was over signaling the end of the battle.

“You idiot…”

Zhang Dong appeared right next to his retainer that was almost decapitated himself. At the last moment, he shifted his body so that only his left shoulder would be blown away. His sword arm was still intact and able to be used to deliver the last blow. By focusing all of his qi on the blade while ignoring his own defenses he was able to dislodge the demi-human’s head.

“I apologize Patriarch, I have shown you a disgraceful display…”

It seemed that Zhang Zhi was more concerned about looking weak in front of his leader than losing part of his body. If Zhang Dong wasn’t versed in healing arts then perhaps he would have been crippled for the rest of his life. Even though he was a nascent soul master, so was his opponent. The amount of damage was serious and normally his body would take years to recover. Yet thanks to the ample holy energies that he had at his disposal, Zhang Dong could shorten the process to a week or two.

“You did well, your opponent is dead and you have gained valuable experience for the coming battles in the future but for the time being I order you to retreat to our sect, our healers will take care of the rest of your treatment.”

“I… I will do as the Patriarch commands…”

Zhang Zhi was happy when he was praised but his smile soon turned sour as he was ordered to return to the sect. It was obvious that in his current state he would be a liability if more enemies appeared before them. Luckily the man would not go against orders like this so Zhang Dong wasn’t worried about him leaving the sick bed before his treatment was over.

“Now hold still, I’m glad that you won but next time you should prioritize your health. Look at the sorry state that you are in now. If you asked me for aid you wouldn’t need to be removed from the battlefield for a whole week!”

“I… I made a grave mistake!”

“Hey stop that!”

Zhang Dong had to deliver a smack to Zhi’s forehead as he was trying to bow down after being reprimanded. His healing energies were slowly recreating the flesh that was once the shoulder blade. It was a lot harder to perform healing arts on nascent soul masters than on regular people. That’s why he needed to do it himself, if he left all of the healing up to the average healer then it could even take a year. After the initial healing was done though, they could continue with the healing process and get him running within the week.

“Patriarch, Elder we have come to aid you!”

While he was applying his healing arts two nascent soul masters that had been given their strength recently appeared.

“Good, one of you can escort Zhang Zhi back to the teleportation gate, make sure that he returns to the sect’s hospital only return to me when he starts his treatment and not a day sooner!

“Yes, Patriarch.”

More and more people started gathering after the battle was over. This was not over as the demi-human parts could actually be used as cultivation resources or weapons. The bones they produced were hard to cut even by high-quality blades and were easily processed by just grinding them down into shape.

With each passing day, his sect was growing. For most other sects this was a time of turmoil and loss, yet for a small few this was the chance to rise up. All of the resources that were left in the wake of this war could be siphoned away. They didn’t need to spend time making weapons, pills, or elixirs that could just be taken from other locations and used to strengthen their warriors faster.

This did not mean that they could just wait as their opponents hadn't actually shown their true hand. Their leaders were still hanging back in their respective empires. would they even appear or just continuously send their forces. It was hard to figure out the number of men that could be thrown their way as they were still in the information gathering stage.

These leader-type demi-humans seemed to know a bit more than the grunts but unless they captured one of the true tribe leaders like Valentine they would not be able to get anything substantial.

“If you know the enemy and know yourself, you need not fear the result of a hundred battles…”

Zhang Dong was starting to take some of the cheesy quotes that he read from the internet to heart. To win this battle he needed to get a substantial amount of information about his enemies. That was the only way of winning the coming battles where he was at a disadvantage.

“But also an enemy of my enemy is my friend…”

He pulled out the holy relic that Argus and the magic knights were probably here for. There was an underhanded method of getting help from them against these demi-human bastards. While he didn’t want to lie there was no way that those people would just give him aid, probably even if he just gave it to them.

‘If I announce that I have it but aren’t willing to give it unless they help me, then they might do it… or betray me at some point to get it… but if I do something else then they will have to help me even if they don’t want to…’

Zhang Dong grinned a bit as he placed the item back into his spatial ring, then soon he took off towards the area where the demi-humans resided with a new plan in mind.

Chapter 492

‘Hm, don’t think they trust me that much yet…’

A month had passed since his last run-in with the forces from the magical kingdom. After battling for two weeks at the border regions together with his sect members, he had managed to push the red demi-humans back. Their tribe chief was nowhere to be seen and it felt mostly to be an annoyance.

It bothered him that the vampire demi-humans were gone, their master was probably resting at the castle that he wished to conquer. For the time being, he couldn’t do anything about that but he had a plan. This plan involved both Argus and Lord Lucius whom he was meeting now. If he was successful then he would have enough backup to storm that fortress before the vampire lord gained back his full power.

“Argus, this is a waste of time, we should resume our search for the holy blade.”

“Please Lord Lucius as you know it would be better if we worked with the natives living here.”

“You two know that I can hear you right?”

Zhang Dong chuckled as the two approached him while bickering. The area that they were in was close to the previously hidden base. It was a wide-open area without any spots that could be used as an ambush. He could also feel that there were several hidden knights on standby probably waiting to pounce if he tried attacking their lord.

‘I guess this is only natural. I did beat them all up and almost killed their leader…’

They were still in an unfamiliar place with no clue of the culture. They had come to retrieve some kind of vague relic that they probably weren’t sure existed. This same relic was already in his possession and he could easily hand it over to them. The question was if that would help him or his people out in any way?

From his point of view, it seemed that these people would leave these lands after recovering the time they wanted. They were a much smaller force compared to the demi-humans with an elite unit with not that many soldiers compared to the other empires. They were not as violent and were not taking over the lands they pushed in but instead hid out of sight.

Would their disappearance be helpful for this war effort? If they vanished then people in the southeast regions would not have to battle them anymore. Yet on the other hand there was the Emerald Phoenix Empire in the upper east regions. These two powers would clash with each other sooner or later and probably keep themselves in check. Thus in a way, they were helpful in blocking the other invaders from advancing too far.

Yet there was another way of making them useful but it would only work once. By producing a white lie concerning the location of the relic he would be given a chance of using this force of knights. His plan was simple, perform a joint attack on the area where the demi-humans are hiding in their fortress. His initial plan was to wait and upgrade the floating golden palace but if he could get these magic knights to aid him, then the Golden Dong Palace would not be needed.

“You must exercise the young lord Sir Dong, he is still skeptical of your motives…”

Argus turned to face Zhang Dong while awkwardly replying.

“It’s only natural to be skeptical but I assure you that I mean you no harm.”

He was telling the truth, even though he wanted to use these people, harming them was not his motive. Nevertheless, it also didn’t feel right to just give them the item without having them work for it. In these cruel times, he could not worry about others while his own people were constantly in fear of death. The invaders were in the wrong here and if they wanted to have their treasure they would need to give their aid.

“A month has passed, do you have any information concerning the holy relic? How could you be able to achieve something that my holy knights could not for so long?”

Lucius was not having it though, it seemed that after the loss he didn’t change that much. Even after being humbled, it didn’t seem that his pride would allow him to calm down in front of the person that he lost to.

“Lord Lucius you shouldn’t…”

“It’s fine Argus, you might not believe me but I think that I might have found your treasured blade for you…”

“You found it?”

Argus was quite surprised after hearing Zhang Dong’s answer. Lucius on the other hand just snorted without looking impressed.

“You want us to believe in your words, where is the proof?”

“I was just getting to that, are you always so impatient Sir Lucius?”

Zhang Dong chuckled while the blond knight was taken aback. The man that had the title of duke was probably not used to anyone talking back to him. Yet the person that he was conversing with was someone that he could not beat, even if he couldn’t accept it the loss was there.

“Argus, do you perhaps have an item or a spell that could confirm the relic?”

“Yes, we do have something like that.”

The old wizard started scratching his beard while looking toward Lucius. It was clear that the person that possessed said item was the knight commander.

“That would make it easier to confirm my claim then, let me explain. I’m not sure if you are aware of the monster-like humanoid creatures that had invaded our lands recently, they are quite ferocious and don’t value human life at all…”
First to get things rolling Zhang Dong started to explain the situation with the demi-humans and how they were pillaging their lands. He went out of his way to portray them as mindless beasts that only wanted to spread carnage and suffering. It was a jab at the knight's code that these people possessed as they would probably be fine with battling bloodthirsty monsters.

“They sound truly atrocious.”

Argus commented while shaking his head but Lucius didn’t seem that impressed.

“Where are you going with this? Are you just stalling because you weren’t able to find any leads on the relic?”

“You are truly impatient my friend. I just wanted to give you some information about the new enemy that your people will have to face to retrieve your relic as I’m convinced that it's buried somewhere in the lands that they had taken over…”

“You want us to believe your word? Where is the proof of that?”

Zhang Dong shook his head while shrugging, Lucius clearly didn’t trust him but even the knight commander would have to if they really had an item that could recognize the holy sword's location.

“As you might know I am fairly poised in the holy arts myself, I discovered this relic’s unique energy signature while battling with the beasts, and to some degree, I am able to recreate this energy pattern. If you really have an item that can detect your relic it should be able to confirm my claim.”

“Is that true Wizard?”

Lucius was clearly not that versed in magic. He relied a lot on that magical golden armor that he was wearing to give him most of his strength. Zhang Dong on the other hand knew the answer to that question. To know the relic’s unique magical pattern he would have to have to come in contact with it. The item was really complex and even Zhang Dong could not use it.

“In theory, it should be possible, the guiding ring should react to the divine energies that the relic produces but are you really able to copy them that easily?”

Even Argus was skeptical about Zhang Dong’s claims, how could he be able to copy their divine relic’s energy fingerprint? It did sound ludicrous but they had to at least hear him out. They had been stuck going through these strange lands that were far too huge to explore.

“What do you have to lose? If you think that I have bad intentions you can move away while I perform the technique.”

Lucius was clearly not having it as he started to back away. Argus on the other hand was more interested than afraid but he needed to listen to the knight leader. Soon the two moved back while the hidden knights closed in as if a battle would break out. All of them knew that Zhang Dong was strong and fighting him even with these numbers would not be easy.

“Well then, let me begin… it should be something like this…”

To not appear that he was trying to blast his new allies with lightning bolts he decided to sit down in the usual lotus position. The only person that wasn’t on guard was the bearded wizard that was more interested in the strange combination of magic and spiritual energy that Zhang Dong was performing.

Soon his body started glowing, it was similar to his usual hue of golden but was slightly different. Lucius placed his hand on his sword while being apprehensive about this phenomenon but soon there was a change. The knight commander noticed that something was happening as the item that was around his neck started giving out chimes.

“Impossible…”

Without waiting he removed the golden chain that was around his neck. A single ring was hanging from this chain and this was the item that was giving out those gentle chimes. All the other knights and also Argus were awe-struck as this was the guiding ring that was supposed to react to their relic if it was close enough.

“Judging by your reaction, it does seem to be the item you are searching for.”

“But how…”

The chiming quickly subsided as mimicking the pattern of that secret relic wasn’t an easy task. Even Zhang Dong could not make that relic budge for long, the most he could do was use up almost all of his spiritual energy to get that ring working. For safety purposes, he was actually copying the energy he experienced when he tried releasing the sword from its sealed state as bringing the relic to this place even in his spatial bag was too dangerous. Argus would probably notice it and then his scheme would be over.

“I see that it was really the relic you were looking for, good. I think we could form a pact between our sides, if you help me take care of the demi-humans plaguing my lands I will guide you towards your relic and also help you get it! Doesn’t sound bad, right?”

Zhang Dong smiled while putting on his poker face. If Lucius wanted to get his hands on the relic he would need to help him capture the demi-human base. Even though the man was prideful he needed to complete his mission and for that, he would need to follow his lead.

Chapter 493

“Then I shall contact you when I have made the arrangements.”

“Very well Sir Dong, we will wait for the news.”

Argus along with Lucius blurred out of existence as they teleported away. The meeting between the leaders was over but this was only the beginning of their cooperation. Zhang Dong flew away from the meeting location only to be welcomed by his retainer.

“...Whew.”

“Is everything alright, Patriarch?”

“Yes, it’s fine more than fine!”

“Is that so…”

Zhang Zhi backed away after seeing a strange devilish grin plastered on Zhang Dong’s face. He was used to the refined look of his sect leader so the cackling noises coming from him were a shock.

“We have a lot of work to do, gather all of the elders, we must prepare for the next stage of the plan!”

“The next stage of the plan, Patriarch?”

“Yes, soon we will go to war… get some rest, this would be a good opportunity to visit your family Zhi…”

The grin that was plastered on his face quickly vanished as Zhang Dong was brought back to reality. His deal with Lucius and Argus had gone through. With some trouble, he managed to convince the two that the treasure they were looking for was in the vampire castle. This was of course a lie as it was in his possession instead.

Even though he lied he didn’t feel that he was in the wrong. After he got help from the magical knights and wizards the relic would be given to them. His reason for the lie was based on some distrust towards their leader Lucius. He feared that if he just presented the item to them, they would just leave before returning the favor.

The second option would be to bargain, inform them about the item in his possession and force them to aid him in the attack. Yet for a deal to happen some amount of trust between the two parties had to exist. Without substantial reassurance, it would be impossible for trust to arise. Even with some soul-binding contracts, there was no certainty that the leaders wouldn’t sacrifice themselves to get the holy sword back to their kingdom.

For the time being, they had made a small pact. It wasn’t much as he only promised to hand over the holy blade to them if his side discovers it during the siege first. Argus along with Lucius did perform a pact while waging their souls on it and Zhang Dong did the same. His promise was to give the weapon to them and they accepted to aid them in the assault and were guaranteed a safe return after everything was over.

‘It’s normal that they don’t trust me, going into enemy lines so deep into the empire would probably never happen unless they were desperate. They did change their tune after I simulated the blade's energy pattern…’

He wasn’t sure if they were aware of his deception but that’s probably why they had him word the contract in such a way. After the enemy was driven back he would be obligated to give them their item if he had it in his possession. This was fine as he could not use it anyway.

“If you say so, Patriarch…”

Both the cultivators propelled themselves back towards a location with a temporary teleportation gate. With it’s help Zhang Zhi returned to the sect as he was ordered to while Zhang Dong paid a visit to the Golden Dong Palace. After two weeks had passed the place was finally returning to a better state. When stepping through the gate he was greeted by a small group of cultivators that were here along with Zhang Jin.

“Dong’er you have returned! Does this mean that I can…”

“No, you will stay here for the time being at least the women in the sect will be safe from any unwanted pregnancies for the time being.”

“H-how could you say such a thing to your dear grandfather!”

There weren’t that many people that he trusted, his grandfather was one of them. He needed someone that would follow his orders in this place and that had enough prestige to instruct the sect workers. This place was far too important to let someone incompetent manage it. While Zhang Jin was a pervert he did all of his tasks accordingly to Zhang Dong’s wishes.

“Treat it as a honeymoon with your lovely wives, I’m sure they are glad that their numbers won’t be increasing for a while, now how goes cleaning, did you manage to get the place into shape?”

“No love for your dear grandfather I see, such is my faith.”

Zhang Jin shrugged while all the other people in this room lowered their heads down. It was clear to everyone in this room that this old man was not to be trifled with. No one besides the old man was able to be so relaxed around the Patriarch besides his wife, even his disciples were very reserved.

“We had managed to get this place into shape but some areas are locked but…”

Before continuing with the report Zhang Jin snapped his fingers. When he did a neatly dressed man appeared from the side along with a clipboard in his hand.

“He will give you the details if you wish, your grandpa is far too old to remember such things.”

Zhang Dong could see the old man laugh while shoving the responsibility on one of his retainers. The man with the notes was quite old and looked more like an accountant than a cultivator. He performed the usual greeting and only when Zhang Dong nodded did he start speaking.

“As the Patriarch commanded we had moved all the rubble, dirt, and broken items into the storage facility…”

The man started going through the list as he listened and walked towards the previously mentioned storage facility. This was a temporary space that was one of the largest areas in the palace. From his system description, it was marked down as a training facility with a lot of space for combat training.

This old accountant was clearly nervous as Zhang Dong walked half a step in front of him and looked over the golden palace. After all the dirt and dust was taken care of the whole place was quite shiny. It was actually a bit too shiny as the golden metal was almost all that remained from this relic. The whole place was mostly just a framework that needed to be refurbished.

“I see, that’s enough.”

They finally arrived at the temporary storage facility where some items were gathered. Even though normally this space would be filled out with various trash it was mostly clean now. Whenever enough materials were gathered he would recycle them without the need of coming here to check. The people here had gotten used to it as even when the materials were disappearing before their eyes they didn’t flinch.

Before continuing he decided to empty out the content of the dimensional medallion and his spatial ring. With all of these various building parts stashed in there, he would be able to start repairing the insides of the palace but it was not enough. More and more building materials were needed along with spirit points. To get this whole place operational far more was needed.

‘Hm… how big is that Vampire guy’s fortress again?’

While he was going towards the demi-human fortress to block off their advancement into his lands, there were resources for him waiting as well. Remembering that great worm with a fortress on its back made him think of a quick solution to getting this place up and running. It would probably not be enough but if he managed to transport all of the building blocks from that place then perhaps he could make his palace fly.

After going through the system he did discover the flight module that kept it afloat. It was an anti-gravity treasure that used up a lot of power just to keep it floating in place. To make it move he would need to restore a lot of the functions and even repair the power source that was that golden egg. This could be achieved through spirit points and various other materials that would lower the costs.

‘But first, let's get some quality of life upgrades, if my people are going to live here they need to have better living conditions.’

The sect members here were reliant on the main sect for their well-being. There was no food to be made here nor any place to sleep. He only had enough points to get the instant transportation chamber to work but there were far more rooms to restore. One of these chambers was meant not just for food production but also to generate various spiritually packed herbs.

With his current spirit points and the various recycled materials, it would now be possible to build this zone. Thus after unloading the remainder of his spatial ring in the current storage facility he went to work on his faction window. There he only needed to find the desired room and start fiddling with the options.

It was possible to recreate this room just as it was in the past but also make some modifications. The soil used for the cultivation of rare plants could be boosted past its original specs all thanks to his system. The whole place was like his own cheat lair that could rise above the placed limits of this world.

‘To keep everyone healthy and safe we do need more recovery pills, let's focus the herb cultivation facility on recovery items for now.’

While he could produce cultivation resources to raise the power levels of his people there was not enough time. Soon everyone would be flying off to battle the demi-humans where they created a fortress. For this reason, more pills and elixirs that could regenerate lost limbs would be more appropriate.

“Okay everyone, you might want to close your eyes…”

After deciding on the second upgrade he walked to the entrance. Instead of a closed ceiling, this room had one made from some kind of glass. From the outside, no one would be able to peek inside but the sun rays could still illuminate the whole area normally. The special glass and gold outlines were the only things that survived through the ages and allowed him to activate this place at a lowered cost.

Soon after the command prompt was clicked the whole area started glowing in blue light. The whole room was consumed by this light and some of the cultivators that were with him had to narrow their eyes and scrunch their noses when they looked at it directly.

Yet the process was quite hasty and a familiar smell that no one expected started coming from the illuminated zone. When everyone opened their eyes once more they were greeted by a lush farming zone filled with sprouts that were already on their way to producing valuable herbs…

A note from Kuropon

Thank you for reading!

Don't forget to follow, favorite, rate.

Donate | Discord |

Chapter 494

“How is this possible… How did you do that Dong’er? Is this part of the Golden Dragon legacy you have received?”

“Something like that but more importantly have some herb masters start cultivating the soil here, it's very rich with spiritual energy and should be a lot better for growing special herbs with vast amounts of holy energy in them.”

Zhang Jin looked at one of the elders that were walking with them. The man just clasped his hands and quickly started running as he had heard what Zhang Dong had stated. It was a nice sight to behold, he didn’t even need to lift a finger and everything would be arranged. What he only needed to do was to restore these facilities and point his sect members towards them.

‘This area isn’t only meant for herbs, it can be used to grow fruits that should be rich in nutrients required for body refinement.’

For the time being, creating more recovery items would be more important but later it would be beneficial if this flying fortress was self-sufficient. The teleportation arrays used up a lot of energy that needed to be conserved during a long battle. While it was stationed here it wasn’t a problem but when it became operational it wouldn’t be optimal to have to constantly rely on outside sources.

‘Besides fruits and vegetables that can be grown here, people also require meat…’

Luckily this place had it all, in another location there was a wide-open area that was meant for animals to live in. With the help of the herbs being rapidly grown at this greenhouse farm animals like spirit chickens could be brought up rapidly. They would fully mature within a few weeks before being able to be eaten.

‘It is a bit strange that a palace meant for an emperor would have facilities like this…’

The Azure Palace of Zhang Dong’s brother didn’t seem to possess these types of rooms. Livestock was kept outside in one of the city districts meant for farming. All the high-quality food was also made there while the rest was imported from spots below this flying fortress. In a sense, the Azure Palace was more reliant on outside sources for survival but would probably still be able to sustain a large population of cultivators even if they lost all the lands outside.

‘At least, in theory, they could have hidden spatial treasures that I’m not aware of like my medallion…’

What the Golden Palace lacked could be constructed inside of the Dimensional Regalia. Yet the facilities here could be created much faster as they were connected to the system. Zhang Dong imagined that in the future the Golden Palace could be used by inner and core disciples while the outer disciples remained in the Dimensional Regalia.

‘I could probably fit the entire Spirit Spring City in there but bringing it there will be the biggest problem, also the citizens might not want to come either…’

While his sect controlled the city their numbers were vastly inferior to the whole population. They were below five percent of the population but held all of the power. Even if he could order everyone to get into the spatial treasure they needed to decide themselves if they wanted to stick around. Living in a pocket dimension might not have been something that everyone wanted.

If they decided to relocate they would not be able to easily leave without the sect’s approval. The world inside was vast but compared to the whole empire it was like a grain of sand. While the regalia was an immortal grade treasure this didn’t mean that it couldn’t be destroyed either. During such an event whoever was inside this dimension would surely lose their life.

‘After getting the necessities in order I should start repairing the battlements…’

First, he needed the Palace to be able to house the minimal amount of people it required to run. There were many facilities that needed cultivators to run them. This place could not work automatically; it actually needed people to run most of the equipment. It seemed that it was created with a large force in mind and not one person using it from the throne room.

The Palace was huge, if there weren’t enough people manning the cannons there would be many blindspots through which the place could be invaded. Only if he managed to restore all of the defensive features could this fortress be operated. It was far too large to evade cannon fire from fast-moving battleships. Its only protection would be the protective barrier and its own cannons which needed to be used by a team of trained marksmen.

Thus for now Zhang Dong headed to the second location to repair it. The stunned sect members quickly followed after him as they were curious about what their leader would do this time. After arriving at another empty large room the whole area was lit up once again but this time around some of the elders kept their eyes open even if it pained them.

They were rewarded by finally being able to identify what was happening. Even then they couldn’t wrap their heads around what they were seeing. Floor tiles appeared out of nowhere along with various pieces of tools. Everything was just materializing out of some kind of spiritual energy without it making sense to them. This only furthered the gap in their understanding of this world and of their Patriarch that seemed like some kind of god.

After going through the large castle various rooms that would allow more sect members to migrate here became available. With them now working over he could prepare for the battle facilities that would be then manned by the people living there.

“This will probably take some time but prepare to move a large part of our sect members here, they can live in the barracks section for now but then will be moved to a special location…”

This whole place was created with spatial items in mind. This allowed them to create more rooms in a special space. These smaller rooms were similar to cultivation caves that were popular in the other sects. By spending more spirit points and materials Zhang Dong would be able to create a long corridor through which certain core disciples would be handed their rooms. There was a limit on the size but together with the wider barracks, it would have enough space for everyone to live in.

‘This whole place feels like it's some kind of strategy-building game, the only thing that is missing is waves of monsters attacking the palace at set intervals…’

It all felt like a game, the more he renovated the place the more spirit points he received. At this point, he wouldn’t be surprised if he would get more resources after this place became operational and started going against the invaders. Yet for the first attack, he would not be able to use it but perhaps after stripping the vampire fortress for resources, he could fix that.

…

“Are you leaving?”

“Yes, we need to prepare everyone.”

“Dong’er are you sure that we should be rushing? If we just wait some more…”

“If we wait, then it will be far too late, time is not something that we have…”

Zhang Jin and Zhang Dong were having a private conversation after he had spent most of his remaining points on renovating the palace. His grandfather knew about the intended attack on the demi-humans that would be taking place soon and was against it. From his perspective, there was no reason to rush into enemy territory. Their position was secured and the invaders couldn’t get past their new borders.

“Is this Wang Long truly such a difficult opponent?”

“I don’t know yet but the more time we give him, the more people will die in the future. If we let him develop his skills to the fullest then even if we survive this war our lives will be forfeit.”

Zhang Dong feared Wang Long for one reason only, he had the original version of the overpowered system. There was no telling what he would be up against when this person appeared before him once more. One thing was certain, Wang Long considered all of this a game and had no reservation in using human lives to reach his goal. If he somehow was able to reach the immortal realm or even step foot in it, then it would all be over for them.

“Is he really such a monster?”

Zhang Dong nodded while his grandfather just gave out a sig.

“If it is so, then I will fully support your decision but not like you need my support, the other Elders won’t speak out either.”

Normally even though he was the sect Patriarch he would need to at least convince some of the Elders to follow his orders. In other sects, the difference in power between the leader and the ones below him wasn’t that large. Here on the other hand he was considered a true dictator that no one could go against. The only person that could realistically go against him was Huo Qiang but the man would be the first to jump into the battle.

“We have been winning most of the skirmishes so those old bastards might actually be itching for a fight this time around!”

“Let’s hope so as we will need most of our elders to move out this time around, if we can secure that location then we will be able to sway this invasion in our favor.”

He was convinced that controlling the area by the bridge was the first step in achieving victory. The plan was to secure that location first before turning their eyes towards the north. His main enemies were the demi-humans and after they were gone he would have access to the lands of the demonic cultivators in the north.

Regretfully he would not be able to do anything to help the people on the east side of the empire. The focus was still on Wang Long, only when he was dealt with could he start thinking of reclaiming the other areas.

“If only the Azure Emperor would see reason, do you think that he would aid us in this battle?”

“Long Qing would probably… not help me, it’s better if we keep this a secret from him for now.”

“Is that so?”

Zhang Jin could feel that there was something between these two brothers that he could not ask for. Clearly, his grandson had some reservations about the Azure Emperor. But was it something more on a personal level or was there a darker reason?

“It’s no time for that gramps, I need you to come with me for the time being, help me gather all of our forces.”

Zhang Dong was not a strategic genius and required someone trustworthy like his grandfather for aid. After assessing their forces they needed to come up with a good enough assault plan that included the magic knights. It was finally time to bring the battle to the enemy's doorstep.

A note from Kuropon

Thank you for reading!

Don't forget to follow, favorite, rate.

Donate | Discord |

Chapter 495

“I’m glad that you have decided to aid us, you will not regret your decision.”

“Do we have a choice?”

“There is always a choice but this one is certainly the better one.”

“Hmph.”

‘Lucius is kind of a tsundere, isn’t he?’

It was time for the offensive and both the United Element Sect and the magical knights were gathering at the closest location to the demi-human infested lands. Even though his forces were much larger than what Lucius had brought along this didn’t mean that they were weaker. What they lacked in numbers they made up in power as they were a smaller battalion of elites.

‘They certainly look like people from the world I met Beatrix in…’

Zhang Dong started wondering if there was some kind of default structure these worlds were based on. Perhaps whoever made them just copy-pasted in the usual bases to make them work and then just let them run their course. Why this was happening was still the biggest question, a question that he was afraid to ask after forming relationships with this world's inhabitants.

The magic knights in question were drawing a lot of attention to them. They were all sitting on top of winged horses that radiated some strong divine energies. All of them were at least of core formation level of strength with quite a large force of ones that were a realm above. These golden paladins were led by Lucius himself, Argus on the other hand would be giving ranged support along with some of his elders.

“We should discuss our strategy, please follow me.”

Before the battle could start everyone needed to be on the same page. Thanks to Lucius being their ally now he would be granted access to their intelligence. Zhang Dong moved towards a tent that was much larger on the inside than on the outside. It was a bit funny to look at Argus that examined the entrance before giving Lucius the nod.

‘I guess they still don’t trust me that much.’

This was a normal turn of events as he would probably not trust any other group after creating a hasty design contract. There were always ways of circumventing those kinds of binding agreements. On the inside, there was a large holographic map, a smaller version of the one they had at the sect with similar capabilities.

“This is where we are and those red spots are where the enemies are focused.”

Zhang Dong spoke out while pointing at the red spots on the map. While the map still had some trouble picking out the qi signature of the body refiners if there was a large concentration of them somewhere it would show it. Argus was somewhat intrigued by the map and quickly voiced his praises.

“What a brilliant device… you can actually see where they have stationed all their forces?”

“Yes, thanks to this we won’t have to worry about being ambushed by a large force. Let me explain, the demi-humans divide themselves into tribes and we will be going against three of them…”

The map started changing as it brought out a visual representation of each individual demi-human type that they had met. From what his sect knew there were at least three tribe leaders still active in these areas. One belonged to the molemen, another to the red demi-humans covered in sharp bones, and then the vampire-like creatures that were comfortably sitting in the fortress.

“Hoh, what a peculiar way of manifesting mana…, and what is this strange energy?”

Argus was more interested in how the hologram worked. Similar effects could be created with illusion magic but they worked on a different basis. While illusions affected the human brain a hologram actually produced a holographic image in front of them. They achieved a similar result of producing an image of something that wasn’t there but went around it in totally different ways.

“Argus, this is not the place for this…”

“Ah yes, excuse this old man Lord Lucius.”

“If you wish to study some of our treasures then I think we can work something out but let’s have that conversation after we are done with our current problem, shall we?”

Zhang Dong chuckled at the old man that was acting like a curious child that found a brand new toy. He could understand the sentiment as he was somewhat versed in both spiritual energy and mana. Perhaps if things went well he could lure in Argus with his knowledge to form a more long-lasting bond.

‘Even if they receive their holy relic this doesn’t mean that they will abandon these lands, the bridge to their kingdom will remain open for another hundred years. Perhaps we could create a beneficial relationship between each other…’

His current enemies were the demi-humans that were killing everything that they came across. When they were removed from this location there was still much more work to be done. Even though he promised to hand over the relic after the battle was over this didn’t mean that he could not bargain with something else. His knowledge concerning the holy arts was paramount, if he gave some of it away then perhaps he could gain a helpful mercenary force consisting of magical knights.

“What do you wish us to do?”

Lucius finally asked the question after going through the holographic map and the enemies that they were going to face. Before answering Zhang Dong handed him three booklets.

“These are?”

“You will find information about the demi-humans there, it includes their weak points and usual strategies during battles. I would like you to focus on the red ones and leave the mole-men to my sect members.’

The demi-human forces were divided. They were not one force and didn’t adhere to one commanding officer. The plan was simple, divide and conquer. While Lucius and his knights kept part of the demi-humans busy his forces would contend with the other tribe. Then Zhang Dong along with a smaller elite force would go for the fortress.

‘Lucius should be on the level of their leader, even though I have made some progress it would be unwise if I just confront all three of them by myself. Huo Qiang will have to contend with the mole leader if he appears…’

Nothing was set in stone, if he was immensely lucky none of the other demi-human tribes would participate in the battle. There didn’t seem to be any sense of comradery between them which he confirmed by seeing one of the mole leaders abandoning the vampire demi-humans during his battle with them.

‘But I don’t think they will let their fortress fall that easily, they might not be afraid of each other but that Emperor of theirs seems to be someone they will not be willing to disappoint.’

“I see, I will examine these.”

“Take your time, we still have some time before we set out.”

The strategic meeting between him and Lucius didn’t take long. The man quickly absorbed the layout and the strategy which it seemed was satisfactory. During the attack, Zhang Dong and his sect would be the ones in the most danger. His allies only needed to keep the other forces busy while they laid siege to the vampire castle.

Perhaps if both sides trusted each other fully they could go with a more joint offensive. Like this, they would not get in each other's way and have to fear any surprise attacks from their allies. Zhang Dong didn’t have any malicious intent but he could not fully trust Lucius’ side either. Perhaps when it was all said and done the knight commander might decide to attack him instead, that was also a possibility.

‘Well, I don’t think he will side with the demi-humans at least and if he betrays me, I do still have the relic as a bargaining chip.’

If for some reason he would have the tables turned on him he could always hold the relic hostage. Yet he did not believe that Argus would lie to him, at least the old wizard seemed like someone truthful that was trying to minimize the loss of life. This didn’t take these demi-humans into consideration as they were unapologetically brutal with their hunts.
…

“Patriarch, we have gathered our forces and we are ready to leave.”

“Good…”

After a whole day had passed every flying ship that his sect had created or bought was up in the sky. Some foundation establishment personnel were flying them while the core formation masters and above were using their own strength to fly. It was quite troublesome to get all of this here through the various teleportation gates, if they were unsuccessful in this attack the sect would not easily recover.

‘We can not lose, too much is at stake.’

Zhang Dong floated up into the sky overlooking his large forces. He could see some of the youngsters among the current forces. While their spiritual power was low they could man the ship cannons or be part of the protective formations that protected their advance.

When up in the air there was a strange feeling in his chest. The number of people following his orders was truly tremendous. They all trusted him with their lives and would toss themselves into fire if he asked. Yet the more they relied on him the more he felt like a fraud that was only handed all of this success thanks to the strange system. If he could do everything alone then he would but even someone like him had limits.

Even when dark thoughts filled his mind there were also positive ones. These people started out as a simple clan that grew into the large sect that was before him. In a sense, he was like a father watching his children grow up and advance through life. This sect could be considered strong and this would be their first move towards real greatness.

Previously all of them were forced to move on the whims of others. First, it was the Dark Palm sect that caused him to almost perish. Then it were the other medium-sized sects around their lands that chose to bully them and it all culminated with Wang Long’s attack. Now finally it was them that would be on the offensive, it was time for his sect to rise to the top.

“Everyone, move out!”

“Yes, Patriarch!”

A faint smile appeared on his face as he saw a large number of flying vessels and cultivators follow behind him. Victory was not assured yet for some reason when he felt all those gazes on his back, it gave him strength. While they all relied on him and their belief did strain his soul it also gave him the strength to move forward. It gave him a reason to fight for and something to strive for.

A note from Kuropon

Thank you for reading!

Don't forget to follow, favorite, rate.

Donate | Discord |

Chapter 496

“Don’t let them advance.”

“Keep suppressing them with cannon fire! They can’t do anything to us if we stay outside of their range!”

“Concentrate on the shields, don’t let their attacks through!”

Zhang Dong listened to his commanders giving out orders while advancing through the air. Their large ships along with the vast number of flying cultivators threw a large shadow at the enemies below them.

‘We do have an advantage when it comes to air battles.’

The enemies they were facing were from various body refining tribes. While their elders that were at the level of the nascent soul could easily fly it wasn’t the same for the core formation equivalents. They lacked flying treasures like swords to keep them afloat and were mostly stuck on the ground.

On the other hand, the people from the United Element’s Sect that were participating in the current assault specialized in ranged Qi attacks. The large flying ships continued to use their massive cannons to rearrange the landscape. This made it hard for the demi-human forces to advance in any meaningful way, their capabilities to pierce the massive mobile defensive formations were also very limited.

‘While my people would certainly fail when confronting these demi-humans in close range skirmishes they are at an advantage.’

By lacking in spiritual energy the demi-humans had one fatal flaw, they could not produce battle or defensive formations. One of them had the strength of five to ten when it came to pure battle power but they could not combine this strength.

By contrast, the cultivators from the empire could combine it by forming various formations that strengthened their Qi. As long as these battle formations lasted the enemies were at a disadvantage and so they were desperately trying to invade their ranks.

‘As long as we can keep the Nascent Soul equivalent masters from breaking through the defensive barriers we should be able to advance without much difficulty.’

“Give me a report on our friends, how are they faring?”

“Yes, Patriarch! Our allies have managed to block the red-skinned demi-humans approach, thanks to their mounted combat they are managing to push them back. We have also sighted the mole men in that region.”

“Good, has any leader appeared?”

“We have confirmed that a large demi-human with a long horn has appeared, he is being held back by both Argus the Wizard and Knight Commander Lucius, the mole leader is hiding his presence but he had managed to kill some of the escorting knights.”

“Good, have Huo Qiang move out to help them out with the mole problem and continue to monitor the situation”

“As you command, Patriarch.”

Everything seemed to be going well as the red demi-humans were removed from the chessboard by the people from the magical kingdom. Even the mole people had entered the fray but with some help from Huo Qiang and some other elders, they would also be too busy to help the vampire lord out. Without any reinforcements to push into his flanks, he would be free to assault their castle.

‘It does look good for me but I can’t underestimate their forces. There could be other tribes lurking somewhere or even arriving through the bridge while we are fighting, it will be best if we get this over as fast as we can… but what’s with this fog?’

They had been able to slowly progress into the enemy territory without suffering much but the further they went in the thicker the miasma became. With time the whole area was consumed by this fog which reminded him of the time he helped the Divine Fist Sect. It was clear to him that this vampire tribe was somehow affecting the environment and changing it.

‘The fog has some evil energy in it but it's very low quality, it would not even be a problem to a Qi condensation cultivator, perhaps the reason is to block out the sun instead?’

While this thick fog would not affect living beings that much it was still hard to see through it. The bright sun rays from outside could not pierce through it which would give the vampire demi-humans some protection from their fabled weakness. These monsters were susceptible to concentrated solar energy that he could employ.

‘But not like we didn’t expect this.’

His people did their utmost effort in scouting out the area. While they did not venture too close to the fortress they gave reports about the dark mist. After analyzing it with his own spiritual sense he was sure that it would only slow down his plan slightly but as long as his ships survived he would have the upper hand.

“Patriarch, the enemy fortress is close, we are encountering resistance.”

“I’ll move out then.”

With that notion, he deactivated the communication device with his flagship and bolted forward where the rest of the vanguard was. At the helm of it all were bulky vessels that contained many core formation masters versed in protective spells. They were augmenting the formations on those ships and creating the mobile defensive array that allowed them to progress without suffering any damage to their armada.
It looked like something from an old horror flick. The castle was truly tremendous and reached up into the sky. It was composed of some kind of obsidian material that was radiating malicious energies. The whole thing looked like a giant spiky tower composed of more towers. The windows were eerie similar to ones found at a church, along with depictions of horrific acts on stained glass.

This wasn’t all, this castle was placed on elevated ground with a moat around it. This moat was not only composed of water but blood as well. Even from this location, he could feel the vengeful spirits gathering around it along with signs of decomposing bodies swimming in it.

‘Are they trying to attract more decrepit souls to feast on them by leaving all those bodies there?’

When looking from the outside he realized that the place was similar to a soul-attracting formation. Some kind of occult ritual had taken place to create a soul gathering location. It was somewhat similar to the one he first met these monsters in but here they weren’t consuming all of the souls by letting them fester and grow into stronger ones instead.

All the trees and lifeforms that resided here seemed to be dead. Nothing that could be considered alive was left behind as a wasteland had been created. This place was supposed to have been similar to a rainforest but the only thing left behind was a dried-up river filled with bones of various beasts.

“How quaint, a pentagram huh?”

With his ability to fly he put himself above his own flying armada. From this vantage point, he could see five large towers that were connected by large walls. Together they formed a pentagram that was visible when looking down. Even without getting closer, he could tell that some kind of occult spell was being sustained by those towers.

“Everyone stop!”

Zhang Dong moved his hand up into the air while shouting toward his people. Without missing a beat they all stopped instantly as if their lives depended on following that order. They wouldn’t be wrong in their assumption, if they decided to continue further their souls would indeed be in jeopardy.

“Don’t push in further, there is some kind of soul-sapping spell around this place.”

He had learned various soul arts and spells concerning them. While other cultivators could not see it there was a peculiar barrier there. It was not something that could halt their advance as anyone could pass through it but then it would already be too late. When inside anyone would have their soul energy siphoned away and soon die. This power would go through any conventional protective formations and even some strong soul-protective talismans that his people were equipped with.

“Execute the plan now and don’t pass through these coordinates.”

A lot of technology was created with the help of his crafting abode. The map in the system had a coordinate system that was now used by his sect, thanks to this he could safely locate the safe zone for his people. The ships under his command were now slowly moving to the sides and spreading out at various elevations. It was probably a strange sight to behold for the vampires inside this palace but soon they would see what Zhang Dong’s sect had in store for them.

‘They don’t seem to be throwing their best at us yet…’

While some of the demi-humans were tossing themselves against the protective barrier they weren’t coming in a big force. It seemed that they were either sure of his forces not being able to move forward or they had some kind of plan in motion. The second option was more plausible as the moment his ships started aligning with each other the castle started glowing.

The towers composed of multiple spikes started out giving out gray energy that slowly turned crimson. While most could not see what was happening Zhang Dong could feel the souls rising up from all of these dead bodies. The quantity and quality of those dead specters was truly immense.

‘If it was any other sect besides mine they would probably have trouble containing all of these spirits that can’t be contained with conventional means but…’

Zhang Dong raised his finger up towards the sky. The moment he did a thin ray of golden light escaped and traveled upwards. Without as much as a bang, the mist was spread apart to reveal the sunny sky above it. This approach was specifically calculated by taking the sun's location into consideration and now it was time to give their secret weapon against these vampires a test run.

The moment the sun appeared above them a loud noise escaped from one of the larger transport ships in the back. A large circular object was propelled up into the stratosphere and stopped in mid-air without falling down. It was a giant lens surrounded by golden metal that was procured from a certain Golden Palace. To the side of it there were strange runic patterns along with various gems that allowed it to float in one location without falling down.

Zhang Dong looked at this large magnifying glass that was slowly aligning itself to catch the sun’s rays. During this process of alignment, various ships revealed large panels with mirrors on them. These mirrors were pointing at an angle towards the massive castle occupied by the vampires.

“Here you go, enjoy your tan, you vampire bastards!”

He appeared behind the floating lens with one hand behind his back and the other pointing towards the sun. The solar rays were easy to manifest and all of them would be concentrated on the giant lens. With its help, he would bathe the entire place in bright light and with a pinch of his holy dao it would become the bane of both the vampires and decrepit souls.

A note from Kuropon

Thank you for reading!

Don't forget to follow, favorite, rate.

Donate | Discord |

Chapter 497

“My Lord, what shall we do?”

“We don’t need to do anything, the prey has just served themselves to us on a silver platter, the spirits of the damned will devour them all!”

An angry-looking vampire lord was sitting on his throne while looking towards something that looked like a red mirror. This was not a simple mirror as it rippled whenever changing the view or angle instead, it was a vertical puddle of blood. At this very moment, they were looking at a large armada of strange flying ships that had halted their progress just outside the range of one of their protective spells.

“My lord, they have stopped, they seem to be aware of our blood magics!”

“I can see that you idiot!”

The lady vampire that was giving the vampire lord information found herself losing her head after a quick finger movement. She quickly burst into a puddle of blood that just soaked into the dark brick floor. Another lady that looked exactly the same took her place but remained silent out of fright of punishment.

“Is it that bastard?”

Valentine the leader of this vampire tribe squinted before motioning the pool of water closer. There he focused his gaze on someone that he recognized and was still furious with. The man was clearly the same person that forced him to use his rebirthing technique that took hundreds of years to prepare. Now if he died there would be no coming back like before and running away was not an option.

“If I leave, the Emperor will kill me…”

The man slammed his fist down making the hand rest crumble into dust. By pointing out toward the pool of blood an image above the whole castle came into view. He started mumbling some occult words that produced a bubbling in the moat made by many of his victims. Soon the souls that were being gathered started rising out and focusing their rage on the targets he specified.

“All these souls have been corrupted by me, even if that idiot can absorb them he will surely be tainted by my blood magic!”

All of the souls here had been infected by his own will. They would not only contaminate the soul of whoever they touched but also their body. It was like a curse that would spread from body to body and soon turn everyone into a mindless slave to his will.

“Wait, what is that?”

While he was commanding all of those souls towards the flying ships he saw the man push all the mist to the side to reveal the sun. Even though it was there it could not pierce through the barrier of darkness that was around his castle. At first, he thought that his enemy made a poor choice but soon enough he started seeing strange contraptions being put into place.

“What is their intention?”

Even though he didn’t know what all of those ships were doing he didn’t like it. There was something they intended to do with that sun. The souls were slowly on their way but the sun would slow them down slightly.

“Use the sacrifices! We must protect my castle!”

“As you command my lord!”

The replacement vampire woman bowed before quickly running out of this throne room. In but a moment of time screams could be heard around the whole castle. All the pools of blood started bubbling up while filling up with fresh blood from some of the prepared offerings.

Outside the castle, the moat that was reacting in a similar fashion started shooting out torrents of liquids into the sky. It was as if several geysers had erupted from five locations close to the focal points of the pentagram locations. They pushed themselves outwardly creating a large-scale shield that was meant to keep everything out.

This was in the nick of time as their enemies from the United Element Sect had completed their formation. The Golden One that they had now identified as Long Dong was shining brightly like a stare before that giant lense and even the vampire leader could feel the energy here.

“Kill more sacrifices!”

Valentine was astonished by what he was seeing and quickly ordered the slaughter. It was clear to him that his opponents were aware of their weakness, which was the sun. After more groans and shouts, the blood fountain expanded even more to produce a dark crimson barrier composed of thick blood.

Soon the ray of golden light was shot towards the giant lens in the sky. Like a huge magnifying glass the solar beam was condensed towards a large array of mirrors that were on one of the ships. Various strange symbols appeared around this ship before the beam spread out to other side vessels that pushed the beam towards the occult barrier.

The vengeful souls that had left the confinement of the castle were instantly burned up by the mix of holy and solar energies. Due to the high amount of corrupted energy in them they were only more susceptible to them than regular souls. With the evil spirits out of the way the big solar spotlight illuminated the whole vampire palace from the outside.

Thanks to the barrier created from blood the vampires on the inside could relax. All of them looked to the leader that had saved them by thinking fast and activating it before their enemies could finish their plan but something was wrong. Before they could congratulate Valentine on his quick wits they saw his facial expression, one that they didn’t see often.

Recently whenever the Golden one was brought up their leader had a look of anger. Many lesser vampires were sacrificed to ease it through the weeks after the resurrection ritual took place. Yet never did they see him be scared or falter.

“M-my Lord? Are you feeling unwell?”

Asked one of the vampires as they weren’t sure what that expression foreshadowed. It was a new mannerism that they were not familiar with, it was fear. Everyone expected the lackey to be instantly murdered but instead, their leader kept his eyes on the blood screen that slowly began bubbling even more.

“No, this is impossible… How can they do this to me? Where are the other tribe leaders, contact them, they must all come here to protect the fortress, the Emperor will be furious with them!”

Instead of killing the vampire that dared to speak up, he started screaming at everyone else. The vampire tribesmen started shaking as they knew that the other tribe leaders would not be coming.

“My Lord, the other tribe leaders are occupied…”

“Occupied? Those scoundrels!”

With a wave of his hand, he forcefully crushed two of the lesser vampires to add their blood to the vertical pool of blood. With the addition of their blood, it was able to show him the other tribe leaders. One of them was fighting what looked to be a man clad in golden armor while the other was fleeing from some kind of demonic creature made from fire energy.

“Useless, everyone is useless… prepare for battle, it won’t hold!”

There was nothing that he could do, if he decided to flee then the Emperor would kill him. This fortress could not fall into the hands of the Golden One that proved himself to be more than just simple prey. If he managed to conquer this location then their access to this bridge here would become questionable, perhaps even the Emperor would need to move to reclaim it.

“If the Emperor is forced to move then I will be done for!”

He grabbed a crimson-colored heavy rapier from the side along with a long black cape. The moment he did he could feel the blood walls caving in on them. Soon his enemies would pierce through the defenses he thought were impenetrable…

…

‘Just a bit more…’

Zhang Dong was floating up in the sky while focusing all of his holy energy on the lense. Thanks to knowing his enemy's weak point he had his blacksmiths develop this magnifying lens. It would focus the solar rays along with his holy energy and spread it out towards the enemy fortress.

To his surprise, they had some kind of strange barrier composed of blood. Luckily it was also susceptible to the solar rays and divine energy mixed inside of it. While this ray of spread-out light would not be able to crush a regular defensive barrier it was quickly dismantling this evil one.

It wasn’t an easy feat though, this place was supposed to be one of the main bases. He expected a lot of resistance if he went by just brute-forcing his way in. Without his cultivation methods being the weakness of his enemies and having help from Argus and the knights there was no way of him getting in there without losing half of his own forces but now the barrier was cracking.

‘Hold on a little more…’

The lens that he created could barely contain the energies it was focusing down. It would certainly not last forever and it was the same for the many mirrors that were spreading the energy out.

Suddenly he heard a strange explosion that caused a massive tidal wave. It connected with the mobile defensive formation which barely managed to hold it back. He could see some of the cultivators on the ships passing out along with others losing all spiritual energy they had in their reserves.

Almost simultaneously the lense he was focusing his energies on finally gave out. It just started melting from the center and then outwardly until there was nothing left than the golden outer shell.

‘I guess we were lucky again this time around…’

He wasn’t sure if he was the luckiest man alive or not. While the lens was now broken and most of the mirrors along with it, the path forward was now clear. The explosion that occurred was just the last bang before the bloody barrier collapsed before them. Yet this had also taken out the mobile protective barrier from around his armada which put all of his people in danger.

‘Ten percent of the cultivators were knocked out but they are still alive…’

The people that suffered from Qi deprivation were being quickly pulled away by the medical units. No one had died yet but they would have a hard time coming back to aid them in the coming fight. On the other side, he could feel many demi-humans in that ghoulish castle.

“Everyone, this is what we were waiting for, take no prisoners! Let none of these evil creatures survive!”

“In the name of the Sect!”

“For the Patriarch!”

Everyone cheered as they descended towards the unknown fortress, their morale high as their Patriarch was with them, and with him, there was no way of losing.

‘It all starts with this…’

A note from Kuropon

Thank you for reading!

Don't forget to follow, favorite, rate.

Donate | Discord |

Chapter 498

“Stay in formation, don’t attack them alone!”

“Use the solar pills on them!”

“Drown them out with cannon fire!”

Everyone was shouting while a massive large-scale battle was taking place both up in the air and down on the ground. Loud shrieks of beings with wings were making regular communication difficult. Even though the demi-human tribes had fewer members their concentration at this point almost made the number equal.

‘There appears to be some type of secondary barrier at that central tower…’

Zhang Dong’s sword traveled in a horizontal line cleaving many red vampires in the process. He was advancing along with the vanguard that was composed of several nascent soul masters and core formation experts using battle formations. Keeping to their tactic they were forcing the monsters to battle them at a range while using various protective spells to counter their soul-draining capabilities.

Not that far away he could see the large gloomy-looking palace that was radiating dark crimson energies. Even though the moat had been drained out of most of the blood some of it remained. Their own protective barrier was also broken which now allowed some of the demi-humans to board some of the ships. Both sides were taking casualties but the United Element Sect was able to advance into the enemy lines.

‘That’s where their leader must be hidden but it doesn’t seem that he will come out on his own accord…’

Even when they were blasting the surroundings with cannon fire he could not see the vampire leader anywhere. What he was encountering were the demi-humans with the smaller horns that could not hold out against him at all. Even when they grouped up he just needed to use his swordsmanship to be victorious.

‘I’ve used a lot of Qi to destroy that barrier.’

This was not something that he chose to do, if he could then another full-power beam blast would be already flying towards the standing castle. His spiritual energy reserves needed to be conserved as the battle could shift at any moment. This is why he was engaging the monsters in close-range combat to conserve his power which was aimed at killing the vampire lord.

The assault was progressing smoothly and everything was within their calculations. Their enemies were certainly ill-prepared to protect their fortress. Probably due to the fast counter-attack they had not been able to reinforce their position. This war was supposed to last a hundred years and normally no sect would be able to stop their regular soldiers from advancing. There was just no reason to build up defenses if their side was assured of their victory.

Yet even though their defenses weren’t that great this didn’t mean that they could just waltz in there. Besides the red vampires, there were all sorts of strange zombie-like beasts down on the ground. Some of them looked like decomposing giants that would be tiresome to contend with as they were giving out poisonous mist with each step they took.

Up in the air were also various flying beasts, not only the demi-humans. They looked of course like giant bloodthirsty bats that were the size of elephants. Some of the demi-humans were using them as mounts and trying to ram them into the flying sect ships. Then to top it off there were various ballistas and cannons up on the towers. Even as he was flying forward they were trying to kill his mostly flying forces.

“Bahamut, come out.”

Zhang Dong pointed forward and before him burst out a small golden dragon that quickly started shifting in size. Soon enough he reached a massive size that overshadowed the other giant beasts that the enemies were using. Without needing to give him a command the dragon tossed itself into a bloody battle with the flying squadron of mounted demi-human soldiers.

“Everyone, keep advancing! Surround them and don’t let anyone escape.”

Even he could see that his side was winning but before victory could be claimed the fortress needed to be breached. For this purpose he would toss himself into danger, if he was victorious then less of his people would need to be sacrificed. It would be easy to just stand here and wait for the barrier to give out but twiddling his thumbs was not something he was inclined to do.

“Zhang Zhi, take command of the forces, I will go take the head of their leader.”

“Patriarch… Understood, I will do as you command.”

Zhang Dong could tell that Zhi wanted to tell him something by the tone of his voice. Normally a group of elite elders would be sent into the castle instead. The leaders of sects would very rarely endanger their lives or even take part in battles. Only when an enemy that could not be defeated by anyone else appeared would they act.

His descent was followed up by a giant explosion as he rammed straight into the main tower. The barrier there was ill-prepared to compete with his holy energies and quickly shattered. When on the other side he stopped in mid-air only to notice that the barrier was quickly mending itself back.

“It’s quiet… too quiet…”

The dark crimson barrier was making it hard to see the things on the inside and also on the outside. Zhang Dong expected to be assaulted from all sides the moment he entered this area but was left with no enemies. This was problematic as a simple fight between masters was usually easier than if one was trying to conceal themselves.

‘I hope that the slimy bastard doesn’t just flee somewhere…’

He had already witnessed some of the demi-humans abandoning their post to save their lives. This vampire lord would not be a hard opponent for him but anyone else would certainly die. If these monsters escape into the empire just more people would die and a lot of resources would be wasted to find them.

‘Would their leader kill him for failing his mission?’

This was the big question, if the vampire thought that he had no choice he would remain here. Demonic cultivators carried themselves in a similar manner, if someone failed their task they would be severely punished by their leader. If he was convinced that the Emperor would kill them after losing the fortress then he could not escape.

‘Probably the other demi-humans would not help him either but drag him to their Emperor for an execution…’

After analyzing their culture this was Zhang Dong’s impression of these tribes. They were barbaric people that loved to hunt other races. They had a clear strength-based hierarchy system similar to the ones in demonic sects where compassion was seen as a weakness. They would clearly abandon their allies if they deemed them unusable.

With that in mind, he readied his sword while venturing toward the castle. In front of him was a giant spooky gate with skulls for handles. When he approached it the gate doors started slowly opening themselves up. The moment they did he surrounded himself with a layer of holy energy. This was just in time as he was hit by a strong gust of wind carrying various curse energies with it.

“Hm… So I guess he wants me to go through this…”

It was clear to him that whoever was inside that castle was expecting him. If he walked inside he was sure that some strange trap would be activated. Perhaps he would be teleported into another location and put through some kind of maze with traps. The whole place also smelled of chaotic spatial energy which made things problematic.

‘Is that the plan? Tire me out by trapping me in some sub-dimension…’

He could think of a few things that Valentine was planning. The most basic approach would be to put him through some long course filled with monsters, traps, and pain. Then whenever he was tired or lost his focus the demi-human leader would show up out of the blue to deliver the last blow.

‘I bet he would bore me with some kind of long speech about me being stupid for entering his lair. I guess that would be stupid…’

Zhang Dong started rubbing his chin while looking at the front gate. While he did not think any of the traps inside would pose a problem, they would certainly put him at a disadvantage and also waste a lot of time. Thus he started backing away while instead looking around and also at his map.

“Hm… I see, that’s actually smart”

When looking up a person would normally think that the last boss would be right at the top of this tower. The building was really tall, taller than the biggest skyscraper from his old homeworld. But that was not the spot that he needed to go, instead, he focused his gaze on the ground below him where his enemy lurked.

‘Analisis complete, sending over coordinates.’

‘Thanks a bunch, Bob.’

While whistling around he moved his sword up into the air and performed a few practice swings. Then he focused his gaze up towards the peak of the tower that was hard to make out due to the dark crimson mist floating around it. With the sword in hand, he went into a thrusting stance as if he was going to push his weapon towards the sky.

His energies surrounded the blade causing it to glow brightly. The miasma that was in the air was pushed back as he covered the entire area with blinding lights. His gaze turned away from the top of the tower as he peeked to the side. There, a small creature that was an eye was promptly blinded.

He had been aware that something was watching him the moment he entered this area. Valentine had proven to be very cowardly during their fight but he could not flee due to his position. Thus instead of placing himself in the throne room that was up in the sky, he was down below. A large set of maze-like dungeons spawned throughout the underground reaching almost the same deepness as the height of the palace.

“Take this!”

Finally, his attack was complete and instead of thrusting to the top of the tower, he aimed it at the ground. His thrust was followed by a loud thunderous bang that caused almost all of the stained glass windows in this fortress to instantly shatter.

“... HOW! “

The speed of this sword art was truly immense and it split the ground like it was water. Almost instantly afterward he could hear the vampire lord screaming out in anger. Yet this was not over yet, his thrusts continued to be plunged into the hard soil producing a massive number of large perfectly circular holes.

“How could I not find you when you make yourself this obvious?”

Zhang Dong replied while halting his attack. His opponent hastily burst out from underground bringing with him a giant dirt explosion. His body was in tatters and each wound was radiating holy energies. Finally, the master of the fortress had revealed himself and it was time to put him down.

Chapter 499

“Damn, is he really going to morb?”

Zhang Dong looked up towards his enemy who was transforming into something else. It was some kind of strange cross between a human and bat monster with giant claws for hands and quite the ugly face. Before the change, the man called Valentine could be considered handsome but now he was just an ugly monster.

“Even if you saw through my traps, this is my domain, I am the Emperor here and everything has to bend to my will!”

The horn on his forehead started to expand while giving away a pulsating red light. Without needing to do much he could tell that all the vengeful spirits around the area were being sucked towards this area. Even the other vampiric tribe people were getting their energies sucked away. This demi-human was a soul sucker and he was clearly intending to absorb all of his tribe members to gain another boost in power.

“Do you actually think I’ll just sit here and let you power up?”

There was a big weak spot in this whole plan, which was Zhang Dong himself. Who in their right mind would just twiddle their thumbs and wait while their enemy reaches a higher power threshold? Even if he didn’t think that the vampire could reach anything above a certain point there was no reason to make a gamble.

Thus instead of just waiting here, Zhan Dong activated his own radiant aura to counter this blood spell. Without his soul core being there he could not absorb all of these souls himself anymore, instead, he could purify them. In some strange way, all these souls were somehow connected to this vampire lord, if he could alter this connection there was a big chance of him not being able to absorb them.

‘No, he won’t be able to absorb them even if he wanted to.’

After smiling he allowed his aura to spread in all directions. Various magical circles started appearing as he yet again combined his spiritual energy with mana. There was a spell used by clerics from the other world called ‘Turn Undead’. With a bit of ingenuity, he could emulate the effect while also forcing a bit of his holy dao into these souls. They would be purged of all malice and occult curses that were used to bind them to this vampire overlord.

His opponent had made the whole takeover a lot easier with this blunder. By stripping his people of their vital energies and trying to absorb them himself, the whole battle had ended almost instantly. The United Element Sect members watched with astonishment as all the red vampires dropped dead to the ground. Only a few of the stronger ones were able to resist their master's call but more than ninety percent of them were now down for the count.

“It does not matter what you do, this Valentine can not be stopped!... huh?”

The mastermind behind his people's demise started laughing as he thought that his victory was assured. Yet suddenly the souls that he had dominated started not replying to his calls. The moment they collided with Zhang Dong’s radiant spell they started being cleansed from all evil energies that they were altered by.

Without the need to adhere to the absorption spell they just started drifting away into the sky and quickly dissolving. With Zhang Dong’s aura being here they would not turn into decrepit souls either.

“No, what is this? I order you to stop, you will be bound to my will!”

“Oh, I don’t think so.”

Zhang Dong was sure to block any attempts of this vampire lord to call the souls here. While they had been cleansed they could still be absorbed by him in this state. While the faint holy energies in them would make it harder they could still be corrupted by the evil energies that the vampires possessed.

“You will stay right here and take this boot.”

Before Valentine could fly towards the mass of souls he was kicked in the face by his opponent. This kick sent him right back down to the ground where he came from. Without the worry of his opponent powering up now, he could start the counterattack. His kicks and punches rained down and even if he tried, Valentine was just not fast nor powerful enough to resist.

“Y-you…”

The demi-human leader appeared far up in the sky with a body riddled with holes. The punches and kicks that he had to suffer through weren’t normal, each one of them was supplied with solar energy and the dao of the divine. Even when the monstrous vampire wanted to regenerate his body, he couldn’t.

Without any other option, he started to flee, the fortress was important but his life was more precious to him than anything else. Even though the Emperor would kill him as long as he hid away until the great hunt was over then perhaps he could survive as an outlaw. There was always an option to rebuild his lost tribe, as long as he was alive he could create more vampire beings.

“Where do you think you are going.”

“What? How can you be here…”

“Do you really think that I wouldn’t be able to see through your tricks and illusions? You escaped me once but your life ends here.”

Valentine’s monstrous eyes went wide after he heard a voice behind him. There was not even enough time for him to turn around before something cleaved his body into two perfect halves. These sides started to slowly part, the holy energy of the sword being used to perform the slice made reform impossible.
“Disappear.”

Zhang Dong shouted while sticking his hand out. From this palm a wide burst of energy escaped, it covered the parting monster's whole body and quickly disintegrated it into fine particles. Perhaps if Valentine was facing another master he might have been able to escape with his soul but to his surprise even it was being burned away by this attack. There was nothing remaining, his body and soul had disintegrated into nothingness.

“Hm… Is he really dead?”

This enemy had been a pain in the behind before but he was almost certain that he had managed to destroy him this time around. Just as he had predicted the previous life-saving method could not be used again and his soul had been destroyed. All that was left was rounding up the remaining demi-humans and the victory would be assured.

“But to be on the safe side…”

During the fight he had attuned himself to Valentine’s soul signature after defeating him he could identify if any shards were left behind. This was a useful method of preserving oneself, masters sometimes used a fragment of their soul behind. Even though they would not be able to retain their might there was a chance of survival.

“Let’s see… hah… that fucker…”

If he wasn’t cautious he would have certainly let his enemy escape but after using a soul tracking spell he found something. A shard of Valentine’s soul was slowly escaping but he was not in any of the other demi-humans that were here.

‘Smart bastard, he probably wanted me to focus on the remaining vampires.”

“There you are…”

It didn’t take him long to home in on the new target, with a few quick bursts of speed he descended into the distance where a blac kbird was making its escape. Inside this bird, he could feel a tiny fraction of his enemy remaining.

“Got you, Valentine.”

“Gwack!”

The small creature could fit into his hand and was clearly the person that he was fighting with before.

“N-no please don’t kill me!”

“Oh, so you want to live? I bet all your tribe members wanted to live to but you killed them anyway.”

“N-no, you can’t kill me!”

“Hm…”

While he could easily just crush this small bird there was another option. The soul shard that remained still had all of Valentine’s memories and knowledge but none of his power. If left alone he would probably start off sucking away the souls of regular animals until going for human prey. This he could not allow but Valentine’s knowledge could come in handy, it was not time to kill him yet.

“Very well, I’ll decide your fate later, for now get in here and be quiet.”

A small birdcage popped out of his spatial ring into which he tossed the bird in. With it being so weak it would be unable to even get out if it. Then to make sure that his enemy didn’t have any more tricks he was tossed into the replica medallion. Inside there he could try to escape but he would not be able to leave the treasure that was attuned to his will.

‘Well then, let's wrap things up here…’

With the boss being taken care of only a few lackeys were left behind. Valentine had almost single-handedly helped him to minimize the damages to his sect. Perhaps if he used his people as more than disposable pawns he would have been able to cause long-lasting damage to his forces.

Thanks to him capturing the leader it was unnecessary to leave the rest of the monsters alive. It also seemed that without their leader around they were acting differently. Before they would toss themselves at their enemies to the last survivor but now on the other hand they were fleeing. Perhaps Valentine was mind-controlling all of them and with him being reduced to a shard they were finally free.

“Give chase, don’t allow any of those monsters to escape!”

He shouted out while tossing himself back into the battle. His energies were mostly drained but he had enough in his tank to take care of these lesser demi-human leaders. On the other side of the conflict, the battle was also reaching the apex. Lucius together with Argus were successful in slaying the tribe leader of the bone-covered demi-humans. Huo Qiang wasn’t as lucky as his enemy had managed to escape but all in all, it was a victory for their side.

Phase one of their plan was almost over, by defeating the demi-human tribe that was holding the fortress they were now able to move in. Various ships with sect workers started appearing from behind and moving in. Even though the enemies were routed they still needed to secure this location. Before anything else could move in through that bridge they needed to block it off.

The large castle that was left standing was ill-equipped for such a purpose. What they required was to bring over their own structures. Thanks to the technology from the secret ground he brought over this could now be tackled by his architects that were already waiting to disembark. The time to shift the tide of battle would begin with this victory and would soon spread the name of the United Element Sect through the whole Azure Dragon Empire.

Chapter 500

“That’s enough! Bring out the heavenly framework, don’t you dare drop any if you do you will be sent down into the spirit stone mines!”

A group of United Element Sect members that had a symbol of a hammer on the back of their robes was transporting a new product that the sect had managed to produce. It didn’t look like much, just a bunch of hollow tubes of various shapes and sizes. They seemed to fit into each other and were now being connected before the large bridge between the empires.

With time the whole construction looked like a big flimsy scaffolding. Some of the sect members that weren’t informed wondered if their brothers would start building a wall there but in such circumstances where they could be attacked at any moment how could they start building?

Something strange happened after one of the frames that looked like a large tower was completed. From the outside, it looked like something made from toothpicks but suddenly the whole structure started growing. The thin rods that were combined with each other started filling out the empty space between them with something similar to gray concrete. The change was rapid and soon a whole tower made of sturdy stone was standing.

“Is this the new innovative building technology that was being kept secret by the building faction?”

Some of the warriors commented from the side while their eyes opened wider. Only about a day had passed since they had taken over this part of the border and some stragglers were out there. They even managed to kill a few that tried running back into their own lands back through the bridge.

“Patriarch, please this way.”

“It’s the Patriarch!”

Various sect members that were here instantly dropped what they were doing as their leader arrived. To them everything was made possible by this one man, their survival was tied to his steady increase in power. Many rumors were spread that he might have been some kind of reincarnated immortal that was hiding his true identity. It didn’t matter though, he had blessed them with his knowledge and now their sect was among the strongest in this Empire.

“I see that you have managed to keep your promise but will it hold?”

“You don’t have to worry Patriarch, it might not look like much but these walls won’t be easily breached.”

“Is that so?”

Everyone was holding their heads down as the leader arrived. They were sure to strain their ears to catch each word that he was saying as telling tales of meeting the Patriarch would be something worth mentioning at a family get-together.

“I’ll give it a small test then…”

What was this test the leader was talking about? They couldn’t fathom his true intentions but after a moment they heard a loud thumping noise coming from the direction of the gray tower that was quickly constructed. All of them quickly raised their heads in fear that their camp was being attacked but instead they saw a palm mark from which many cracks were coming out.

“Hm, it should be enough to deflect some cannonballs… good, go ahead and resume construction. Everyone go back to work and be vigilant! We ”

“Yes, Patriarch!”

Everyone shouted while Zhang Dong floated away towards the previously gloomy-looking castle. After the take over all of the dark mist had disappeared along with the miasma. Without the evil energy soaking, everything up the structure looked a lot more reserved.

….

‘The walls didn’t collapse after a punch so it should be able to survive hits from a lower realm nascent soul master.’

Zhang Dong was floating away while looking at the quick construction of the walls and guard towers. Two large ones would be placed on each side and then smaller ones would follow soon after. A large wall reaching up to the skies was going to be created and many defensive formations and weapons to defend this location would also be brought here.

‘I have this place's coordinates saved so I can return here at any point in time too.’

The battle was over and it was a sound victory. He had managed to use his forces to capture this place not even a year into the war. With this location secured he would be able to expand his influence further. That is if he could successfully use this base and counter any enemy attacks that might come.

“You have kept us waiting long enough, where is he?”

“Hah, he will get there when he wants!”

“Why you …”

“Please lord Lucius be calm.”

“How can I be calm, my men have died and we still haven’t found the secret blade, what if he had tricked us into fighting his wars?”

His ears picked up an argument in the distance. Huo Qiang and a few other nascent soul elders were keeping the golden knights company. After the siege of the fortress, he was quite busy with making sure that everything went smoothly. There were still many strange items inside the castle so it was forbidden for anyone to go in before he did a sweep.

Argus along with Lucius had arrived half a day ago after defeating one of the demi-human leaders. All they wanted to do was to get their holy relic and be on their way. They weren’t convinced that it was actually here anymore. Their detection device was not picking up anything, thus they thought that Zhang Dong had lied to them.

They were only half right as the item was in his possession. The only reason that he didn’t present it to them was to not make it more suspicious than it already was. If he instantly pulled it out they would surely discover that he had it on him before they even attacked. Perhaps they would have forgiven him for his lie after receiving the item but it was better not to make a bad impression on the two. Perhaps in the future, he could ask them for more aid.

“Argus, Lucius there you are, I have been looking for you, I think that I might have found what you have been looking for.”

“There you are, you won’t talk yourself out of… you found it?”

After Lucius noticed that Zhang Dong appeared he was ready to give him some strong words but the moment he mentioned that he had the relic the knight was stunned.

“Of course, what do you take me for?”

“A …”

“Don’t answer that, here. I think this should be it.”

Before Lucius could start listing down Zhang Dong’s faults before his sect members, a large chest appeared on the ground. He had found it inside Valentine’s castle and it was perfect to hold the holy relic that was once part of a bed. The moment the chest appeared from within his spatial ring there was a change in the medallion.

“It’s reacting? Could this really be it?”

“Let me see my Lord!”

Argus could see that the medallion that Lucius was wearing was faintly reacting to the presented chest. In reality, the one that was blocking the holy energy from flowing outside was Zhang Dong himself. Only after lifting the chest outside of his range could their device react to it.

“This…”

The wizard held out what looked to be a part of a sword hilt with both his hands. They started to quickly shake after he activated various identifying spells that confirmed that this was the item that they were really looking for. Lucius moved the medallion closer and when it touched the relic it started giving out a strange chime.
“Is it the treasure that you were looking for?”

“It is… we have found the Holy Sword of legends!”

Lucius held the piece of the sword and almost instantly tried to activate it. The rise in holy energy caused the nascent soul masters to pull out their weapons. This in turn made the golden knights move forward with their own blades drawn. Only when Zhang Dong and Argus moved their hands up did they stop with their approach.

“It’s fine, stand back.”

“Please lower your swords knights.”

“I…”

“Lord Lucius, only the hero can awaken the holy sword, we must bring it back to the kingdom and await his coming”

“Yes Wizard, I do know the old legend…”

The swordmaster looked disappointed as even after he continued he could not make the relic budge. Even Zhang Dong whose understanding of the divine arts was much better could only slightly make the item move. It was something specially created for a different setting and thus probably locked away by the system. While he could try to get Bob to decode the problem there was no time.

‘I guess they will now retreat back to their kingdom, I probably can’t expect them to help me anymore from this point on.’

He was a bit disappointed as the knights were capable allies. After giving them their relic they would probably see him as a friend. Yet when they had received what they required there was no reason for them to stay here anymore unless they also wanted to push in to get more resources or land.

“Isn’t this a blessing Lord Lucius, now if we can find the Holy Aegis then we will be able to go back home!”

“The what now?”

A name that he was not familiar with was mentioned, was there another relic that these two were searching for that they didn’t mention? It seemed that he was not the only person withholding information.

“If you will allow me, Lord Lucius, I think Lord Dong has proven himself as a trusted ally…”

“That he did, you must apologize for my previous behavior Sir Dong but you must understand that I had to be careful. Go ahead Argus, you have my permission.”

The stern knight commander that found fault with him at various junctions was now bowing his head. He was mistrusting to the very end but now after they had reclaimed a part of the treasure, there was more trust.

“The holy sword is but a part of the treasured relic, there is another one in the shape of a shield. Only when the two come together will the hero of the legend be able to defeat the demonic king and bring peace to our world!”

“Is that so…”

With this revelation, he realized that his new friends wouldn’t be leaving just yet. There was another part to the puzzle that could have been anywhere. If the sword was at the golden palace then the other piece was probably somewhere in the enemy territory.

“Well then, I hope that we can also aid each other in the future.”

All in all, it wasn’t such a bad thing, with his relationship with these knights increasing he would gain strong allies. Perhaps they would even help him to capture the second demi-human fortress now.

‘This ended better than I expected…’

A note from Kuropon

Thank you for reading!

Don't forget to follow, favorite, rate.

Donate | Discord |

Chapter 501

‘So now I have to keep a lookout for a magical shield, where could something like that be? I’m not sure I have any time right now, luckily they left me that thing. My little informant didn’t give me much information though, at least I’ll be able to move from here soon…’

Zhang Dong was reflecting on what had happened some time ago. For the time being, he was stuck sitting at the bridge between Empires protecting his people. They were building massive walls and inscribing defensive formations everywhere. The new fortress that would be defended by his people needed to be able to block the way into his lands.

It had been a whole month since his hostile takeover. This time he needed to mostly spend hovering in the sky with his radar out. It was similar to the time he had to protect his sect from any spies and just like before there had been some attempts. Various tribes from the demi-human side were trying to gather information while wandering closer in smaller groups.

Yet no large-scale skirmish had erupted, the demi-human presence was slowly being drowned out as they retreated north to where their second fortress was. It was quite a stressful month for him as the Emperor of the demi-humans might have decided to attack. Valentine was forced to cough up some information but it didn’t really help much.

The Emperor seemed to just be the strongest member of all the demi-human tribes. Every ten years they would host a tournament where everyone could participate. The winner would become their leader, only strength counted in their society, and family ties were nonexistent. His kids would need to defeat their father if they ever wanted their position and could easily be then vanquished by a rival tribe member.

This Emperor apparently had been in power for over five hundred years. At this point, no one was confident in beating him in an honorable way. Even when the battle tournament started only the foolhardy participated and were massacred while tribe leaders like Valentine sat back and watched. Only if they spotted some kind of weakness in their leader would they attempt to sink their claws into his neck.

Besides the power structure and the notable tribes, there was not much that Valentine could disclose. The Emperor was apparently so overpowering that his new informant could not list any weak points. How strong this enemy was compared to someone like him or the Azure Emperor was unknown.

Then there was the issue with his new partners that were not out of the picture yet. Perhaps after he found their holy shield they would suddenly require divine armor from him. Luckily his task was made easier by them handing over a tracking device. After he proved that he would be helpful they put some trust in him.

“Hm? Speaking of the devil.”

While contemplating his next move he noticed a certain item that was vibrating. He quickly waved his hand and a crystal orb popped out. After injecting some mana into it he was greeted by the face of his wizard friend, Argus.

“Greetings my friend.”
“Hey Argus, what can I help you with?”

“Ho ho, I can’t ask for any more help, you have already done so much for us, I just wished to give my gratitude again, those emblems that you gave me worked like a charm!”

“Is that so, did any of the sects or clans complain or were they accomodating?”

“They were surprisingly cooperative, your name alone was enough to make them kneel, this will truly aid us immensely in our quest!”

Zhang Dong smiled at the wizard that had been more relaxed ever since their first meeting. It seemed that his commanding officer Lucius was now actually listening to this powerful mage for once.

“Good but be wary of the Heavenly Crane sect and the Long Clan, they might not put as much respect into my name like the others.”

“Aye, we will keep that in mind.”

“Just keep Lucius out of trouble, if he attacks those people you’ll be in more trouble than necessary.”

Argus started laughing but Zhang Dong was serious. The Heavenly Crane sect would probably have enough power to go against the magic knights that had lost some of their knights in the last battle. He expected the people from the magical kingdom to be victorious if it ever came down to it but that would weaken his side.

‘The Heavenly Crane Sect has a lot of their sub-sects in the eastern regions, they probably have already suffered some losses from the Emerald Phoenix Empire but as long as they can keep them busy it should be fine.’

After the conversation was over a group of elders from the building faction arrived to make a report. The whole area around the bridge had been worked on by his people with no time for sleep.

“Patriarch, we are finished with the first main stage of the construction, the base formations are ready for you.”

“Good, let’s go.”

He nodded and moved towards the gigantic wall that had been established here. The bridge that the wall was blocking luckily had a ceiling. They had just enough to make it halfway there but with the addition of the defensive formation, it could be fully blocked off. Now he just needed to add some of his own spiritual energy to jump-start it.

Thus he floated right before the long construction and onto the middle tower. With the two largest on each side, there were exactly nine smaller ones on the inside. He took a seat on the middle one that was also a lot larger than the other ones around it. This was the center point of the protective formation and needed to have most of the defenses.

‘I hope this will be enough…’

The coffers of the sect had been emptied to develop this defensive structure. The demi-humans didn’t stock up on resources that cultivators used so receiving compensation was hard. The only thing they could do was to ransack the abandoned clan abodes and sect grounds that were devoid of people.

Soon the mostly gray walls started pulsating with power. Magical circles together with various characters started to light up as the whole formation system was activated. In the middle of it was Zhang Dong, just sitting down and concentrating. He needed to drain all of his power so that if the enemies came they would not easily break these defenses.

Not far away were Huo Qiang and Zhang Zhi. Both of them were guarding their leader and friend against any surprise attacks. If someone was informed about what they were doing then this would be the perfect moment for an assassination attempt. By raising the protective barrier he would be weakened and need to recover for a few days.

Luckily for him, his sect would not be willing to part with their Patriarch. Thus everyone that was able surrounded the glowing orb of light that was rising above the central tower. Zhang Dong had surrounded himself with a shell of golden energy. Arcs of lightning were shooting out and quickly bombarding the whole place with his essence.

The energy that started out as chaotic lightning started to quickly connect to the various lines of power. These lines that were previously faint and pale started to churn with energy that made all the various magical runes glow even more. Soon there was a strange sound that indicated that the protective barrier became operational.

Zhang Dong that was previously surrounded by an orb of holy energy started to slowly float down to the ground. His breathing was somewhat erratic and beads of sweat covered his forehead as he had used up almost ninety percent of his spiritual reserves. Yet before he could gently drop down and rest a sudden glint entered his eye.

“Die!”

A thick black spear shot out from underground after the barrier was created. It was aimed right at Zhang Dong’s heart and already breaking the sound barrier after it was shot out from underground. The one responsible for this act was a large humanoid being that had a face similar to a mole. His body was quite muscular and his hands were replaced by sharp claws.

Yet before the black spear could reach its target it was stopped by a combination of molten lava and water. First, a giant fist made of plasma energy collided with it that belonged to Huo Qiang’s soul beast. Secondly, after losing some of its speed it was devoured by the water dragon belonging to Zhang Zhi.

“It’s just as the Patriarch said, block his escape!”

To the demi-human mole man’s surprise, they had been waiting for his appearance. Thanks to this being already Zhang Dong’s domain he was able to scan it with his mapping function. A week or so ago a small squadron of mole men had attacked their encampment. During that scuffle, their leader hid underground and waited for the right chance to strike.

The risky trap had been deliberately created by them. They had ordered some of the sect members to talk loudly about how he would be powerless after the act was done. Now after the leader took the bait they could finally remove him from the chessboard. With how the barrier was successfully created he would be unable to flee even through the ground.

‘I see that they don’t need me for every little thing anymore.’

He observed the fight from a distance, Zhang Zhi, Huo Qiang, and three other nascent soul masters were giving chase. Together with all the ranged support from their new defensive cannons and the flying ships the mole-man had no place to hide. By superheating the ground with his soul beast, Huo Qiang was able to force the enemy outside where he took his last breath.

With how the barrier was constructed it didn’t allow anything to escape even through the underground. This was one of the reasons that he decided to draw the mole-man into this area. If this tribe leader was unable to break through the newly created protective shielding, then the worms they used to get through the tunnel wouldn’t either.

While he was truly tired he could still check for any damages that the protective barrier sustained. Even after the scuffle, it was still fully operational and quickly recovering from any damage it sustained. With the test out of the way, he could now focus back on the second problem which were the demi-humans stationed in the north.

‘With the fall of their fortress they might start taking us more seriously now, the training wheel period will now be over…’

With that in mind, he removed himself from this area. After recovering it was time for more upgrades to his golden fortress, the old vampire castle was already half stripped for resources and all of them would be getting moved. The time to proceed with the war effort was at hand and soon after Wang Long’s demise was on the menu.

A note from Kuropon

Thank you for reading!

Don't forget to follow, favorite, rate.

Donate | Discord |

Chapter 502

“Give me a report, what have our strategists come up with?”

“Greetings Patriarch!”

Zhang Dong walked into the room, in the middle there was a large holographic map with various colors on it. The side that represented his lands was colored blue while the middle where his brother the Azure Emperor resided was green. In various other locations, it was quite red with a focus on the areas connecting to the other empires.

“The region that we had managed to take from the demi-humans is stable, we have experienced an attack coming from outside but our forces were able to handle it with minimal losses, no force has attempted to travel through the bridge. We assume that the other demi-humans have informed their leaders already and are probably unwilling to risk losing forces by going through the bridge directly.”

“That does make sense, have our scouts discovered anything? Are they building up a force up north?”

“It is so Patriarch, the enemy is probably building up their forces before attempting to reclaim the area, we expect the recent skirmishes to be nothing more than scouts meant to test our forces.”

“Mhm.”

Zhang Dong nodded while looking at the map, he had wanted the enemies to just attack him through the bridge where his defenses were the strongest. Regretfully they weren’t all just brutes and were smart enough to wait for more people to arrive. It wouldn’t be strange if after they charge from the north another sizable army would appear through the bridge to attempt a pincer attack.

“Very well, concentrate on building our defenses outwardly; we can not have that location fall. How about the other regions, any words from the east side?”

“Yes Patriarch, we have received information that the sects and clans are being pushed towards the center of the empire.”

“Has the Heavenly Crane Sect moved in yet?”

“No, they have taken a passive approach but are allowing other sects to join their ranks.”

“As expected, they don’t want to spread themselves too thin without knowing the other sides full might.”

Zhang Dong nodded as the second strongest sect in the Empire was acting in a similar fashion to the strongest. They didn’t care about the lower regions or protecting them, most of their wealth was gathered in the zones with higher spiritual energy concentrations. There the spirit stone mines were more plentiful and the spirit herbs grew in abundance.

“Do we know something about the East attackers or about the ones coming from the north?”

“Yes, Patriarch, the ones to the east have identified themselves as residents of the Emerald Phoenix Empire and are very similar to our own people. They are also cultivators similar to us but their way of progressing is different.”

“I presume they have been ransacking the cities they managed to occupy?”

The person giving the report nodded as Zhang Dong was familiar with that group of people as he had spent some time in that Empire. They were a reflection of the Azure Empire so they would act the same way as the cultivators here. This was like a secret ground that became open for a short amount of time. They were like locusts that hoped to devour everything before the path home closes.

‘They have learned to cultivate in lands with lower amounts of spiritual energy, so now that they have come here they will gain a boost to their strength. I can’t move into that region before taking care of the Demi-humans and Wang Long…’

While the Emerald Phoenix Emperor and his people could not be taken lightly they were predictable. They wouldn’t push in too hard and slowly try to gather all the resources they could get their hands on. He believed that they would wait and gather information before pulling all the stops. Getting used to the increased spiritual energy would also hinder their siege as a lot of their Elders will wish to cultivate in a more favorable environment instead.

“What of the beings from the spirit sea? Have they been identified?”

“No Patriarch, we only have rumors and the map we speculate that these beings can’t function on land as we do and instead will continue to spread their influence in the uncharted waters.”

The north side of the empire was connected to a giant ocean that could not be crossed, anyone that attempted to make the trip had never come back to tell their tale. The way was clearly barred and only opened up after this scenario had started. Probably if he tried sailing those waters he would arrive in another area with those supposed fish people.

‘If they can’t reach into our lands then its fine but the only problem is…’

The map here was showing a fog of red moving from the northeast towards the northwest where Wang Long was supposed to be. When crossing over to the demonic lands there would be a possibility of running into these invaders. It was also possible for Wang Long to interact with them first.

‘It would be nice if they could just kill him for me but they will probably be nothing more than a spirit point farm…’

The sea creatures could perhaps be a perfect farm just made for a system holder. If they couldn’t come over towards the landmass then Wang Long could retreat to safety after killing a few.
‘I can’t just wait, I need to strike while the iron is hot as long as we keep winning the sect will also continue getting a morale boost.’

The United Element Sect was his faction and this feature had several uses. One of them was giving him passive spirit points by keeping everyone happy. Yet this wasn’t all as after reaching a certain threshold the whole sect would be given a power boost that was affected by their morale. During battles, he could also choose to spend points to give his people passive buffs if he so wished.

‘The more we win, the more they believe in me and give me points but if many people die then the whole thing could crumble…’

Zhang Dong disliked treating his people like numbers and statics on the screen. This was the unfortunate truth of this system he just had a general idea of how his people were doing, it was all like a strategy game. It made things easier for him to run his faction but also dehumanized the people living there.

‘I hope when this is all over, I can just put all of this to rest…’

After going through the map again he retreated to his system menu. There he accessed the faction window where he found the Golden Dong Palace. After frowning at the name he had given it he looked at the resources that were being stored there. They were steadily increasing thanks to the castle Valentine brought over and almost all of it had been transferred.

‘All of this seems too easy but this was probably done by design.’

The floating golden castle was very convenient. It was an end-game item that he received at the start of the scenario that was supposed to last for a hundred years. Probably after a few years of losing their borders, everyone would gather closer to the center of the empire, and even the invaders would not be able to contend with the nascent soul masters that had all gathered up under one banner.

Then when they counterattacked the person with the system would be able to constantly farm spirit points and finally ascend. This of course didn’t go well with him as he wasn’t really planning on ascending. Whatever was out there he didn’t really want it, spending a thousand years of his lifetime with his current family didn’t sound that bad.

‘I just hope that I’ll get a choice in all of this…’

Yet he needed to have a plan B for whenever the overlords decided to show themselves. Perhaps going above the limits that this place was created with would be the only way of saving everyone that he loved. The first step in that quest for true freedom would be taking care of Wang Long.

‘I just hope my dear ol’ brother won’t throw a fit after his treasured family relic vanishes…’

Zhang Dong thought to himself while vanishing from his current location and appearing in the palace made from golden material. He appeared in a secluded room that only he as the owner of this place could access freely. After renovating the large room he was left with something that looked similar to his old man cave.

It was somewhat similar to the area he saw at the old secret ground. A gaming desk with a lot of screens was here along with any old technology that he was able to bring over from that place. Here he could monitor all of this palace without even clicking on the screen.

“So how is it going, Bob?”

“The Golden Dong Palace is 77% operational.”

“Good, so we have enough energy to leave this place, right?”

“Affirmative.”

His AI partner had been uploaded into this flying fortress to take care of all the difficult calculations. While all of the cannons could not be automated Bob could take care of the teleporting. This required a lot of processing power and precision, if someone was to get sent into a rock their atoms would become a jumbled mess as they died almost instantly.

‘It only needed to be at 75%, that castle was worth the trouble!”

He wanted to pat himself on the back for choosing to ransack the vampire castle for valuable resources. Together with all the various building materials the destroyed sects and clans left they were able to restore this place into working order.

‘The Long Clan doesn’t seem too bothered by anything as usual…’

His flying fortress was able to somewhat monitor the Long Clan on the outside. He could tell that from the day he had entered the palace a lot of nascent soul elders had been stationed closer to his location. They were keeping tabs on him but weren’t aware of what was happening on the inside.

There was one reason that he needed to leave this place, it was impossible to fully prepare this flying fortress otherwise. Most of what was missing were the defensive structures on the outside that he could not restore without the Long Clan noticing. Everything that was upgraded was on the inside but if he didn’t want to be a flying target he needed to get those cannons ready.

‘That Goliath thing is also bothering me but… perhaps if I show my independence my dear brother will fill me in on the secret.’

With that in mind he decided to flip the switch to alert his people, it was time to take the fight to the demi-humans once more and hopefully end this whole war prematurely.

A note from Kuropon

Thank you for reading!

Don't forget to follow, favorite, rate.

Donate | Discord |

Chapter 503

“Huh? What is that… why is everything shaking?”

“Is the Emperor angry? What is happening!”

A group of people was looking at some shaking tableware. Just a moment before they were having a heated conversation about the state of the world and now the entire floating city was trembling. This was not something anyone was used to and they certainly didn’t think that the floating city could ever be breached. Thus the only explanation could be an internal conflict of some kind.

“C-could the Emperor be battling with his brother?”

“The Golden Dragon? He wouldn’t dare!”

“B-but I’ve heard that he matches the Emperor in power…”

“Even if he is the Emperor’s match, he would need the backing of the elder, without it he will have to go against every single martial master in the city!”

An old man shrugged while smiling, in his mind, if the Golden Dragon decided to go against his brother now, it would be suicide. He had no backing and came from a lower sect with no power. How could someone with so little backing be brazen enough to attack the most powerful man in the empire?

“Oh, perhaps they are having a friendly spar instead?”

Another option was given by a young man, this sounded plausible but not quite probably. Why would the two top cultivators of the clan allow their spiritual attacks to affect the populace in the city? They would normally do something like that in seclusion to hide their techniques to be released to the world and copied.

“That’s probably not it… but isn’t the shaking getting worse?”

At first, only the tables were moving around but soon the small restaurant they were sitting in began shaking as well. With a fear of the whole place collapsing on their heads they all started to leave, perhaps when they got outside they would be able to figure out what the problem was.

“What is going on?”

They were not the only people outside as many clan members started crowding the open streets. Some of them that were of core formation and above started taking to the sky. There was a certain strange spiritual pulse coming from the direction of the Azure Palace.

“W-why is there such a bright golden glow? Could it really be the Golden Dragon?”

To everyone’s surprise something behind the Azure Palace that they had no access to was brightening the sky. It was as if the a miniature sun was rising from behind it and slowly going up, but when it revealed itself it was something different that they had never seen before.

“W-what is that Golden Structure…”

“Wait, there is something written on it… ‘Golden Dong Palace’? Isn’t that the name of the Golden Dragon? I… Is he really revolting?”

“T-that…”

Everyone here was used to certain privileges, even though their cultivation levels were high they were not really used to fighting people at their own levels. Whenever anyone went out into the world they were treated like kings or queens. The whole world bowed their heads before them, so in a situation like this where a capable enemy might have surfaced, they were starting to panic. In their minds, if a usurper arose they would be prepared for battle.

“Wait, that palace… it’s glowing…”

“Hasn’t it been glowing already?”

“No you idiot, the glow is different… it’s…. teleportation?”

While the people were panicking and expecting the floating castle to start firing projectiles everywhere it just vanished. The golden glow subsided as the structure was submerged in a pale blue light before disappearing.

Everyone here could tell that it had performed a teleportation spell but how was it able to get outside their protective barrier that was supposed to block all teleportation attempts? Was this something the Azure Emperor agreed on or was the Golden Dragon powerful enough to ignore his older brother?

…

“Emperor, we have lost it…”

“What do you mean?”

“W-we can’t find the Golden Palace within our lands, it must have traveled further outside.”

“That is indeed surprising… my brother is full of mysteries…”

Long Qing was sitting on his throne while looking at something that looked like a holographic screen. There a moment earlier he could see Zhang Dong’s palace rising up above his own and then vanishing. He had assumed that his brother was just cultivating in his new home and would come out soon, but instead, he had escaped from his range of influence.

“Why would he leave?”
Long Qing posed the question to the elders here as he didn’t understand his brother. Why would he leave the most prosperous region and the safest place in the Empire? There was no reason to go out there, it only complicated things as now the relic of the past was not there anymore. Without it, their city had lost some of its defensive capability but not to the point of going after it.

“Perhaps the young dragon wishes to prove that he can be self-sufficient?”

“So is it hubris then? Very well, we will wait for him to have his little adventure, he will return here sooner or later, send a few elders to keep watch of his moves, and report back.”

The Emperor waved his hand as if he was tired of the talk. In his mind, this didn’t change much of the future plan. His brother had the golden palace with him so there was no danger of him losing his life. Even if he did, that wouldn’t change much. While he was glad to have received a sibling on his level he would not cry when he was gone.

“Yes, Emperor!”

“What a troublesome little brother don’t you think so, my Empress?”

Long Qing gave out a sigh while turning to his wife that seemed a bit too quiet. As he called out to her, the smile on her face quickly appeared once more.

“He is truly an interesting individual, my Emperor.”

She nodded while moving closer to her husband but from the corner of her eye she was focused on the area where once the Golden Palace resided.

…

“Woah, that burned through almost all of the energy reserves… luckily we are out…”

Zhang Dong along with all of the sect members that were inside the Palace were feeling drained. Everyone had to inject some of their own spiritual energy into the flying relic from the past. With everyone's help, they were able to teleport outside the lands of the Long Clan but not enough to return to their own Sect Grounds.

“Bob, give me a status report!

“Energy is low, redirecting all power to the anti-gravity module.”

He was still sitting in his command room without anyone else around him. Some of the screens that were used to monitor the various rooms were flickering. Red light accompanied by an alarm was signaling that they were on a collision course with the ground. If this huge structure were to crash without any energy within the protective barrier it would be a disaster.

“Shit…”

There was no time to think about his own health as the weapon to finish this war was about to be destroyed. To the side was a large pale orb that he had already used to add power to the teleportation function, now he needed to do the same with the flight modules.

‘Warning… Warning… Warning…’

“Yeah, yeah be quiet for a second Bob.”

He placed both of his hands on the basketball-sized orb and soon after it started sucking away his spiritual energy. To make the process quicker he decided to inject it at a faster rate which caused the orb to start cracking. Zhang Dong was not the only one, various members of his sect had been spread out throughout the structure to act as potential batteries and now they were giving it all they had to keep this mobile fortress afloat.

“R-run!”

On the outside, a group of villagers was having a bad day. Out of nowhere a giant building made of gold appeared out of nowhere and began falling on their peaceful village. Most of them were in a state of panic, some started running away while others accepted their fate. If the large structure collided with the ground the ensuing shockwave would wipe everything that they knew and loved.

“W-wait, it… it's stopping?”

One of the elders from the village looked up in shock as the golden palace started to glow from underneath. It looked like some kind of round disk started to flicker in and out of existence before finally settling itself into place. This disk started growing to the point of being wider than the entire structure before it finally stopped in place.

A gust of wind hit their faces and caused some of them to tumble to the sides. When looking back up they could not see anything besides the underside of this glowing palace. It was bigger than their entire village and just floating above their heads like some kind of divine construct.

All of them dropped down to their knees to bow their heads. Even without knowing what this thing was they knew that it probably belonged to some powerful sect or clan. Their only hope of survival was to lower their heads and hope that the master of this flying city was merciful with them.

Yet as they remained on the ground nothing seemed to be happening. The building above their heads was giving out a warm glow with a calm harmonious sound that felt somewhat relaxing. Some of the people that were injured could even feel that their wounds were being mended.

Finally, after about fifteen minutes a person on a sword appeared from within the palace and was followed by more people wearing similar robes. Anyone that was previously looking up lowered their heads once more out of fright. Now their fears came back, what if these people decided to murder all of them, in these troubled times a small village like theirs would not be remembered or avenged by anyone.

“Raise your heads. We would like to apologize on behalf of the United Element Sect, we hope that this will be enough to cover the damages.”

The young man that was speaking possessed white hair and was quite the looker. The moment the girls from their village laid their eyes on him they were captivated. The man didn’t stay for long as he tossed a sack to the ground before quickly returning to the golden palace he came from.

It didn’t take long before the giant structure above their heads began moving away. While it might have seemed slow it was actually moving fast when considering its large size. Finally, after it was gone the village elder decided to look inside the sack.

“T-this is… spirit stones and gems… why this is a fortune!”

To their surprise, it was filled with precious items that were more than enough to cover the repair costs of a few collapsed roofs that occurred after the strong winds collided with their home.

“The United Element Sect… truly a peculiar lot…”

Chapter 504

‘This does make things a lot easier now… I hope the other clans and sects will overlook this…’

A few days had passed after their escape from the Long Clan territory and his flying fortress was slowly traversing the Empire. Even though its speed was close to a plane’s it would still take a lot of time to get to its destination. There was also a tiny problem of them stopping at various locations that was prolonging their trip.

This was the fifth stop that they were making and it was not due to any energy problems. After the hovering palace was stabilized the golden egg that was powering it all with holy energy was enough. The reason they were stopping so many times was to stock up on free materials.

At this very moment, a beam of light was shooting out from under the palace and slowly sucking up partially destroyed structures. Zhang Dong was sitting in his office chair replica while sipping from a mug of tea while his sect members did all the work. They dismantled buildings to toss them into the tractor beam that then sucked up everything for recycling.

‘I guess if those demi-humans didn’t come through here this wouldn’t be possible…’

He felt bad for gathering up all the materials that were left over by fleeing sects and clans. All of them were just there unattended and without an owner. The thing making it rationalize it was the cause these materials were going to. They would all be used to combat the invaders that destroyed everything in the first place.

‘Whoever lived here would probably not be able to get their belongings back or even return here before someone else snatched it all… I’ll have to mark all of these places down and reimburse them after the war is over.’

What he could do to ease his conscience was to make a note of every region he borrowed materials from. If the original owners were still alive and everything coincided with the old records then he would pay them back in full.

The buildings would probably be worth less than his sect's cultivation materials or knowledge for improvement. His biggest worry was that he couldn’t really ask for permission and could only assume what the other party wanted from him yet for the time being this was the best option.

Thanks to this approach his golden palace was being quickly built up to its full potential. But there was something bothering, even though it was quickly reaching a hundred percent it didn’t seem fit for a collision with the enemy empires.

All of his previous resources were spent on getting the inside of the palace in working order. This amounted to a whopping eighty percent number in his faction window. The rest was just twenty which normally would be something to be happy about, yet this number was somewhat small. How could the outside armaments only be this good?

‘Is this really it? I might have to move some of the cannons from the ships if this is the extent of their capabilities…’

After spending the resources he was somewhat disappointed in what he received. The first problem was that there just wasn’t enough firepower here. Then the second problem concerned the amount of damage the few large guns he was able to get with the help of this system.

‘They won’t be able to cover the whole fortress… like this, it’s not much better than the Argonaut… it’s also far slower than it and will be a sitting duck’

While the fortress was sturdy and it would take a while to get through the protective barrier it wouldn’t be much of a problem for a high-level cultivator or a battalion of faster ships. It wouldn’t be much else but a large transport for people at this point that would have to hang in the background.

‘This can’t be it… perhaps?’

Zhang Dong had already gone through the pain of taking this thing out of the Long Clan. If he couldn’t use it as a spear to throw at his enemies it would be a devastating setback. All of the resources that went into this thing could have been used elsewhere and he also would need to potentially offend his older brother.

During his pondering, he continued to look at the percentage number going up while the floating palace was sucking up a deserted city. Soon he would have enough of the recycled resources to complete all of the available armaments and rooms that were on the inside. There was something he was hoping for when he reached that number and his luck was as good as ever. When the last structure was repaired and the counter hit a hundred he was given a new option.

“Haha, why was I even worrying? There is always some kind of new upgrade!”

This was truly a game-like system, even the flying palace could be upgraded after meeting the right criteria. While this was the first of the enhancements he expected there to be at least a third form that might require something harder than just pumping it full of recycled parts.

“So I’ve got two options… hey Bob, can you show me how the palace will look with each upgrade?”

`Affirmative, uploading schematic to an external screen, please wait a moment.”

After waiting a few seconds he was presented with two golden palaces that looked different. The difference was quite noticeable as one of them was much bulkier with thicker walls and an increase in size. The other one was more similar to the current one with a more streamlined upgrade.

‘The larger one looks better at first glance but…’

“Hey Bob, can you show me some stats?”

The two palaces started getting smaller while a graph appeared next to them. These painted a picture of what he could expect if he decided to go with the bulkier castle. Its capabilities shifted towards defense, it lost some of its speed while gaining more powerful shields and defenses. The second one on the other hand was more inclined towards attacking, it would be faster and the cannons would hit for more.

“So that’s the big question, do I want to have a giant impenetrable slow-moving fortress or one that can blow everything to Kingdom Come?”

This was not such an easy decision to make, the slower version was more robust and would probably not be easily breached. Yet its armaments and mobility were inferior, and the teleportation features became more limited as well so escaping from a battle would be hard.

But what he wanted was something to become a shield for his people while he became the sword himself. Even though he would be given fewer options for attacking that was just a limit placed on the system itself, it didn’t limit anything that was outside.

With a strong enough shield and defenses, he could bring over his engineers. There were many ships in production along with cannons at his disposal. Attaching them to a larger fortress that had sturdier walls would not be as difficult.

‘It will be a lot easier to bring over some artillery than reinforcing the outer walls themselves and I bet I’ll be able to upgrade the side components to alleviate the lack of mobility.’

There was another reason for him going with the more defensive upgrade, the engine's power limit with that form was above the more mobile one. With more spirit energy at his disposal, he could safely bring over more of his own upgrades from the sect. Then perhaps when he reached a hundred percent in this form of the ship, he could reduce some of its deficiencies.

“Hm… I guess this is a good time as any, Bob upgraded the Golden Palace.”

“Affirmative, which variant should the Golden Dong Palace be upgraded to?”

“Do you have to say the full name in that monotone voice… but anyway, the larger one… oh right it has a name, upgrade it to the Bastion variant, but hold on a second, patch me through to the communication system first.”

“Affirmative.”

“Here is the Patriarch speaking, I want everyone to go outside the palace and wait for further instructions, worry not this is only a little test.”

Before he continued with the upgrade he decided to have everyone move outside. He was mostly sure that no one would suffer inside of the palace even if it started changing but there could always be some kind of accident if he didn’t announce it. People would start panicking when the walls started to expand and perhaps trip and fall on something pointy. It took about ten minutes for everyone to evacuate and he was finally able to continue.

His people gathered outside, some were floating up on their flying swords while others remained in the small ground area outside the main gate. Soon they realized that some kind of transformation was taking place as the whole palace began to shake.

By this time they were already used to the strange things happening on the inside of this golden palace, so their reaction was a lot milder. Some of them were just happy that they were finally allowed to step outside the flying fortress for the first time in months. Their joy was short-lived as the whole flying contraption started expanding in all directions.

First, the ground that was the foundation of this flying fortress started getting bigger to accommodate for the increase in size. The walls became thicker and higher, six towers appeared around the old palace and surrounded it with these new walls. On the inside, more free space was created with strange squarish plots of land that seemed to be for something.

The interior of the palace was changing in a similar fashion. The rooms started expanding to the sides along with the ceiling. This was all done via the spatial formation that warped the space inside to create larger rooms that should not be able to exist normally. However, the biggest difference was to the golden egg that was powering the entire flying fortress.

“I can feel the holy energy rising…”

On one of the monitors, Zhang Dong could see the golden egg expanding in size. He was attuned to everything that was holy and the increase in power output was more than doubled. With the increase in the exterior size the flying relic would use it all up but he wasn’t worried as he was greeted by more system prompts that he began to read.

“Hm… so that was just the start of it? Think I’m going to need to ‘borrow’ more materials…”

Thanks to the first base upgrade he was now given an option to reinforce all the existing components with the use of spirit points and building points. These he would be getting via passive production and recycling as always.

“Everyone, we will be taking a small detour so return to your posts, we have a lot of work to do!”

“Yes, Patriarch.”

Everyone quickly replied while hastily jumping through the main gate that was once again open. On the inside, they were baffled with all the free space that looked brand new and ready to be filled out.

A note from Kuropon

Thank you for reading!

Don't forget to follow, favorite, rate.

Donate | Discord |

Chapter 505

“This ‘borrowing’ business is really paying off.”

“Patriarch?”

“Oh, it’s nothing, just continue…”

Zhang Dong was looking at the ever-increasing counter of his points going up. Since the first transformation of his flying fortress, he was going through the deserted cities and sucking up all of the resources. Sometimes they encountered small groups of demi-humans but with him around they weren’t much of a problem.

Thanks to them appearing in some places they were even able to test out the new defenses and cannons. The demi-humans that they were up against were remnants of the red-skinned ones. With their violent nature and lack of intelligence, they tossed themselves against the large flying fortress in the sky.

It seemed that they were lacking a danger sense, or could not identify spiritual energy to measure their opponent's power levels. Their bone spikes were unable to pierce through the translucent shield that this upgraded bastion had. It was holding up well against the members that were on the lower edges of the nascent soul. Thanks to this test he now knew that it would be possible to survive a prolonged siege.

The cannons on the other hand did slightly worse. While they had a lot of destructive power the aim wasn’t that great. They were not designed to hit fast-moving enemies that were in a small group but when placed against a tightly packed army they would probably be enough.

‘Zhi had to go out and finish their leader off but I can still place more of those cannons, trading out precision for ammo spam…’

Everything seemed to be moving in his favor, in the time it would take for him to arrive back at his lands this fortress would be outfitted with enough defensive power to act as a proper mobile bastion. With its help, he would be able to slowly force his way into the demi-human territory and perhaps take them out for good.

‘If I’m lucky I might be able to do everything before the last boss arrives, but I can’t count on that…’

He had already committed himself to the rapid war effort. The sensible approach would be to wait and fully upgrade this flying fortress to its last stage. For that to happen he would need to abandon his push into the enemy territory which would allow them to reconsider their tactics.

Even then he would still have a powerful impenetrable war machine that would probably allow him to easily win. The biggest problem with that approach was Wang Long who was a dark horse in all of this. His strength after killing everyone from the Soaring Dragon Sect was unknown and he would only get stronger.

The more time he had the more Zhang Dong worried, the system allowed anyone to reach an astonishing power level in a matter of seconds and his version was probably inferior to Wang Long’s. The only real advantage he had was his sect that he built up through the years. Without them around this flying monstrosity would not be able to function.

‘I just hope I’m not leading everyone towards their destruction…’

Zhang Dong knew what needed to be done but he was worried about the cost of lives that were at stake. His counterpart Wang Long treated these people like NPCs in a game, for him on the other hand they were just people. All of these people had their own thoughts and dreams but were also reliant on his will.

As the number one cultivator in the sect, they would not deny the call to battle if he issued it. There was no use in talking to them as they would certainly rely on him to make a decision. If he proved unwilling to make one, he would be a failure of a leader. Thus it was time to take the initiative again, the battle to end this war prematurely needed to commence sooner rather than later.

…

“So, Valentine has fallen, how many chiefs does that make now, huh? You there, answer me.”

A large man was leaning on his fist while sitting atop a throne made from bones. He didn’t look very pleased with the people here. The person that his large finger pointed at trembled but was forced to speak up.

“We have lost four Chiefs, my Emperor…”

“Four huh?... How could four of the ten great tribe Chiefs have died? Is that name only for show?”

Silence fell upon the whole place, the sound of volcanoes exploding in the distance was the only thing that anyone could hear. Yet, before the man on the throne could raise his voice again another large person walked up and kneeled.

“Emperor, send me, I will bring you the heads of whoever is responsible!”

The man had a large horn protruding from his forehead, his body was covered by some kind of green moss. This being's features were similar to that of a tree, small branches were shooting out from his body along with leaves that seemed somewhat malnourished.

“We from the Treant Tribe will massacre the prey and…”

“... Who told you that you could speak?”

“M-my Emper…”

Before the tree being could finish the sentence it felt a massive force coming down on it. The sturdy-looking body made from hard and practically indestructible wood started to splinter. The tribe chief had made a grave error in speaking out, he had misread the Emperor’s mood and he would pay the ultimate price for it.

The other horned beings that were here started moving away as the entire throne room began to shake. A pillar of dark purple energy shot out from the center of where the tree demi-human was disabled. When it reached a high enough altitude it called something, a tiny sparkle up in the sky was now coming their way.

Everyone started to panic as they realized what was happening. The Emperor was truly angered by this tribe leader and if they didn’t escape they would also feel his wrath. Luckily for them, their leader didn’t seem to care as he remained seated in the same nonchalant expression while performing the strange magical art.

“N-no p-please Emperor, s-show mercy…”

The person from the Treant tribe called out but his calls were meant with silence. Instead, he could feel something approaching from the sky and on a collision course with him. When glancing up his vision was overtaken by a large orb of fire that soon collided with his crumbling body.

Everything suddenly exploded, even the powerful Chiefs were unable to hold on and had to retreat from the blasting zone. After opening their eyes they could not comprehend the amount of damage that was before them. The Emperor’s palace that had been there having a giant gaping hole in it, the only thing that remained in place was the Emperor himself who was still sitting on his throne with a bored expression on his face.

“That changes it to five…”

They could hear him mumble something but were unable to raise their heads to answer. After seeing this monster's might they were unable to do anything but shiver. Finally, after a small pause, their leader decided to stand up.

“I had hoped that they would have posed as an appetizer for my prey but he was already matured… I hope that he won’t be a disappointment …”

The Emperor that had a nice set of three large horns on his head surrounded himself with the same dark-purple energy while floating up. There he rose up so that all of the people that were still alive after a blast could see him.

“I will venture into the hunting grounds myself, all of you will join me, whoever retreats will die by my hand! No more mistakes, you all are a disgrace don’t even think of returning here alive if you fail!”

During the speech, the Emperor became louder and louder. His ferocious voice traveled through the whole area and started causing earthquakes. Yet some of the rubble started rising up from the ground. A small ball of rocks was quickly uncovered by the Emperor to reveal a pointy horn. The same that belonged to the Treant Tribe leader, it had survived the attack of the leader and was ready to be passed on to the next generation.

“You!”

The Emperor pointed to one of the other tree tribesmen that were trembling. This person that was pointed to had no other choice but to step forward and accept his fate. Normally it would be a great privilege to accept the tribe leader's horn but it would lessen this tribe member’s ceiling.

It was thrown towards the tree-like person’s forehead and quickly attached itself to it. The change was quite instantaneous as their body grew in size. In just a minute the person grew twice in size and was a mirror image of the old leader. His power had increased exponentially but it would not be able to reach a higher point than this.

“Your tribe will redeem itself by attacking the second path to the hunting ground, don’t fail me.”

“Yes, Emperor, it will be an honor!”

The new leader of the tree tribe just bowed their head and tried not to say anything that could provoke this Emperor’s ire. The message went through if his tribe failed in taking back the area where Valentine resided they were good as dead. It would be a battle for survival that they needed to take seriously.

“The rest of you will follow me, gather all of your best warriors, we will gorge ourselves on those bastards and remember, the golden one is my prey, whoever dares to touch him…”

During his short speech the earth continued to rumble but finally when it was over things started to calm down. But suddenly from the distance, a loud sound of galloping could be heard by everyone. No one else but the Emperor was looking in that direction and he was not surprised by the sight he was seeing.

A large Chariot was approaching his position, it was being pulled by two large flaming horses. Their eyes and legs were constantly covered by burning flames and it seemed as if they were running through the air. Each time their hooves connected with the air it was as if they had traction and produced a sound.

In a matter of seconds, the large chariot sped by the large demi-human leader but instantly stopped when to his side. The two steeds that were giving off a strange aura were even bigger than the man himself. Yet they were clearly subservient to his will which they showed by lowering their heads.

Without missing a beat, the three-horned Emperor jumped onto the battle carriage. There were no reins that he needed to hold, instead, he just crossed his muscular arms together while the flaming horses bolted toward their next destination…

A note from Kuropon

Thank you for reading!

Don't forget to follow, favorite, rate.

Donate | Discord |

Chapter 506

“An emissary from the United Element Sect has arrived?”

“Yes, Patriarch.”

“Did they say what they want?”

“No, they proclaimed that it's an important letter from their leader.”

“From that man? … Let him in, everyone be silent, do not antagonize the messenger, we can’t allow anyone to irritate the message-bearer, if they carry the official word of their Patriarch it's as good as him coming here themselves!”

Every person in this large meeting hall nodded at the words of their leader. It was common knowledge that the people carrying direct orders from sect leaders could not be offended. Even if they were weak in cultivation, if any harm came to them, the other sect had a reason to retaliate or ask for payment in money or blood.

“You have my gratitude for accepting me at such short notice.”

“Greetings, what brings a member from the esteemed United Element Sect to our humble abode? You must be tired from your journey, perhaps you would like to join us…”

“You must forgive me but this matter is of utmost importance, I have been tasked to deliver this scroll with haste.”

“Is that so?”

The group of elders that were sitting on large chairs and the Patriarch that was at the back end of this large hall frowned slightly. The person that they were trying to be cordial with ignored them and just gave the scroll over to one of the retainers that would bring it to the Patriarch before turning away. This display was already sending them a message as he didn’t stay for the reply and just left quickly.

“Who do they think they are?”

One of the old elders slammed his fist into the chair he was sitting in, the armrest immediately gave out and burst into a million splinters.

“Calm down elder, what can we do? We can’t offend that Zhang Dong … he is in good graces with the Emperor and you have also heard the reports…”

“Aye… they are strong, far stronger for any of us to go against.”

“Why don’t we just look at it first before we make a decision? Perhaps they just want payment for patrolling our borders?”

“How much would they even want…”

Even though everyone here wanted to be positive they couldn’t imagine that this wasn’t something bad. They have heard of the monsters roaming the lands of the Empire. The United Element’s Sect's militaristic might was also increasing at an unfathomable rate. They had apparently secured a far away location further in the north where these monsters had a base.

“What does it say?”

“...Read it out loud…”

The man in charge went through the writing quite fast and quickly threw the scroll over to the retainer that almost letting it fall to the ground. Just as he was ordered, he started reading the content of the message.

“We of the United Element Sect request the aid of the Dragon Gate Sect in the coming battle with the demi-humans, The Dragon Gate Sect is required to send out troops to the …”

The man started to read while sweating along with all the other elders. This was a call to battle that was usually sent out to subservient clans or sects. It was very simple, they needed to send a large portion of their troops to aid the United Element Sect’s war effort. They were to meet up with a group of other sects where they would be informed about their task.

“... If you refuse this call to arms it will be taken as an insult to the sect leader, Long Dong the Golden Dragon, brother of the Emperor…”

In the final statement, they were more or less forced into the battle, if they didn’t then they would be offending the Emperor himself. If this happened then they would not be able to hide anywhere, escaping to the middle of the Empire would not be an option as they would be offending the Long Clan by refusing to join.

“W-what will we do?”

“What can we do?”

Replied Xu Qing while rubbing his brows, the leader already knew that similar messengers had been sent out to all the other sects in this area. The United Element Sect were organizing a full-blown offensive against the invaders in the northwest and everyone under them would be required to join.

“Send word to everyone, we must agree on the members that will be sent!”

Xu Qing made his decision that was not up to a vote. They had also been helped by the United Element Sect that was guarding their borders. If not for them he knew that the Demi-humans would have been at their doorstep.

“This might not be a setback but a chance, if we can show our worth then our Sect will prosper!”

This Patriarch also had his own agenda, Zhang Dong’s faction was strong and it was also part of the Long Clan. If they could show that they are trusted allies then their future would be assured. Other factions like the Demon Subduing Sect or the Limitless Sword Society would be also forced into this but only those that brought results would be rewarded in the end.

Those three sects that were situated around Zhang Dong’s core area of influence weren’t the only ones that were receiving the call to arms. Places like the Divine Fist Sect that he previously helped out were also given the opportunity to return the favor that was granted them in the past.

…

“Is something bothering you?”

“No, it’s nothing…”

Zhang Dong was looking out into the distance where his two children were playing with Bahamut in its small cute form. Next to him was his Wife Liena who had a concerned look on her face. The decision to gather the other sects that were still strong to their aid was posed by the other elders.

From their point of view, it was natural for them to join this important battle. They had been given protection by the United Element Sect while other grand factions like the Heavenly Crane Sect had taken a more passive approach. They had been saved from having to escape into the center of the Empire.

‘It’s normal for the strongest sects to utilize the weaker ones as their foot soldiers, no one will blame me but it still doesn’t feel right…’

“My husband, you have always been too lenient, are you still bothered by the decision the elders came to? As the Patriarch you can go against them if you so desire, I will support your decision but…”

“Yes… it’s the ‘correct’ decision, we lack the manpower for a decisive strike and have no idea of knowing what the demi-humans are planning.”

Zhang Dong gave out a sigh while looking toward his wife. This was one of those hard decisions that he needed to shoulder. People would die because of it but it was something that had to be done to prevent their enemies from slaughtering everyone in their wake.

“Then why are you sulking! You are in the right, those bastards are indebted to our Sect, they should be grateful for having this honor!”

He wanted to chuckle as from the point of view of his wife there was no problem at all. She was a pure cultivator and was brought up with a certain set of beliefs that could not be changed. Yet her husband wanted to alter some of those beliefs and laws. He did not want the person with the biggest fist to just force their principles on others.

This was quite the conundrum as for this dream of his to come true he required to be the strongest person in the world. Only after getting rid of every enemy and perhaps even the Azure Emperor would he be able to start changing the world. But would that change anything? Even if he was a benevolent dictator, he would still be a dictator. Unless he managed to change the people's mindset after he was dead they would go back to the ways of old.

‘Is it even possible to end all this bloodshed or are just humans too flawed?’

While contemplating he looked at his wife who was all for the forceful draft. Then his gaze went to his two young children that were now slowly soaking up the culture of this world. Their minds could still be molded into another reality but for this too happen he needed to get through this big hurdle first.

“I guess you are right my wife, what has to be done, has to be done, after it's all over then the time for change will arrive.”

While Liena smiled he slowly leaned over for a surprise smooch which rewarded him with quite a blushing wife. Even after all of this, she was still acting like a schoolgirl whenever he showed her any kind of affection. He wanted to engrave this moment in his mind as it would be the last time in a long time that he would be able to.

This was a short rest period for his forces, while the other sects gathered their cultivators he had some free time. It was the last time he would be able to see his kids before endangering his own life. If he failed then they would have to retreat to the Azure Palace. While his brother was only interested in the Gold Dragon title, his children carried the same bloodline. This bloodline was probably important enough to grant them access to the floating city.

‘But would they last against Wang Long or the other Empires?’

In reality, he didn’t believe that if he failed that this world could be saved. Wang Long’s system had already made him one of the most dangerous people in this world. He would only continue to farm points and get stronger. He lacked morals and would not put himself in harm's way to save others. It would be hard to kill him and the longer he lived the worse it would become.

‘If I can’t end it then everyone could die or be enslaved…’

While looking at his lovely wife he recalled the battle with that person. Wang Long had shown an interest in Liena and was worried that he would hold the same perverted feelings for her as previously.

“I was truly blessed with such a wonderful wife and two cute kids.”

“S-stop that.”

“But it’s true!”

Zhang Dong laughed as he tried to push the worries to the back of his head. There wasn’t much time left for him but he wanted to make it count. The next day he would be leaving and Liena would remain in the sect as the main protective force. He had used his position to keep his family safe but it wasn’t the same for everyone else.

‘I will be victorious…’

A note from Kuropon

Thank you for reading!

Don't forget to follow, favorite, rate.

Donate | Discord |

Chapter 507

“Is that all of them?”

“No Patriarch, we are getting more support than we had previously assumed.”

“Oh? Did they send more of their elders than we expected or replaced them with inferior members from their ranks instead?”

Zhang Dong was hovering up in the air along with Zhang Kuo. Below him was a temporary encampment filled out with tents and various abodes that had spatial technology. This was the area where they decided to gather all of the troops from other sects and clans.

It was previously occupied by a whole city but after the demi-humans passed through it was turned into rubble. This rubble was then absorbed into his golden bastion that was daily growing in power. Yet to achieve the next transformation he would need to wait, the rate of the upgrades had substantially slowed down and it would probably not reach the third level anytime soon.

“No Patriarch, all the sects and clans have followed our instructions and given up half of their fighting forces, they have been all accounted for.”

“But unless I’m bad at counting… aren’t there too many people here? I can even see Qi condensation juniors…”

Zhang Dong had scanned the entire area and found many weak cultivators arriving from all sorts of places. For this coming battle, the weakest he recruited were foundation establishment adepts, anyone below that would not really be able to participate in the coming battle.

“These people have heard our call to battle and decided to aid us for their own reasons.”

“Own reasons? Are they the ones that lost their homes or families to the demi-humans?”

“Yes, Patriarch.”

“That explains a lot, Kuo do we have a place for them in our army?”

“Some are strong enough to join the battalions, others could be used for various errands and support but their allegiance is questionable. Some of them probably see this as a chance to increase their fame.”

“Hm…”

He looked at the people here, even without using his system he knew that some of them probably had ulterior motives. This wasn’t something new, the easiest way to earn support with a large sect would be to help them. Many of them probably hoped to get taken under the wings of the rising powerhouse that was the United Element Sect.

‘Do they expect us to accept them as outer sect disciples after it's over?’

“Let them stay, for now, offer each one a small reward after the siege is over but not too much… Examine the problematic ones and do the usual, we can’t allow ourselves to have assassins in our ranks.”

There was no reason not to use the larger forces to his advantage. He could always place them in the defensive formations as human batteries. Everything in this world ran on spiritual energy and cultivators were small nuclear power plants exuding this energy.

“As you command.”

‘Things are ramping up but will it go as well as with that Vampire guy? Will that guy actually come?”

In the previous battle, he had managed to be victorious for a reason. His forces were stronger and he also had help from powerful allies. This time around it was slightly different as everything was on his shoulders. There was no one on the level of those demi-human leaders that he could ask for help, besides one person that is.

“Hm?”

“Excuse my late arrival, Lord Lucius was against this idea but luckily I’m not a Knight nor a noble!”

“Glad that you could make it Argus, your help is much appreciated.”

“I wish that my motives were unbiased but I do have my reasons for helping you.”

“That hurts, I thought that we have become the best of friends, you hurt me deeply!”

“Ho ho ho.”

Argus laughed but Zhang Dong knew the real reason that he had arrived to help him. This reason was part of the previous lie about the holy sword. The grand wizard was hoping to find another part of the relic at the other fortress of the demi-humans. It somewhat made sense that if one part was at the first castle then the other would be in the possession of those body refiners.

‘Would be nice if Lucius and the other knights aided me but I can’t be too greedy.”

His helper was here on his own accord but he could not expect Argus to prioritize the battle. Probably if things got troublesome with a quick teleportation spell he would be gone in a second. He was there to find the relic and perhaps would leave if that detection device stopped working.

‘I could try to imitate the frequency again but that aegis thing is a shield, it’s signature might be different…’

Zhang Dong had thought of using his unwilling allies in another pact but didn’t want to overdo it. If the Wizard here gave him some ranged support from a safe distance then it was more than enough. His opponents were usually weaker when attacking from an outside location.

“Well, if you need something just ask one of my retainers or you can make yourself at home. Take this seal, show it to anyone if you have any problems.”

Before Argus left he was given the Patriarch’s seal of approval, with it there would be no one obstructing his way. There were still a few limits as he would not be allowed in areas like the engine room with the golden egg. Soon Zhang Dong pointed toward the giant floating golden palace that was hovering over them. Argus had seen it already and was salivating while looking at it. It was clear that he was a man of knowledge and something of this scale would be a very interesting research topic.

“Astonishing… I will see you later then, my friend.”

After taking care of his friend he floated up to examine the state of his troops. As the illustrious leader, he didn’t really need to do anything at this point. All the other nascent soul masters could do all the grand speeches and move the forces around for him. His presence was the only thing that they needed to be aware of.

‘Ah, there they go again, treating me like the second coming of God…’

Yet again he was receiving bows from the cultivators with less power. This wasn’t true worship as the only thing they were doing was out of fear. All of them were conditioned to fear the strong. If they were convinced of a large power disparity the cultivators of this world would lower their heads. Sometimes if the gap was not something that could ever be crossed they would abandon all hope.

‘I can trust these people to flee the moment we start losing… not very trusty allies but it's better than nothing.’

He believed that a large chunk of the people here would abandon their posts in the face of true adversity. Yet some of them were just looking for a place to die, husbands with dead wives, brothers with parents or siblings that had fallen to the demi-humans. They had a similar trait of having a certain look in their eye, a face of someone that was ready to end it all.

‘Those will probably better be suited for large-scale defensive formation augmentation than the frontlines…’

Even though he tried to justify his decision of allowing people like these to join the coming war it didn’t go well with his morals. If he could he would just go there alone like in the old days, regretfully his strength was not at such a level that he could take on a full army of demi-humans with multiple leaders.

Before these types of thoughts clouded his mind he pushed them aside. For the coming siege, he needed to become heartless or suffer the consequences. There was no place for a weak mind when going against a strong opponent. The only positive notion in all of this was that he was going against a ruthless enemy who seemed to lack any morals. There was no chance of clearing things up with diplomacy like he was able to with Lucius.

…

Minutes turned to hours and a few days had passed since they had gathered here. Their current location was the closest region to the northwest lands populated by the demi-humans. The large scale flying ships that his sect painstakingly produces were slowly rising up into the clouds. They carried various cultivators, young and old, male and female.

They had all gathered here with one enemy in mind but with various things motivating them. Morale was high as everyone cheered at him as he placed himself at the front of the arrow formation. Right in the middle was the grand relic, the Golden Dong Palace. Even though to him the name was a joke to the people it carried a meaning, the name of one of the strongest masters in the whole Empire.

‘Everything will be fine.’

He reassured his trembling heart while trying not to look nervous before this massive group of people. Without performing a long-winded speech he took out a brand new shiny sword. It was recently forged by him from some of the superior metal that he discovered in his new fortress that also came equipped with a proper forge.

This forge was not quite as advanced as the crafting abode but it had its uses. One of them was the smelter that could produce high-quality ingots for forging purposes. Thus by spending a truckload of spirit points and other resources he created this holy sword. At first glance, it looked like a golden prop that a person would place over their fireplace but in reality, it was a true masterpiece.

It was created by Zhang Dong to magnify his current strengths. It included the knowledge of the three Daos that he was a grandmaster of and could only show its full potential when wielded by him. With this magnificent blade in hand, he was ready to go against his new enemies.

“Follow me, brothers and sisters, towards victory!”

He pointed his sword towards the cloudy sky that was above them. With a swing forward the same clouds started parting. The cultivators from the other sects and clans couldn’t even blink as they saw Zhang Dong cleave the sky in two.

The path that was created in the sky was their destination and the place where the Demi-humans were gathering their forces. The flying ships started speeding forward while the loud humming sound of the flying fortress signaled its activation. Everyone started shouting as they advanced toward their final destination, it was time to rid their lands of this scourge.

A note from Kuropon

Thank you for reading!

Don't forget to follow, favorite, rate.

Donate | Discord |

Chapter 508

“Push them back! Don’t let them reach the ships!”

“They are unable to get through our formations, attack and kill them all!”

The ground exploded along with the demi-human that was trying to run away from a large fleet. Instead of the maddened charges into their enemies, the invaders were finally retreating. The ground they walked on was quickly becoming barren and devoid of any life as the constant cannon fire riddled it with massive holes.

Yet, some of them were unwilling to turn their backs on the enemy. They were clearly lacking anyone in a proper leadership position. Part of them continued to fight while others just kept running. It didn’t help that their numbers consisted of mixed tribes, with their leaders dead they could not find common grounds.

‘It’s going well but these lands won’t be livable for a while…’

Zhang Dong along with some other sect elders floated in the sky. They were observing their soldiers performing their tasks while they conserved their strength. All of the nascent soul masters here could easily perform the same task as the flying ships but they needed to remain vigilant. Only when the demi-human leaders appeared would they be allowed to act.

A few days had passed since their fleet had left the initial location. Not soon after they encountered the first resistance force. These demi-human remnants were unable to get past the hail of spirit bullets and defensive formations. Their advance couldn’t be stopped and they slowly approached the second fortress at the other bridge.

If they were able to capture it, then Zhang Dong believed that he would be able to keep everything in check. Even if their Emperor appeared, with a proper defensive line he would be unable to press his forces into his lands. In the chaotic passageway anyone would be a sitting duck, not even the strongest nascent soul master would be able to survive. Even if they did, he could always teleport to confront the strongest demi-human himself.

“How are our new friends doing?”

While observing the battlefield he decided to message Zhang Kuo who was the commanding officer of the flagship, Argus 1. Through the years they had managed to make five more of the same class of ship.

“The mercenaries and vagabonds have been giving our troops some ranged support and are acting as a good distraction, their fighting power isn’t substantial but their numbers make up for it to some degree.”

“Good… leave them be for now but prioritize our own sect members.”

To Zhang Dong’s surprise, they received even more reinforcements after progressing through the lands. Word of their advancement into enemy territory had reached everyone in the empire. This resulted in even more cultivators wanting to participate.

The reason for them participating was clear, they wanted to gain fame, glory, and treasures. This wasn’t that odd, sometimes when larger sects went on sect cleansing excursions other people would join up to reap the rewards. They would be integrated into the vanguards and used as meat shields. It was a dangerous strategy but one that could allow for quick progress.

‘I’m not sure that death is even on their mind, luckily they came of their own volition so we won’t have to pay them anything.”

There was a downside to this kind of force, they would certainly make a run for it if their side started losing. Sometimes these cultivators would even try to rob the allies if they started to flee. This kind of force was a double-edged blade that could turn on them at any moment. Yet with how much stronger the United Element Sect was, this would probably not be a realistic concern.

“Do we have any information from the front?”

“Yes Patriarch, the demi-humans have started to flee towards their fortress, their forces have been seen retreating from other areas in the north as well.”

“Are they gathering their forces?”

“We belave it is so.”

It was uncharacteristic for the demi-humans to gather at one location. They tended to work in smaller groups only composed of people from their own tribes. Even when working together they would abandon the other tribes to save their own.

‘If someone is gathering them in one spot…’

Zhang Dong had a bad feeling about this, everything pointed towards one answer, there was someone strong there. Either the Emperor had ordered them to finally work together or he might have appeared himself. From all the information they received there were no other demi-humans that could order the tribes to work together besides their Emperor.

‘This could actually be the final battle then…’

He had hoped to arrive at the other fortress before something like this happened but he might have been too slow. This golden fortress that was upgraded wasn’t very fast, they would need a few more days to arrive at their destination. This gave enough time for the demi-humans to gather their forces to defend.

‘But will they all sit still and just defend or…hm?’

“Flying enemies coming from the Northeast!”

While he was thinking about a potential fight with an end boss, a group of flying enemies appeared. They belonged to the demi-human tribes but looked different from the remnants they were encountering. Their facial features were more aligned with lizards and all of them were sitting on flying mounts.

“Are those wyverns?”

At first, it looked that his new enemies were riding on small dragons but they lacked certain features. Bahamut, his dragon familiar had a set of arms to go together with the large wings that were attached to his back. These creatures on the other hand had webbed wings where their arms should be.

“GAO!”

“Oh, you want to go have fun with our new friends?”

Bahamut was flapping his small wings next to him, it was clear that the little dragon wanted to help out. After a small nod from Zhang Dong, the small creature bolted towards the far away swarm of wyverns. The demi-humans had little time to react to the bright light that indicated the transformation into the giant dragon.

‘There really isn’t much to do for me here…’

Zhang Dong remained in his upright position and with his hands behind his back. It felt a bit strange to sit back while his allies did all the work but he needed to conserve his energy. With the looming threat of the Demi-human Emperor, he needed to be in top shape.

‘Is the Emperor a body refiner as well? He will probably be hard to kill if I engage him from close range. This new sword should be even able to cut my body apart, hope that’s enough

While he was trying to strategize he paid attention to what his forces were doing. Bahamut had dived right into the middle of the swarm of smaller winged creatures. The people that were riding them were holding spears and bows. Yet even when those projectile weapons connected with his dragon’s golden scales, they could not penetrate them.

This improvement of a soul beast was much stronger than its past counterpart. With ease, it devoured the smaller creatures and their mounted owners. The sect ships gave some support by firing their large cannons but the dragon could not be denied. Bahamut continued to toy with them around all the way until something close to his size appeared.

‘Hm, what is that… a giant scaled bird?’

To his surprise it was not a dragon instead, it was a large black monster bird that was covered in scales. On its back, it was carrying a man that was holding a large spear. This man was part of the lizard race and had a large horn protruding from his head.

‘A demi-human tribe leader? … Can Bahamut handle him by himself?’

Zhang Dong wanted to rush in but instead, someone else decided to show up. Huo Qiang jumped onto the back of the golden dragon as if he was going to challenge the demi-human to a mounted battle. His familiar wasn’t amused but was convinced by his master to allow the red-haired brute to have his fun.

“This Huo Qiang will be your opponent!”

While his friend normally only used his fists for combat it didn’t mean that he couldn’t wield weapons. He was still a nascent soul master that had gained insight into many combat arts and could also proficiently use armaments. Thus before the clash started a large spear appeared in his hand that mirrored the demi-human one.

This demi-human was on the level of the other leader types but thanks to his faction system and Bahamut, Huo Qiang could level the playing field. There was one important thing that this flying fortress allowed him to achieve, it could generate the same buffs that he could activate at his main sect.

Just like when they got a power boost when Wang Long attacked, all of his sect members could be given buffs. Everything used up points but with the golden palace generating them constantly the buff could be activated throughout the whole battle.

For the time being, he just watched as Bahamut bit into the monster bird's long neck. In response, it tried to sink its beak into the dragon’s side but was unable to penetrate through those golden scales. Both of the large beings started thrashing around while the two men riding them clashed with each other as well.

The spears connected to generate a massive burst of energy that caused all of the other flying monsters in close proximity to explode. They just couldn’t stomach a clash between two experts at such a high level.

‘Huo Qiang’s opponent is stronger than him, but…’

It was obvious that if this was a fair fight that his friend would lose in a direct confrontation. The only reason that he was holding on was due to the buff and his partner that he lent him. Bahamut was clearly stronger than the monster bird that this lizardman was riding on and with it out of the picture it was two against one.

Surprisingly after the creature was dead the rider spawned their own wings. It seemed that he was some kind of human wyvern hybrid. While the wings allowed him to fight up in the sky they weren’t as good as a cultivator's flight technique. The mobility that Huo Qiang could output allowed him to continue the clash for much longer than he would be able to.

‘Are they testing us or did one of the tribes want to hunt the strong prey?’

The fight was coming to a close, together with Bahamut, Qiang was able to push his enemy back. Yet this was suspicious, it was as if these demi-humans were stalling for time. They had a strong force but it was nothing compared to his and the leader would soon be dead.

“Kuo, start advancing, we have lost enough time here…”

With a bad feeling in his gut, he turned away from the fight that was ending. If he was correct then there was no time to lose, they needed to get to that fortress and clear it out.

A note from Kuropon

Thank you for reading!

Don't forget to follow, favorite, rate.

Donate | Discord |

Chapter 509

‘They are really putting up a defensive effort this time around…’

The invasion of the United Element Sect continued into the lands that the demi-humans took over. It was a strange feeling for Zhang Dong that usually was the one on the defensive, there weren’t many times when he was the aggressor.

After they had managed to clear out the wyverns and their leader they continued to push deeper to the north. There they encounter more varied demi-human resistance. After the flying lizards, they encountered a batch of snake-people. They were similar to nagas or gorgons that he remembered from games and had female-looking upper bodies.

There was even a group of green skins that was similar to fantasy orcs or ogres. Together with some other remnants, they put up a defensive perimeter that blocked their advance. When looking at the map of the empire they all could tell that they were actually trying to halt their advance.

Yet the forces weren’t strong enough, at most they could put up a fight for half a day before pulling out. Each time they lost more than half of their forces, this only made sense if they were stalling for time. Ignoring this blocking effort wasn’t possible, the demi-humans would circle around and attack their backline if they were allowed to.

‘Should I go ahead by myself?’

His mind was filled with various troublesome thoughts. What if his enemies were transporting some kind of massive weapon through the bridge? What if that Emperor appeared out of the blue? But, could he just handle him alone when he arrived? If he got locked down by their leader then his whole army would collapse.

“Patriarch, we have a problem!”

“What is it now?”

“We have spotted tree-like beings trying to go through the lower bridge, they are trying to take back the fortress they lost!”

“A surprise attack from the back? Have the defenses fallen?”

Zhang Dong would have liked to use a teleport to travel to that area to help out but he needed to remain here. The main enemy hadn’t appeared and he was getting a feeling that this was only a diversion tactic.

“Our soldiers are managing it, the demi-humans are ferociously trying to get to the other side of the bridge but our forces are driving them back.”

“Good, monitor the situation, we must continue… and we must do it faster, I shall return to the fortress.”

The transmission to Zhang Kuo went silent while he decided to go to the engine room. With how things were progressing they might be running out of time. While he wanted to conserve his power for the final battle, to make it easier on his people they needed to advance faster.

“Everyone, this is your Patriarch, we will be pushing toward the enemy stronghold faster.”

After informing the people of his new plans he placed himself in a lotus position in front of the golden egg. From his spatial ring, he removed previously prepared golden pills that would boost his spiritual energy reserves. He had expected such a possibility and it was time to use up one of his trump cards.

A handful of those pills made their way into his mouth. Due to a recipe that he developed himself, they tasted like candy and made the process of eating a lot easier. His body began to rapidly give off a radiant glow as he pushed all of his holy energy into the improved fortress engine. With a new injection of power, the whole massive structure started vibrating and moving faster.

It was the slowest of the flying vessels in the armada but with the injection of more energy it could equal things out. The large anti-gravity ring that was humming under it began to get bigger and the speed increased to match the other ships. With the fortress moving, it brought along the giant barrier that would be hard to cross by the demi-human attackers.

Their trip continued with a lot of resistance from the combined tribe forces. They didn’t let up with the assaults but the powerful sect Elders along with Bahamut were enough to stop anyone from breaching inside the barrier. Together with the constant barrage of cannons they were making their way towards their destination.

Slowly but surely they were getting in range of the other demi-human base. Yet before they arrived the golden palace stopped glowing and the anti-gravity disc under it reverted to its previous state.

“I was too slow…”

Zhang Dong threw a batch of recovery pills down his gullet before quickly appearing outside. They had stopped above a destroyed city that was devoid of any life. He remembered this place, it belonged to the sect he visited when he was chasing after Wang Long. They had not heeded his warnings and didn’t retreat in time after he left and this was their fate.

This was not the reason why he stopped with his hasty approach. The reason was that he felt something, a powerful being had appeared and had managed to cross through the bridge at this very moment. When looking at the map that presented him with the enemy locations he could see a bright red dot that was previously not there.

‘Could that be their Emperor?’

The warning signals were going off in his head as he felt the massive amount of spiritual energy that this person had. Compared to the other demi-humans he was truly on another level. While everyone else was a body refiner without that much outward energy, he was different. The spiritual energy that he had was not inferior to his own, it might have even been slightly above Zhang Dong’s.

‘So this is one of the end bosses?’

Considering that this had been a scenario created by the person that made the system, one of these Emperors might have been the true last boss. They all could be at similar levels but perhaps one side was supposed to be defeated earlier than the others. Could this Demi-human Emperor be the true last boss or was he perhaps on the weaker end of the spectrum?

‘Lucius and Argus aren’t as strong as this guy… but they supposedly have a king that should be stronger.’

“We shall return to the previous formation, prepare for battle!”

He could contemplate all that he wanted but the battle needed to be fought. Even though the enemy had reached their side, getting here wasn’t a total waste. This Emperor was here but it seemed that a large chunk of their forces was still going through the bridge. While there they would not be able to pose a threat.

The first thing that he noticed when he was outside, was that the demi-humans that were trying to stop them all cleared out. It was as if they were inviting them towards their fortress that Zhang Dong could already see from this location.

‘That’s an ominous-looking tower… but it kind of looks, decrepit?’

The structure looked like it was hastily put together by people that didn’t know how to construct things. There was spiked iron wire everywhere, even the black stone walls were wrapped around it. The structures were large and gaudy with strange red tribal drawings everywhere. From what he could tell, this place belonged to the green-skinned demi-humans that were similar to orcs

‘So that’s their leader?’

Then he finally saw him, he was floating up in the sky on top of something that looked like a chariot made from thick bronze-like metal. The person riding it was wearing a similar bronze armor that was probably made from some kind of superior metal. It wasn’t shiny, instead it seemed to be covered by dried-up blood and scratches from bladed weapons.

On top of his head, he was wearing a large helmet that was similar to ancient roman ones the remembered from some old history lessons. Yet the most characteristic thing about this man were the three protruding horns that made him look like some kind of demon.

‘Does that make him three times as strong as the other leader types?’

Even without getting closer, he could tell that this being was more than twice his size, probably over four meters tall. The horses that were pulling this chariot that seemed to have been lifted from a Roman arena were even bigger than their master was. Yet his appearance was similar to a human's, with the exception of the horns and mouth filled with pointy teeth.

“So, my prey has appeared before me, this does please me.”

Before he could examine his opponent further he heard him speak. Even though they were many kilometers away from each other, he could hear his voice clearly. It carried power along with his Dao which caused the earth to quake. This quickly gave a read on the man’s abilities which were something that he didn’t encounter before.

“Turn back if you wish to spare your and your people's lives. There is nothing that awaits you here but death.”

“Hah, you wish me to return, where is the fun in that? Only when a warrior encounters their equal can they truly become alive! Now come, entertain me, my prey. I hope you won’t be another disappointment like the ones that came before you.”

There were two large armies on both sides. His side possessed the numerical advantage but the demi-humans outperformed the average soldier. In a direct battle, the enemy would be superior but his side had various other pieces of equipment to make up for their lack in combat strength.

Yet they were the aggressors this time around, they needed to secure the bridge and block it from ever being used by the demi-humans. That their Emperor appeared was always a possibility but luckily his eyes were only focused on Zhang Dong. This only made the next decision easier.

“Kuo, I’ll leave the fortress in your care, I will lure their leader to a secluded location.”

“But Patriarch…”

“Follow my orders, if we both fight here our forces will be caught in the middle, without their leader their forces shouldn’t be difficult to handle, I trust in you and the elders to be victorious.”

This time around he would need to give it all, Bahamut quickly flew over to its master to act as a proper mount. The demi-human Emperor was fast approaching, with each step in the air those massive horses took, the whole area started shaking. It was as if they were running on the ground and crushing it at the same time.

After appearing on Bahamut’s neck both of them left the safety of the protective barrier. Just as he had theorized the enemy Emperor instantly gave chase to where he disappeared to. Soon enough both of them found themselves in a desolate area with nothing but earth and rubble, it was time for the showdown between the two leaders to finally start.

A note from Kuropon

Thank you for reading!

Don't forget to follow, favorite, rate.

Donate | Discord |

Chapter 510

“Bahamut!”

Zhang Dong pointed out with his sword to order his familiar. The large golden dragon opened up that large maw to produce a stream of heated energy. It flew towards the large demi-human Emperor with the intention to drown him in hot divine flames. Yet, before they collided with the target they were smacked away to the side by a large cleaver.

This large weapon was probably as thick as a human and this person was wielding two of them around. The moment the stream of heat approached it was batted to the side as if it was smoke. He could see dark purple energy crackling around those blades. The space was being shifted in a strange way when the blades were used, it was as if the holy breath was still going forward but the area around it shifted.

‘Is he able to bend space around himself?’

Zhang Dong had a lot of knowledge concerning the various Daos in this world. He didn’t go into much detail into all of them but even he was able to use some lesser gravitational spells. This Emperor that he was fighting seemed to be specialized in gravity. All of his ranged attacks would suddenly change trajectory when that purple light appeared, sometime they would even be absorbed into a strange black orb.

‘Does this ability have a limit or can he create black holes as he wishes?’

This was a problem, Zhang Dong was capable of producing beam spells that involved his Dao of Lightning and Holy. These attacks were being countered by the gravity techniques this person was using. It seemed that he would need to get closer to get in some damage.

‘His soul is too strong for my soul arts, unless I can interact with his body directly it won’t do me any good.’

If he could overpower this man’s soul with his own then his victory would be assured. For this, he needed to start exchanging direct blows to slowly scrape away on his defenses. This would certainly not be an easy battle as he could tell that the man had a strong body. It was above the other demi-humans but only after a proper exchange would he know how much of a difference there was.

“Good… But is this all there is to you? Entertain me more!”

While he was trying to figure out his opponent from a distance, the Emperor kept rushing in like an angry bull. There wasn’t any tactics involved in the way he fought, it was clear that this guy was a brute, quite similar to Huo Qiang from his sect. Feeling out his opponent wasn’t something he was interested in, it seemed that he didn’t think that he needed to be strategic, his powerful body and gravity techniques were enough.

*GROWL*

“Shit, reduce your size Bahamut.”

After a couple of clashes, the first side to suffer was his. During a fly by the demi-human Emperor managed to nick Bahamut’s side with one of those cleavers. This was the first time he had seen someone being able to damage those golden scales this easily.

His dragon was just far too big to make fine adjustments in the air. Luckily he could shrink himself down to gain a boost in speed while also retaining most of his strength. Together with the vast healing capabilities that Bahamut possessed, he was back in action within a few moments.

Zhang Dong was now more similar to a dragon rider. With him being on top they swooped back towards their opponent. With the help of the smaller frame, they began their counterattack. His sword collider with the huge cleaver for the first moment, and his wrist took instantaneous damage as he almost lost the grip on his weapon. Only thanks to his healing capabilities was he able to quickly recover for another exchange.

The Emperor that he was fighting with looked like a monster. After a few clashes his mouth opened up, and the smile he was showing was truly gruesome. He was really enjoying himself, though Zhang Dong’s arm felt like it would fall off, his opponent could feel the effects as well. While his body was in good shape, his soul was being damaged each time they made contact.

‘What a sturdy body, I can’t go against this guy in a contest of pure power…’

Normal cultivators that were on his level would usually lose out due to Zhang Dong’s massive amount of stamina. He could just heal all of his wounds and continue the fight until his opponent became weakened. In this situation where the Emperor’s body refining technique was above his, he needed a different approach.

‘I should have the speed advantage, but I can’t use it during mounted combat, I need to get him down from that chariot.’

This was clearly not working out, his opponent was much heavier. With each strike, Zhang Dong felt the weight of the world dropping on him. Each time the Demi-human Emperor would increase the weight of his cleaves. It was already a miracle that the sword that he created hadn’t disintegrated on the spot. Only by surrounding it with a thick layer of sword energy was he able to hold on.

“This might hurt but I need your help, Bahamut.”

Thus when the time for another collision was upon them, he decided to change his target. His opponent was a battle idiot and had clearly lost himself in the contest. He was enjoying himself too much to see that the dragon that Zhang Dong was riding changed its flight path to collide with the two large horses that were pulling it.

A massive explosion rocked the sky as the two grandmasters collided with each other. Everyone that was fighting on the sides stopped in their tracks as they were affected by the shockwave. When turning to see what was going on, they could see the demi-human Emperor entangled with the much smaller human master.

“Haha, you wish to fight me like this? You overestimated your capabilities, now fall before me!”

The man dressed in bronze-like armor performed a double slash with both of his cleavers. He was aiming for the moment when Zhang Dong lunged forward when jumping down from his mount. Yet before he could perform a full swing something interrupted it. Another collision of metal against metal rocked the whole place.

Zhang Dong connected with the dual blades at the exact moment they were crossing each other in a cross pattern. It caught the Emperor in a bad position that mitigated some of the force that was created and pushed him down to the ground. A purple comet surrounded by golden energy collided with the rocky surface on the ground to create another massive explosion.

‘Did I just break both of my wrists?’

While the Emperor was producing a massive creator below, his hands were in a world of hurt. His body refining skill was maxed out, his whole body was made out of resistant metal but his bones were still getting shattered with almost every hit he had to take. Only thanks to his healing skills was he able to hold on.

‘At least I got him down to the ground, hope this will even things out.’

For a moment he looked to his familiar that was getting double-teamed by huge black ponies. They were surprisingly vicious in their attacks which caused Bahamut to receive damage and back away. He had hoped that he would be able to easily devour the two by himself but they proved to be close to his level.

“You… No one has been able to push me this hard in centuries, this is exhilarating, show me more! This is truly the hunt that I’ve been waiting for, I will be sure to place your head with my other treasured trophies, you have earned the right to be in my collection!”

“Sorry, but I still need this head, my wife would kill me if I became a stuffed animal.”

Zhang Dong descended down to the ground where the Emperor was slowly moving toward him. With them facing each other while standing there, the size difference had become apparent. His opponent was still capable of deflecting his ranged attacks and would probably get back onto his chariot if he let up, it was time to go toe to toe with this monster. If the leader was defeated then the rest would disperse.

Without a proper leader, the tribes would be unable to work with each other. Even if they remained in the Azure Dragon Empire, they could be slowly hunted down while his forces block the bridge to their original zone.

‘This is easier said than done, first I need to defeat this guy, he is a fighting maniac so he probably won’t try any underhanded tactics…’

“Okay, let’s try this again…”

As his enemy was slowly moving toward him as if he was assured of his victory, Zhang Dong activated one of his techniques. It was an old one that surrounded his whole body with a golden aura and an array of lightning bolts. His body started getting bigger, muscles began expanding and his all-around aura began to become fiercer.

This rapid change caused the demi-human leader to stop for a moment. His previous wide grin became even wider, it was as if he was enjoying that his opponent was becoming stronger before his eyes. Soon the two charged at each other, yet this time around the larger of the two was getting pushed back.

The two giant cleavers were swung around by the brutish Emperor. They destroyed the ground that the two walked on, yet Zhang Dong did not falter. Each hit was evaded with grace and after each dodge, a counter was delivered swiftly. Soon the man’s giant body started caving into all of these attacks, when they finally separated the winner of the exchange was obvious.

“You…”

After getting pummeled by Zhang Dong that activated his power-up technique, the Emperor was slightly stunned. His grin didn’t disappear, instead he looked pumped up.

“Finally, after so many years I find myself a worthy prey for the hunt! The hunger, it fills me even now, I will bite down on your jugular and feel the warmth of your blood!

Instead of a concerned opponent, he was rewarded by another psychotic speech. It was clear that this Emperor wanted to be challenged, all of the battle maniacs were like this. Probably he would be satisfied even if he lost as long as it was to a proper challenger.

“You have earned the right to my name and I will have yours!”

“No, I really don’t care about your…”

“Engrave the name of Phallusius Maximus as you die by my blade!”

“... Of course you would have a name like that…”

Zhang Dong gave out a sigh after receiving the name of his opponent. Even though he wanted to laugh this was not the place for it. His opponent was already powering up as he got ready for a counterattack. It was finally time for the real battle to start.

A note from Kuropon

Thank you for reading!

Don't forget to follow, favorite, rate.

Donate | Discord |

Chapter 511

“Wait…wait…!”

“Have you realized that you are not a match for me? It’s too late to turn back, your fate has already been decided and it's to become a head on my wall.”

“No, that’s not it… your name is Phallusius … Maximus?”

Zhang Dong asked while having difficulty keeping a straight face. After all this time he thought that he had gotten used to the strange names in this world, but this one caught him off guard. The huge muscular man looked super serious and unsure of what was happening, this made the whole scene even funnier and caused him to chuckle slightly.

“Did you just laugh at my name? You dare mock this Phallusius Maximus!”

“No please stop… Let’s just go back to killing each other and not mention our names, how is that?”

“What’s wrong with my glorious name? How could a savage like you understand our glorious culture.”

Phallusius Maximus started going on a rant, it was clear that the man never had a proper conversation in his whole life. This was probably due to no one being able to talk back to him. His strength placed him in a position close to godhood.

“Sure… next time your say that your predecessor had a name like Biggus Dickus.”

“You know the grand Emperor's old name? Have you visited our lands before? Who are you?”

“Huh?”

He wasn’t sure if he should laugh or cry. It was clear that whoever made this world had a ten-year-olds sense of humor just like him before he transmigrated. Yet this was not the time to joke around, a bloody battle was taking place around them.

With his enhanced senses he could hear his generals giving out orders and demi-humans being blasted by the cannons. For the time being, his forces were managing to push towards the green demi-human fortress. But if this Emperor of theirs changed his targets, then they would be in for a lot of pain.

“Well then, Ginormous Phallusius or whatever, It doesn’t matter what your grandaddy was called, it only matters that this daddy here is going to kick your ass.”

Getting an opponent angrier was one of the basic battle tactics. The demi-human Emperor’s forehead and neck veins started popping up after the few choice words. The man was clearly not used to being antagonized by the people around him and very easy to anger.

His energies intensified as he slammed those two large cleavers into the ground. The purple gravity energies ripped the rocks out of the ground. He gathered those rocks around the two blades while large boulders started floating around his large frame. With each step that he took the ground started shaking and it was obvious that he was affecting gravity to make himself heavier.

Regretfully Zhang Dong needed to get in closer. His ranged attacks were all getting bent out of shape and missing. Only when he got closer could his aura cancel out the Dao of gravity enough for his attacks to actually reach this muscle idiot's flesh. Thus he charged in and quickly dodged out of the way of the downward swing that caused the earth below to explode.

After a skillful dance to the back of this armored man, he delivered a cut to the slightly exposed side. His golden blade which was clad in a thick layer of all of his three Daos was able to draw a bit of blood.

‘It’s shallow…’

Before he could take a double take a large cleaver was coming for his head. When moving to the side he could feel that air pressure along with the space around it being distorted. When moving to the side he was pelted by small rocks that burst to all sides.

“You think something like this will take this Emperor down?”

Phallusius laughed before sending out a giant burst of energy to all sides. This was enough to force his retreat and pancake a hundred-meter area around the demi-human Emperor. A giant circle of squished earth appeared that was uniform from all sides and perfectly flat. But after the exchange he was feeling good, even though the flesh was already mending itself back, he had managed to inject his energies into the brute's body.

‘He looks fine on the outside but his soul is taking direct damage and wavering…’

This soul-sucking ability of his was the real trump card here. Without it, he didn’t feel like he would be able to win. His opponent was truly a tank that could shrug off almost all conventional attacks. Zhang Dong didn’t want to admit it but Phallusius’ body refining skill was above his and the gravity attacks were at least equal to his lightning techniques. Then the holy arts were less effective as this man was not an evil being nor a demon that were susceptible to them.

‘He might not be aware now but the more his soul gets damaged the weaker he will become…’

The two high-level leaders continued to clash with each other while generating massive shockwaves. Each time Zhang Dong was forced to retreat while tending to his wounds with the help of his holy energies. Even though he was healing himself his white robe started getting drenched in his blood.

For everyone that was looking in, it seemed like Zhang Dong was losing. All the cuts and punches that he was able to deliver to the demi-human Emperor’s body were shallow and didn’t draw much blood. After a few exchanges, it was the United Element Sect Patriarch’s body that was looking like it had gone through a tornado.

“This has been entertaining but I grow bored of this, die!”

Finally, Phallusius started gathering up all his energies for the final blow. All of the rocks and boulders that were floating around him traveled at speeds comparable to bullets to weaken his enemy before the last blow. He expected Zhang Dong to dodge most of them but it was only a smoke screen for the main blow he would deliver.

Yet, as he was powering up those huge cleavers to slice Zhang Dong’s body into four equal parts he caught a knee in the face that forced him back. This attack felt different than before, his nose was instantly broken and he could feel the taste of blood in his mouth. His body was quickly recovering after the damage he took but the pain was real.

“A lucky blow… now die!”

The two flew past each other but yet again, an elbow found itself embedded in the demi-human Emperor’s face. Once more he was tossed to the side while being unable to deliver the finishing blow. It was as if his enemy had gained a strange power boost that made him more ferocious. The only logical explanation was that Zhang Dong was burning through his life energy to achieve a short-term boost.

“Such tricks won’t work on me!”

Phallusius continued with his assault while being convinced that his opponent would run out of steam soon enough. However, with each and every strike that was exchanged his opponent became stronger. All the hits that he was receiving started adding up and his body was also becoming riddled with wounds that weren’t healing as fast as before.

“Y-you…”

“You still haven’t noticed? I guess this is part of my luck that you’re not much of a thinker. You’ve probably never really had to exert yourself against an opponent of a similar level. But… not that I’m complaining.”

Zhang Dong was actually surprised after being able to turn things around this easily. The demi-human Emperor was truly powerful, probably the most powerful opponent that he had ever faced. Even though he was this powerful, there was one fatal flaw in the way that he fought. This was probably due to him being strong from his birth.

“What are you prattling about, I have faced many opponents, I have never known defeat and it won’t be any different now!”

While Phallusius was raging on, Zhang Dong just smirked. The brute hadn’t even noticed that he was receiving attacks to his soul. This person had naturally strong defenses, there weren’t many experts that could perform valid attacks to the souls of such experts. Thus he was probably unaware that his power levels were slowly deteriorating.

If the soul of a person was damaged in any way, it would start affecting their body. Only if the soul was balanced could a person give a hundred percent, but with even a slightly damaged soul they would start losing strength. His tactic was easy as he slowly chipped away on the demi-human Emperor’s soul to reduce his defensive and offensive capability.

‘I didn’t expect this to work so well. I thought he would catch on but he just kept coming like a mad bull…’

While Phallusius’ soul was huge and already slowly mending itself to health, the Emperor was not aware of it. As a person that was only interested in getting stronger through more conventional means, he lacked in other fields. Perhaps if he faced someone like the Azure Emperor that was also someone that was more conventionally strong he would have been victorious but as things stood now, Zhang Dong would win.

“Die… Die… DIE!”

Phallusius was seeing red as he continued to relentlessly assault Zhang Dong with all of his might. Yet all of his wild swings that were previously able to deliver menacing blows could be easily dodged by his opponent. The added gravity that was making things difficult to dodge felt like a minor inconvenience and Zhang Dong started counterattacking. For every blow that he received, he returned it fivefold.

Previously he was taking it easy and mostly focusing on damaging his opponent's soul. Now after his plan had gone through he could wholeheartedly toss himself into the bout. Just like before shockwaves started spreading in all directions but this time around the one kissing the floor was the demi-human Emperor.

The weight of those massive cleaver-like blades could now be repelled by Zhang Dong’s smaller longsword. Suddenly a large gash appeared over the man’s chest, his armor was unable to defend him after the gravitational field wavered. With the difference in might becoming equalized the person with more skill would be victorious and in this case, this was Zhang Dong.

It was quite surprising as Zhang Dong had not spent that much time training. Normally the large man before him should have much more experience. He truly had been blessed by this world with an overpowering body and presence. Yet this would be the reason for his downfall as he had never had to compete with anyone this close to his own level.

“Y-you… you are the prey, not me … I shall feast on your bones after I crush your skull with my bare hands!”

In a sudden act of despair, the Emperor jumped up into the sky and kept going up into the stratosphere that even Zhang Dong would have trouble following. With him came large chunks of the earth that they had destroyed. All of those giant boulders started flying up as if they lacked any weight and were quickly sucked into a dark purple orb of energy.
“... Is he doing what I think he is…”

It seemed that this would be his final attack, he would bring down the force of the heavens and probably eviscerate everything down below, that is unless a certain Patriarch used his own secret attack to stop it.

A note from Kuropon

Thank you for reading!

Don't forget to follow, favorite, rate.

Donate | Discord |

Chapter 512

“That looks like a giant meteor…”

Up in the sky above him, he could see a small speck of red. When using his enhanced eyes to zoom in the tiny object turned into a massive rock formation that was above a kilometer in diameter. The demi-human Emperor had decided to drop this thing on him without worrying about his own people. If this huge object collided with the ground a large portion of demi-humans would be affected as well.

‘Has he lost his mind?’

It wasn’t really a smart plan, the meteor would take some time to get down here and he could always just dodge it. Yet there was a problem, if he decided to evade this attack then his own people would be caught up in the blast. He did not believe that the defensive formation would be able to last through the large explosion. The golden bastion and the people inside of it had the highest chance of surviving but the ships that were flying around it didn’t.

‘Does he know that I will defend my people or did he just lose his mind in a last attempt at victory?’

It made sense to go after his good heart but he did not give this person any clues to believe that he would just take the meteor head-on. Either this was some kind of trap or the man was just out of ideas after the usual brute force approach didn’t work. From the looks of things, the demi-human Emperor had never tasted defeat. It wouldn’t be strange if he lost all of his reasoning because of this.

“You’re not the only one that can work with gravity here…”

Zhang Dong shouted while pointing out with his finger. Before him, a tiny speck of light appeared that was the size of a pea. This tiny orb floated forward while many tiny orbs of light surrounded it. These light balls started to quickly rush to the center as if they were being absorbed by the radiant speck.

A tremendous amount of light was flowing into the small circular area that continuously expanded and got smaller. This was an attack that he had used in the past against a nascent soul master before he was thrown to the other world. Now with his added knowledge of magical spells that also included gravity and magnetism, he was able to improve on the idea of this pulsar-like object that could contain a massive amount of energy and mass.

The size wouldn’t be nearly as large as the meteor that was slowly being finished. Instead, it would have a much higher density and comparable mass along with his combined energies. Even then he wasn’t quite sure if this would be enough but luckily he was not alone in this battle.

While charging up he had notified Zhang Kuo. With the help of his whole sect, he would get rid of that massive object. His golden fortress pointed its cannons towards the sky and was ready to fire when the meteor got in range. All the other large flying ships did the same as they pointed their main cannons upwards.
The plan was simple, keep shooting at the giant meteor that carried the demi-human Emperor inside. They would not be able to destroy it but they could reduce its size. Then he would finish the job and deliver a devastating attack that would hopefully kill the gravity monster.

“GRRrrrr.”

“Bahamut, I see you were victorious, could you help me out here? Go help the others, they won’t be able to hold out for long if they aim the cannons at the meteor.”

His familiar had finished taking out the monster horses and also eaten them in the process. While his sect started shooting at the sky this allowed the demi-human tribes to launch an attack on the wavering protective barrier.

Without the spiritual bullets raining down on them they would easily force their way through and damage the ships. His golden dragon would not allow this as he charged right into everyone. His loud roars were heard by everyone and were followed by the screams of the merciless demi-humans that were falling like flies.

‘I expected them to evacuate…’

It was surprising to see people ruled by fear not evacuating from this area. It could soon turn into a giant crater were both sides suffered immeasurable deaths. It seemed that they were so frightened of their Emperor that they would rather risk staying.

When looking through Bahamut’s eyes he could tell that their eyes were empty, there was nothing else that they thought about than battling. This was a contrast to the people that were fighting with him. Their eyes were filled with hopes and dreams. They had many reasons to achieve victory and all of those made them into proper human beings.

“I guess I’ll have to answer their call, can’t make my cute sect juniors see their Patriarch falter in the face of danger.”

In the past, he would be feeling the weight of all those hopeful people crushing down on his shoulders. Yet, now it only motivated him to push on towards victory. He couldn’t imagine achieving as much as he did without the people around him pushing him towards a goal. While the drive to achieve progress was still there, without his family and friends around to push him even further, the world would feel empty.

‘I wonder what they would think if they knew that their Patriarch is this sentimental…’

In this world ruled by power, it was taboo to get too attached to others. Their enemies could use his family and sect members against him. Normally a person in his position would be forced to abandon anyone from his close confidants if it endangered the sect in any way. Even now in this battle, no one would blame him if he just evaded this meteor to retreat. As long as he was alive the sect would be able to survive and be renewed.

Finally, the energy blasts started becoming louder and louder. The meteor above them was truly huge and it wasn’t getting much smaller. Even when the Argonaut class ships used their huge cannons they weren’t able to lower its size by much. However, this was time to show of a secret weapon that he discovered while traveling here.

The Golden Dong Palace was retreating towards his location and to where the main impact location would be. Zhang Dong’s body hovered upward all the way until he was right above the large golden structure. In this position, he was directly under the largest tower of the palace.

“Charge me up!”

He shouted while the roof of the large tower started gently moving. It opened up from four sides to reveal a large white gem in the middle. It was already glowing and filled with spiritual energy of the holy variety that it had sucked from the golden egg engine.

A beam of thick light shot towards the location of the small pulsar that he was creating. Instantly what was only about ten meters in diameter started expanding in all directions. With the giant infusion of energy that was part of his faction system, he was able to tremendously power up his large-scale attack.

The sphere gave out a thunderclap as it was constantly filled up with various Daos that he was capable of producing. Suddenly the sky above him darkened as the burning meteorite came crashing down on top of them. His whole sect moved under it to accommodate his technique, their belief in him being able to destroy the gigantic burning mountain above them, was unshaken.

Sweat appeared on his brow as he was slowly becoming drained of all of his energies. If for some reason his enemy remained, it would be hard to continue with the battle as before. The beam of light from the tower became thinner and thinner until there was nothing more that he could absorb. With his technique now ready, he pointed it towards the center where the highest concentration of gravity was and tossed it forward.

“Everyone, brace for impact, protect yourselves!”

With the spinning sphere of light thrown, he quickly ordered everyone to take cover. The collision of the two heavy bodies rocked the entire place. The trees that were still standing were instantly flattened along with the earth as the shockwave of the blast exploded in all directions. The demi-humans that were outside the protective barrier had no place to hide and were almost instantly eviscerated from existence.

The golden orb that Zhang Dong produced was a hundred times smaller than the meteor but it still managed to burrow inside it to reach the core. There the maddened Demi-human Emperor experienced another defeat as it rammed itself into him and quickly released all of that stored energy.

The meteor started cracking from the inside and finally erupted into many smaller chunks. These large burning boulders were pushed to the sides by the explosion that started from the middle. These large chunks flew everywhere and this also included directly below.

“If it’s not enough then … Cleave the heavens!”

After gathering his spiritual energy and the surrounding mana he used his blade to split the heavens in half. A thin layer of sword energy flew forward and divided the already crumbling meteor into two halves. Thanks to this attack the large shards were pushed to the sides allowing his people to quickly drift to the inner side of the protective barrier that was getting a beating.

“yOu dAmN bUg!”

Zhang Dong looked towards the sky while feeling wobbly. He had burned through a massive amount of energy and his enemy was still coming. Phallusius wasn’t looking good, his left leg and arm were missing and his whole body was covered in burned marks. He looked like a shriveled-up burn victim but his body was still functioning.

In his right hand, he still had one of those huge blades that was sparkling with purple light. He was going for the kill and coming down faster than the meteor to finish the weakened Zhang Dong. Yet before he reached his nemesis a large golden dragon appeared to block his path. It opened its massive jaw and blew out a massive torrent of energy that connected with the demi-human Emperor’s body.

“Not enough, I will not die here, I am …”

Phallusius’ body lost a few more chunks but he clung to his sword and was ready to kill the dragon and then the man behind it. Before he could reach his destination another opponent appeared. It was a massive energy fist created from plasma and fire energy that belonged to non-other than Huo Qiang. Not far behind it was a dragon made from water, an attack delivered by Zhang Zhi.

“Aid the Patriarch!”

Many other such attacks appeared and continue to collide with the demi-human Emperor’s body that was deteriorating with each second. When it reached Zhang Dong there was nothing left but a half-torn torso and a bony arm.

“I…”

Before the large man could mutter his last word he was beheaded by the Patriarch’s golden blade. There were no life-saving techniques involved, no demi-humans to help him in his time of need. The Emperor of the enemy faction was dead and the battle was almost over.

Chapter 513

“How could this be…”

“Hah, the Emperor is dead, now it’s finally going to be my turn!”

“Was that monster truly defeated? … Hey, what are you doing?”

Phallusius Maximus had appeared like a comet and left the stage just as quickly. To the demi-human's surprise, the undefeated monster that had remained their leader for centuries was gone. No tears were shed for him, instead, this was a chance for the tribe leaders that remained alive to rise to the top.

“What are they doing?”

Zhang Kuo from inside the Golden Dong Palace looked on in surprise as the various demi-humans started attacking each other. It was chaos, everyone was split up into several groups while not paying attention to the cultivators they were fighting with.

“Are some of them fleeing back through the bridge?”

While part of the demi-human tribes remained in a frenzied state, some of the smarter ones started fleeing back to their lands. They were aware that after the person that held them together as a group was dead, they would suffer a quick defeat. It didn’t matter that the United Element Sect had drained a lot of their power to defeat the Emperor, the fact that they managed to do it was enough to make them flee.

‘It won’t take long now, the bastion should be enough to clear them out now…’

Zhang Dong panted while devouring a handful of recovery pills. Luckily there was no one there to sneak in an assassination attempt as at this point in time he was quite weakened. The elders that were with him surrounded him from all sides to keep watch while he was quickly recovering. The monster was dead and he had fallen a lot sooner than he anticipated while also leaving behind a reward.

‘Bob, what is this?’

An item floated in mid-air, it was glowing purple and radiating the Dao of gravity. The item in question was the three horns belonging to the Emperor. It seemed that this was the source of his power or perhaps his power had been transferred into them through some strange art.

‘The item in question is compatible with the user’s system, do you wish to absorb it?’

‘I can use this in that way?’

Without the old system, he thought that he would be unable to gain anything after defeating his foes. To his surprise after defeating his foe by cutting of his head, the three horns burst forth and floated towards him as if they wanted him to accept them as their new master. He had seen these horns before but the ones that belonged to the other tribe leaders didn’t behave like this.

“Patriarch, please be careful.”

“It’s fine don’t worry, go back to our sect and aid them against the demi-humans, their forces are in disarray and they started fighting each other but this battle isn’t done yet. We will push forward and secure the bridge to their lands.”

He shouted out while also grasping the glowing horns, after agreeing to absorb them Bob went to work. The purple energy washed over him and was quickly integrated into his own body. To his surprise, all of the Dao headed towards the not yet bloomed seed and increased its size even further.

‘Does this mean that I can’t germinate this thing if I defeat more of their leaders?’

The increase in his power wasn’t that large but he was given the full comprehension of the gravity Dao. When thinking back to his old system he remembered that it was possible to buy new Daos. They cost an astronomical amount of spirit points but were perhaps required to get to the next stage. After adding this one, he had four whole paths of cultivation that he had a full understanding of.

‘I can increase the weight of my punches and also produce a gravity field around myself…’

He was already thinking of a few ways that he could implement his new knowledge. Some of the old techniques that he knew could be improved, even the pulsar could be condensed more to form a proper celestial body. This was however not the time to contemplate his newly gained power.

The war needed to be won, there would be enough to contemplate his next move later. Thus after grabbing the two huge blades that survived the massive explosion he headed toward his people. After he arrived out in the open, his targets were the tribe leaders that posed a threat to even the nascent soul masters here. After the large meteor fell down, the protective barrier was in shambles so now it was an all-out brawl between the two sides.

“U die ‘umie!”

His first opponent was a large green-looking monster that was similar to an ogre in shape. He had a large horn on his forehead that radiated a wicked power. Yet compared to the Emperor he wasn’t much. The giant club that he was holding devastated the land he walked on but if it couldn’t connect with his opponent it wouldn’t be of much use.

Thanks to his new gravity attribute that he had gained, it was easy to increase the weight of that club and make it even harder to swing around. The size of this monstrous opponent would be his downfall as he soon found a giant cleaver connecting with his thigh. This was followed by an arc of golden energy that went straight for his throat.

‘I think I’ve gotten a bit stronger, is this what this scenario wants me to do? Kill the Emperors and gather all of their Daos for myself before ascending?’

It made a lot of sense, normally the person with the system would be fighting for a hundred years while gathering spirit points. Then when the main boss arrived beside the system currency they would be rewarded with a free Dao. With time they would have so many resources and easily advance to the next stage. However, what came after leaving a world like this, he did not know.

There were three other forces from the other empires that still existed. But one of them he was allied with so that limited the number of rewards that he could get. The Emerald Phoenix Emperor sounded like someone that combined both wind and fire energy while the people from the north sea would obviously be water-based. Then there was also the Azure Dragon Emperor that might also be a potential source of a reward.

While he was already looking toward the future the battle continued. Without the defensive barrier, their ships started being damaged by the demi-humans ranged attacks. Even the huge bastion was getting pelted from all sides and even attacked directly by some frenzied attackers.

Try as they might, they were not able to get through the massive golden gates and the reinforced walls. The cannon fire slowly demolished the fortress that seemed to lack many defensive features. This coupled with the infighting only brought them a fast victory.

…

“Is it over?”

After a day of fighting the demi-humans were all retreating. Now without the threat of their monstrous Emperor, they did not shy away from saving their lives. Most of them fled directly back through the bridge area while others scattered in random directions. The battle was won but it would still take some time until they captured or killed the remnants.

“They are fleeing Patriarch, should we give chase?”

“No, we shall move as we planned, take over their fortress, and reinforce our position!”

“As you wish, Patriarch!”

Zhang Zhi cupped his fists while flying into the distance. Just like with the other fortress they needed to quickly create a teleportation gate and move their engineers over. It would take some time for the next wall to be built but after it was complete they could finally rest easy. With the limited space and the casualties that the demi-humans suffered, it would be hard for them to gain a foothold again.

“Is there a problem, older brother? You should be joyful, we have met our enemies and been victorious?”

Huo Qiang appeared from the side, his clothes were almost all gone and his body was filled with wounds. He still radiated an oppressive aura of someone that had gone through a life and death experience. It seemed that his younger brother had managed to reach a new level while battling one of the tribe leaders.

“That we did but we need to look at the bigger picture, this whole war is far from over.”

“Is it about that Wang Long fellow? Don’t worry, he and the demonic cultivators will fall before us just as anyone in this Empire…”

Zhang Dong raised his eyebrow while also interrupting Huo Qiang as the conversation was going in a direction that he didn’t like.

“That’s enough, if someone was listening in, they would think that we wanted to conquer the Empire for ourselves.”

It wasn’t strange for the strong to rule above others. Huo Qiang probably just mentioned what the other cultivators from his sect were thinking. In their eyes, the sect was becoming stronger and stronger. Their Patriarch was on the level of the Azure Emperor so they were getting prideful about their existence.

“Oh, I get it, you want to keep it a secret! Don’t worry, I won’t tell anyone!”

“No… We are not trying to conquer the Empire…”

“Yes senior brother, we are not!”

Huo Qiang gave Zhang Dong a wink before bursting out in laughter. Some of the other elders were of course listening in. After the reaction from his right-hand man, he wasn’t sure if the other idiots got the wrong idea as well. For the time being there was no time to correct them as his battle fortress was slowly moving into place and in need of repairs.

“My friend, you did it and with such ease.”

“Hey there Argus, thank you for your help.”

The grand wizard Argus was still here, during the battles he could see him aid his people in battle and also kill a fair share of demi-humans in the process. Now he was looking at the shabby fortress of the enemy faction that still remained.

“As I promised you can take a look around but please hurry, I will be replacing that building soon.”

“You have this old man’s gratitude!”

‘Look at him go.’

The old man pulled out a medallion and started casting various spells but Zhang Dong didn’t believe that any holy relics could be found here. He was already attuned to the energy fingerprint of the relics but could not feel even the faintest spark of energy here.
Yet this was not his problem, the magical shield would probably not help him in the coming battles. Instead, he looked towards the distant reaches where no cultivator dared to venture. The lands of the demonic cultivators were near and it was time to pay his old acquaintance a visit.

A note from Kuropon

Thank you for reading!

Don't forget to follow, favorite, rate.

Donate | Discord |

Chapter 514

“Emperor, there is a matter we must bring your attention to!”

“Huh? Can’t it wait? Can’t you see that busy?”

Three elders were looking at a lazy Azure Emperor that was resting his head on his wife's thighs while she continued to feed him some grapes. To the side were two lovely-looking women just fanning them with large fans. It was a strange scene as it was all happening in the throne room where some people were already kneeling down.

“So you’re just going to stand there? Fine, what is it? Make it quick and then let me have my peace.”

“Thank you, Emperor.”

One of the elders clasped his hands while stepping forward. If Zhang Dong was here he would recognise the three as they were the most important elders from the Long Clan. Even though they had a dislike of how their leader conducted himself they couldn’t really call him out on it.

“This information concerns your younger brother, Long Dong.”

“Oh? What has my little brother done this time?”

The moment Zhang Dong’s name was mentioned, Long Qing perked up and turned his head towards to old man that was talking.

“We got word that he has been taking parts in the battles with the Otherworlder, he has been successful in reclaiming most of the western Empire.”

“My little brother has been busy, he used the ancestral relic well.”

Long Qing finally decided to sit up straight and move himself to his actual throne. Previously he had occupied a large bed that was behind it.

“So, is that it? Why are you panicking over nothing?”

“My Emperor, this isn't the issue…”

“It’s not? Explain then, and make it quick.”

Long Qing seemed bored and uninterested in what was happening in his own empire. The three elders had a hard time holding in their sighs. This wasn’t anything new to them, their leader had long since become bored of the issues in the court. The only thing that seemed to give him joy was his wife and now his brother which added a little bit of randomness to his life.

“We have been keeping a closer look at Long Dong ever since his… departure.”

The people here were all surprised that the golden palace that was kept a secret was able to vanish only a little while after finding an owner. Previously they had underestimated Zhang Dong’s capabilities and ignored what he was doing in the Empire. If he wanted to play the hero then it was fine with them.

“He has been growing his forces rapidly, even the strongest Otherworlder was not his match, if the legends speak true then this should not have happened…”

Now it was different, he could not be ignored anymore. Zhang Dong was now posing a direct threat to Long Qing, the Azure Emperor. Rumors were spreading, people liked to pit the two brothers against each other and naturally, sides would start to form.

“So my little brother isn’t weak, isn’t that a good thing? His fame will only increase our Long Clan’s legend!”

“If that only was true, Emperor…”

“What do you mean?”

“Long Dong, your brother has been performing all of his acts with his previous name of Zhang Dong… it doesn’t seem that he holds out Clan to a high standard.”

Long Qing started rubbing his chin while contemplating. This was something that even he knew wasn’t acceptable. When he reclaimed the lands it wasn’t in the name of the Azure Emperor or the Long Clan, it was in the name of the United Element Sect. It looked like he was trying to distance himself from the Long Clan and establish his own separate branch.

It wasn’t odd for large families to have branches from the main house but this was only tolerable if one side was superior. If the branch family became too strong it could cause a rift or war between them and the main family. This was what the elders here feared, Zhang Dong was becoming too powerful and influential for them to control him.

“The refugees that we had accepted are starting to return, we won’t have enough people to bolster our forces for the future attacks as we had planned, we must deal with this issue now before it gets out of hand, Emperor!”

This was not a simple matter, for the Long Clan they had now only replaced the demi-human invaders with the United Element Sect. For them, the danger was on a similar level now but Zhang Dong had an actual birthright to challenge the Azure Emperor for the throne. If that happened the Long Clan would become the branch family or perhaps eradicated in the process of changing leadership.

“Now this is a problem, I’ll have to talk with my dear little brother to see what his intentions are…”

“But Emperor … “

“Quiet!”

Long Qing’s oppressive aura washed over the entire throne room which even made the three prime elders twitch. This wasn’t a reaction they were used to, their leader had always remained a jokester while not taking anything too seriously. Yet now his disdain was plastered over his whole face.

“I will make the decision, do not act without my approval.”

The message was sent and the people here could only bow. However, some of the elders weren’t looking too happy about this decision. A lot of them were unwilling to wait for the worst possible outcome but would they go against their leader to achieve their goals?

…

“Hh… This looked different the last time I was here…”

Zhang Dong floated up in the sky, his gaze was on all the water that spread out into the distance. The land of the demonic cultivators was further ahead on a large separate island. There was a small problem, the layout of the land had changed.

“This ocean wasn’t this big, it must be the northern invaders spreading it…”

When glancing at his system map he could see the red dots in the north but the largest concentration was in the northeast. Where he was going was more to the west where the fish people's presence should be lowered. However this water was giving him a bad vibe, the concentration was low but he could feel some otherworldly energy mixed in.

After spreading his spiritual sense he could feel that this alien energy was affecting marine life. The fish were acting strange, their eyes had a faint glow to them. With some more prodding he figured out the problem, it was some form of mind control.

“I never did like the sea…”

He recalled a scene from his youth where he almost drowned when he was ten. While he had not developed a fear of swimming he was still not comfortable with wandering out too far away from the shore. The sea monsters that plagued the depths could be agitated with all of this strange energy affecting them. It was like slow-working poison and perhaps even the stronger ones would eventually be controlled.

“Patriarch!”

His contemplations were interrupted by a sect member, he just nodded before a report was given.

“As you have instructed we have begun the assembly of the new wall, if everything goes well we should have a barrier within three weeks.”

“Sounds about right, try to speed up the production if you can, the demi-humans could try launching a counter strike and we still have the remnants to worry about.”

“Yes, Patriarch!”

The large-scale battle was over and the casualties were lower than expected. They had lost more machines and relics than lives which was always a welcomed outcome. This was all thanks to the enemy forces going into a berserk state with their leader gone and all of the infighting.

This was one of the largest problems with people being led by only strength and terror. When that person on the top was removed the people below did not have anything holding them together. There was no cause that they were fighting for together, just their own selfish reasons. Only after a new Emperor was crowned would they be able to bounce back.

If this was even possible within the next hundred years was questionable so the threat was mostly within the stragglers that now roamed their lands. Zhang Dong already heard the rumors of the old sects and clans trying to reclaim their own lands. This could have catastrophic consequences as they were usually inferior to the demi-human warriors.

‘I will need to leave the bastion here as a safety measure, for now, Qiang and the other nascent soul masters will patrol the lands and that leaves me with some time to scout…’

This was a big problem, he did not want to wait anymore and go quickly push all of his forces to the demonic lands. Yet the demi-human remnants could decide to launch a counterattack to get back to their own side or to take back their old fortress. Without them worrying about the Emperor killing them, there was no way of knowing what they could do.

‘It would be nice if they just settled down and stopped fighting… but they are just a wounded beast and they will certainly try to bite when backed into a corner.’

While he didn’t need to go after the demi-humans he couldn’t have his forces move out yet. The lands needed to be reinforced and then a squad of potential demi-human hunters needed to be established. They would stay back to battle the leftover demi-humans while his main forces traveled to the north to take care of the Wang Long situation.

‘This might take another month…’

Zhang Dong pondered but he quickly decided to at least check how things were up north. Even though it was too soon for his forces to do an all-out attack, he could still perform a mission. Infiltrating the demonic lands would be quite difficult for anyone below the nascent soul level.

Even though everything was flooded, there were still various stopgaps like poison mist before the end was reached. There was a reason why the other sects stayed away from those lands. There was nothing to gain but death from going there and the resources of demonic sects didn’t translate into the orthodox martial arts practices.
Without monetary gainst no sect was willing to risk their life even if they could get rid of this bunch of murderers that plagued the lands. The regular sects and clans didn’t trust each other, some of them would be weakened during such an assault and then probably lose their standing. Thus the biggest shield for the demonic cultivators were the orthodox ones that could not trust each other.

‘I guess it's time for another little adventure…’

Before plunging himself into the unknown he decided to return to his golden palace. There he would stock up on all the necessities before venturing towards his next destination.

Chapter 515

“We shouldn’t 'ave come here, this was a mistake…”

A grizzled old man with a dark tan looked at a monstrous tentacle rising out of the sea and pulling his ship down. The massive storm was already a big problem but then the sea creatures were agitated.

“Captain, you said that this wouldn’t happen, were the blood crystals not enough? ”

“Shut yer mouth, the sea has been actin' strange these months, somethin' got the creatures spooked, me ship shall remain hidden but they spotted somethin' here, it's like must be one o' ye! Are ye hidin' somethin' that attracted the beasts t' me ship!?”

The people that looked like sailors took out their sabers and pointed them at the other group of passengers. Both sides had about the same fighting strength and it seemed the ship's captain was willing to toss the other side overboard to appease the monsters below.

“You dare go back on your promise, we haven’t even reached the destination, you clearly lied to us, where is the island?”

The ship captain frowned after remembering that he had taken these people on a quick cruise to a secret island location. The island was supposed to appear once a year for a week period and had a secret ground filled with various tests and trials. He had sold this information and fare for a lot of blood crystals that were the currency around the demonic lands.

“It should be here, I said that the sea was actin' strange lately…”

“Excuses!”

The two leaders from each side started shouting at each other while the lackeys got ready for a fight. The only problem was that the sea creatures that were around them were already devouring the ship which made this infighting even more stupid.

“Stop this nonsense or we all will die! Please, grandfather, appease your anger this is not the time.”

A young woman of alluring proportions placed herself between the leader of the robed figures and the pirate look-alikes. She was the only one that could see the bigger picture, if they didn’t work together they would surely die.

“Meifen … you are right, we need to take care of the beasts but then we will have a talk!”

“Aye…”

The ship captain nodded at the sailors that turned to face the dark tentacles coming out of the sea. However, even when they turned to face the monsters they were still keeping an eye out for the other party.

They were in lands without any laws or morals. Cheating between the demonic and evil cultivators was a daily occurrence. The sailors could have easily planned all of this just to kill them, the monsters that were attacking the ship could have even been part of the scheme. Yet after realizing that the ship was actually being torn apart did the party of cultivators decide to work together.

“These things… are they at the core formation level?”

Only the captain of the ship and the leader of the cloaked figures had any luck in harming the tentacles. The monstrous squid that looked like a smaller version of the legendary Kraken was just too strong for the others. All of their weapons just bounced away and couldn’t cut through the thick flesh.

The man that the young woman named Meifen called grandfather jumped forward. In both of his hands, he was holding a giant gloomy-looking scythe. The dark blood from the sea creature was dripping from it but also making it radiate more power.

“... Now!”

The man waited for the monster to pop its ugly head out. It was bulbous in shape and mostly consisted of a swarm of eyes and shark-like teeth. When it drove its mouth into the ship he used this chance to slash diagonally. The weapon he was holding burst forth with dark red energy as a massive blade surrounded by wailing souls was formed. This attack collided with the sea creature and sent it tumbling back.

Following this attack, the ship’s captain thrust forward with his heavy rapier. A sonic boom escaped from it as the blade tip collided with the monster as well. With both of the attacks hitting the creature retreated into the depths while its tentacles let go of the ship.

“That wasn’t bad for an ugly bastard.”

“Aye, no’ bad ye ole fart!”

Both the leaders started eyeballing each other once more, the monster had retreated but their feud was not over yet. Either the ship captain returned the blood stones that he took or he delivered them to the requested spot. It was a problematic decision as he had already suffered massive damage to his ship and would need these crystals to cover the expenses.

“Return the crystals, you have lied about the… huh?”

Before the argument could continue further a massive wave hit them. It came from the side where the squid monster vanished.

“Is that blasted thing still alive… no… how could this be!”

To the surprise of the people on the ship, it was something else. A giant humanoid hand rose from beneath the depths with the squid monster in it. This monster that had almost caused them to go under was handed like a little fish by the creature that just appeared.
A massive scream of pain escaped from the Kraken look-alike before it was squished before them. The giant of the depths rose up and pushed the full-sized ships as if it was a tiny boat. Its body was covered with dragon-like scales and the head was similar to a hammerhead shark. The upper body had a humanoid shape but from its back, a mass of tentacles with various horns and teeth could also be seen.

“I-it’s a leviathan? … Why would one of these things be so close to the shore?”

The ship's captain crumbled to his knees as he saw the gigantic monster devouring the other sea creature. A leviathan was how they described the rulers of the dark seas. They were monsters on the level of nascent soul masters and were considered stronger than their human counterparts.

“Meifen… please forgive your stupid grandfather…”

“Grandfather…”

The two family members clung to each other while looking at the beast. It was clear that they would end up inside of its belly, there was no escape. Its energy wouldn’t allow a core formation expert to fly away on a sword, there was no place to hide or run, if a miracle didn’t happen they would be quickly devoured.

This massive being of the depths looked down at the tiny beings below. It could feel the two core formation experts on the ship and it desired their spiritual energy to sustain its body. The massive mouth opened up to show off the rows upon rows of greatsword-sized teeth, the squid flesh still on it as it craved more sustenance.

Yet while everyone was trembling in fear and had their lives flashing before their eyes, something strange happened. The beast stopped right before chomping down on the ship. Everyone gathered there had a front-row seat to the stinky mouth of this large being.

It suddenly started being pulled away and rose up into the air. The monster’s lower body was similar to that of a legendary mermaid while also having a plethora of squirming tendrils. While the leviathan were considered on par with nascent soul masters, they weren’t known for their flight ability, there was something fishy going on here.

“W-what is happening… what is that purple haze around it…”

“T-there, up in the sky!”

Meifen looked up to where her grandfather pointed and quickly saw a man’s figure floating up in the sky. It wasn’t hard to figure out that this person was pulling the creature out of the sea but how was he doing it? The monster started squirming around but its massive hands collided with some kind of transparent barrier that continued to get smaller and smaller.

After a few moments, they could see a truly gruesome display of bones breaking. The leviathan was being crushed while floating defenseless in the air. What kind of being could do something like this to a strong creature like this? Was this the second coming of the Heavenly Demon?

…

A few moments earlier…

‘Hm, this should do… can’t use my old pseudonym of a demon hunter, so I need something new…’

Zhang Dong was hiding his presence while shrouding his body in the thick clouds above. Below him was a mass of water filled with various sea creatures that would give his previous self nightmares. The creatures had sharp teeth, tentacles, and eyes where they shouldn’t have. Devouring each other seemed to be their only pastime and perhaps the reason why the water was a murky dark.

He had already spent a few days zooming through the air towards the lands of the demonic cultivators. It was quite boring and the only thing keeping him awake was his new disguise that he was still deciding on. His robes were of course switched out to more demonic-looking black ones with various occult-looking symbols on them.

His new persona would be a solo demonic cultivator of unfathomable power and knowledge. He could not look like a bum, instead, he decided to go for a more refined-looking elderly person. A white bread that was cut at angles to pronounce his chin was the first thing he attempted, his hair was slick and plentiful. He somewhat based it on an old meme from his old days, just an aged-up version.

For the time being, he needed to lock away his holy aura. Luckily he had gained a nice replacement with the Dao of gravity. Coupled with his spooky soul Dao he could shroud himself in mysterious purple energy that wasn’t far off from what the demonic cultivators used.

‘The concentration of spiritual energy here is even worse than in the lower regions.’

He had a lot of knowledge concerning the empire. The demonic cultivators used a different way to get stronger than the orthodox ones on the mainland. Instead of mostly using spiritual energy to slowly cultivate the arts, they absorbed it from other living beings. This allowed them to cultivate at the lower levels faster but halted their progress later on.

‘So they turn the beasts and other humans into blood crystals that they use as a substitute for spiritual energy.’

This was the main reason for all the evil cultivators being hunted down. A lot of them infiltrated the mainland to gather humans as a resource. After partaking in the evil arts they were unable to use regular spiritual energy as a resource. They needed to instead capture other cultivators and turn them into human pills.

‘This is going to be an interesting expedition… I just have to remember to not get involved with their squabbles… Wait, what's that?’

In the distance, he spotted a lone ship fighting both a storm and a large squid monster. Yet this was not what he was worried about, below them was a much bigger creature that was grinning for some reason and even further away there were some strange fish people.

“Oh geez…”

A note from Kuropon

Thank you for reading!

Don't forget to follow, favorite, rate.

Donate | Discord |

Chapter 516

‘I can’t just leave them to die…’

Zhang Dong looked at the giant creature rising out from the depths. The people on the ship were clearly from a demonic clan or sect. They called the creature a leviathan and it was at about the power level of a middle stage nascent soul master.

Even though they were supposedly ‘evil’ cultivators, he also spotted a few people that weren’t that tainted. The people that lived in these lands were just a product of their environment, the strength they gained was mostly for survival. Some of the robed figures were also quite young, it was as if the elders had taken their disciples out for some training.

Then there was also another reason to help them which was to gain information. People from the mainland didn’t really know anything about the demonic island and the rules there. He wouldn’t be surprised if the demonic deeds of the people that lived there were over-exaggerated.

‘Not like the sects I’ve run into are really any better…’

He recalled people from the Dark Palm Sect that didn’t really act differently than a demonic cult. They used the lower clans as cannon fodder and milked them for resources. Perhaps there was a way to clear things out with these people that were forced to rely on demonic rituals and blood crystals.

Finally, he decided to take care of the leviathan, with the help of his gravitational Dao he was able to get rid of its immense weight. Hoisting it up into the air with the help of his spiritual energy was quite easy after that. Once it was out of the water he also noticed a rapid drop in the monster’s fighting capability. From the middle stage, it dropped to the lowest of the early stage.

‘Make sense that these things would be weaker when not underwater, didn’t expect such a rapid decline though.’

With how much stronger he was than the beast it was easy to just crush it with pure Qi. The sigh wasn’t pretty but he wanted to make his entrance as imposing as he could. The people on the boat were truly shocked but in reality, he wasn’t trying to impress that group, he was going for the strange beings that were hiding in the sea.

Even while he was crushing the leviathan in an imposing manner he was still paying attention to them. If his theory was correct then these mare people belonged to the northernmost invaders. One of the beings there was at around the strength levels of this leviathan but not really above it.

From what he could tell these sea creatures were uncommon around these parts. Someone from the ship had commented on them usually not appearing here. There was also one thing bothering him, why were the huge sea creatures not attacking them. There were two more monsters of around the same size next to the leader, perhaps it was this leader that ordered them to eat the ship with the demonic cultivators inside.

“Hm… so you have chosen … death!”

Zhang Dong disguised as an oppressive demonic cultivator called out toward the submerged people. The ones on the ship were quite confused and horrified as they could only see themselves as the recipients of those words. All of them almost instantly dropped to their knees as they tried to appease the scary demonic cultivator.

Yet suddenly two similar-looking sea creatures burst out from the murky waters below. Considering their body size being vastly over their intended target they produced giant waves that sent the damaged ship to the side.

Their target didn’t budge though, even though he found himself in the mouth of one of the monsters, it couldn’t fully bite down. He had surrounded himself with an energy shield that only caused the teeth of the monster to shater.

“Ew… have you ever tried using mouthwash, what is that putrid smell?”

The smell was horrifying and also filled with poison. Luckily it wasn’t that hard to cancel it out with the help of his shield. He released a burst of energy that made the large monster’s head explode. Normally the other one should have noticed the disparity in power and ran to protect its life. It took a lot of time to grow to this level, even beasts had a strong survival instinct.

“So, your masters want me dead, is that it? It won’t go the way you want it to…”

After the first monster was falling down into the water the other one attempted some kind of ranged attack. From its mouth, a torrent of green water flew his way. Instead of dodging it though, he pulled out a pitch-black longsword that he used to cleave it in half. Behind the ship with various people was in the line of fire, he still needed to ask them about the situation in the demonic lands so he couldn’t have them be melted by this corrosive concoction.

His sword energy traveled further and connected with the beast. It almost split the whole beast in half but it managed to dive back under the water which caused the attack to weaken. It was an interesting sight to behold as this monster’s wounds started to almost instantly heal themselves. Small black tentacles came from the sides to grasp the flesh that was falling off to pull it back together.

His true enemies didn’t budge from their underwater hiding place, perhaps they were convinced that if they remained there then he could not reach them. Regretfully for them, Zhang Dong originally came from a water-element inclined clan. Even though his Dao of water was not perfect it was still above the norm.

By combining some of the water arts and the new gravity dao he started pushing the water to the side. A massive hole started to appear in the middle of the sea. He had some luck as the water wasn’t all that deep and some kind of strange ruins were right beneath. The huge monster dropped down onto the regular ground with no water helping it move and behind it were several fish people shouting out commands.

“The gill-less has spotted us! What should we do oh great Nahmah?”

The person with the title was of course the leader. There was a group of about twenty people here, everyone besides the leader were around the core formation level. This looked to be something like a scouting party that was using the sea creatures as disposable weapons.

These ‘people’ had some distinctive looks. The weaker ones looked more like creatures from the deep with bodies covered in fish scales. Their faces faintly resembled human beings with gills sticking out from the side. They had hands with webbings between fingers but lacked legs that were replaced with a large tail. The leader, on the other hand, looked like a mermaid with the upper body of a man and the lower body of a fish.

‘Hm, do they evolve to resemble humans the stronger they get?’

He couldn’t really tell if the person called Nahmah was from a different species or if he was different due to his higher level of power. His appearance made Zhang Dong recall some of the old cartoons that he watched when he was young. The fish person was holding a shiny golden trident in his right hand and had a long white beard.

‘Don’t see any mermaids around though, all of those guys seem to be males.’

To his disappointment he could not spot any beautiful lady mermaids, instead, he was received by ugly fish people and one cranky-looking grandpa. Even though he had managed to push the waters apart he could feel that the old man was fighting him for control. After raising that golden trident there was a slight pull from the sea, he even had to use quite a bit of his Qi to counter this effect.

It seemed that he was still lacking when the water Dao was involved but while watching this man perform the strange techniques with his trident, he was already learning. There was an aura of this Dao around that weapon but it was of a lesser Dao, and it only involved the sea. Probably only the leader had the knowledge to use the higher techniques and could drop some kind of item that he could absorb later.

“Yoink.”

The power disparity was just too big, without a need to use any grand techniques he managed to pull the trident away from the stranded fishman. The old man even flew for quite some time before he decided to let his weapon go. Now he and his men were in a rather panicked state.

“Hm… interesting… so this is how they control the sea creatures.”

For someone of Zhang Dong’s level, it wasn’t hard to inspect this weapon after pushing his spiritual energy within. He was much stronger than the previous user so it wasn’t difficult to overwrite the weapon. Now he was the master of this lower heavenly ranked item and it was the catalyst to control the huge sea monster.

“Grab him!”
After pointing out with the trident toward the remaining Leviathan it wasn’t difficult to make it obey. The monster was out of the water though so even when it tried going towards the merman it wasn’t able to catch him. It seemed that this person could actually fly like any other nascent soul master. He had surrounded himself by a water bubble and was now making his escape towards the dark sea.

Regretfully for him, before he could reach it a massive downward gravity push crushed him into the hard ground underneath. Zhang Dong would not let this person escape, they were part of the enemy invasion and he needed more information. There was no reason to kill them yet, they might turn out to be more friendly just like Argus.

‘In you go.’

After successfully containing their leader called Nahmah, he dumped him into his replica medallion. There he would contain and interrogate him later. The weaker lackeys were all dropped off into the prison cells as well. With some luck, he would be able to use them as bargaining chips later. They did attack the people on the ship first and then him directly, so he could always use the self-defense argument when asked by their leaders.

‘That’s about it… The fish people aren’t that important now, I need to get to Wang Long.’

Within a few moments, the danger was gone and the waters were closing up. Zhang Dong didn’t sense anything worthwhile in that ruin. It seemed to have been occupied by someone at the nascent soul level. Any techniques and resources there wouldn’t be worth the hassle of exploring. Perhaps later he could forward the information to his sect and someone from the juniors could examine it further if they found it worthwhile.

‘Now, what do I do about these people… I think that I scared them a bit too much…’

When looking back at the people on the ship he could see that they were spooked. All of them were down on their knees and not daring to look up. At least it would probably be easy to get the information he required from them. Thus he started to slowly float towards the group of scared people while thinking of pulling off a proper demonic cultivator persona.

Chapter 517

“J-junior greets the great s-senior…”

A group of terrified demonic cultivators were looking at a true monster. The man had swooped in and killed more than one Leviathan that could destroy a whole armada of ships. Then opened up the sea to reveal the secret island they were trying to reach to eradicate some strange other sea creatures.

For some reason, he took interest in the little ship of theirs and the weak cultivators on it, which normally didn’t bode well. Such beings of power operated on different rules in the demonic regions. Even if they started a feud with a powerful sect, most of the elders wouldn’t take revenge for a few juniors being slaughtered. They wouldn’t risk getting killed by an equal even if it was to take revenge for their faction.

The man looked strange. First, the robe was quite flamboyant and filled with strange occult symbols. Normally demonic cultivators were more reserved and hit their true power before taking action. This man on the other hand was pointing to himself as if he wanted to be identified as a madman.

Then there were his strange facial proportions, he had an oversized square jaw that looked unnatural. His body padded out of that robe which implied that he was quite muscular. Perhaps he had integrated some beast DNA into himself, from a gorilla?

His appearance was not the problem but his unknown motives. It wasn’t odd for beings of power to use lesser cultivators as cultivation resources. Everyone here was already thinking about the worst possible outcome. There were only a few reasons that someone of this status would help them.

One if they were part of their clan and another for nefarious reasons. It didn’t seem that anyone here knew this person so most of them were already shivering. They could only hope that their deaths would be smooth and that they wouldn’t become lab rats for a madman.

“Hm…”

The powerful man started stroking that perfectly angular cut beard while looking in the direction of a young woman. The young girl had been stunned in place and unable to properly show decorum before the powerful man. She was just standing there with her knees trembling and staring right at him.

“M-meifen! P-please forgive my granddaughter, great senior, she isn’t versed in the ways of the world, please appease your anger with my life!”

“...”

Zhang Dong narrowed his eyes at the crazy old grandpa that pulled out a dark-looking dagger and started moving it towards his own throat. He had only descended to ask for directions and ask about the political climate on the demonic island.

What he needed was information about the factions and the forces controlling it and Wang Long’s whereabouts. If he was lucky, his enemy would have been stuck at some demonic brothel without progressing much. He was a known pervert that loved to indulge his perverted desires. The demonic lands were filled with various she-demons that could probably satiate some of them to keep him busy.

“I am sorry Meifen, forgive your stupid grandfather…”

It was a truly dramatic exchange between the young woman and the old man. She was holding back her tears and lowering her head. The man really thought that they would all be turned into blood crystals at his whim. It was better to kill himself to appease a scary demonic cultivator than to try talking it out.

“... That’s enough …“

With a wave of his finger, the dagger in the man’s hand exploded and the shards were pushed to the side. The old man crumbled to his knees while apologizing instantly. They clearly thought that he was going to turn them into human pills or suck away their souls.

“Grandfather! Please, Senior, my grandfather didn’t mean to speak out without your permission.”

There were two sides here, one was a group of robbed cultivators from some kind of sect or clan and the others were sailors. It seemed that the latter was slightly smarter as they remained with their faces pointed towards the ground. Even eye contact could sometimes enrage the scary old monsters to go on a killing spree.

“Calm down, I’m not going to hurt you. I just require some information.”

He swished the long robe sleeves that he prepared just for the occasion. Yet his words didn’t seem to go through as everyone continued to panic.

“I see that you don’t believe me, raise your head, if I wanted you dead, then you would be already dead.”

Finally, everyone decided to listen to his intentions. Zhang Dong was somewhat surprised at the amount of fear and respect that these people had for him. On the mainland, people feared the ones in power but it was not to this extent. To them, he was like a hungry lion while they were tiny mice waiting to be eaten. It was as if they couldn’t fathom that he would not do something evil to them when he is finished.

“Do you really think that someone like me could gain anything from insignificant insects like you? The only thing that you will give me, is information.”

“I-information, Senior?”

“Yes, I have been away for many years, tell me the state the demonic lands are in, I’ve heard some words about turmoil in the empire, what has been happening.”

He could see the cogs turning in these people's brains. It wasn’t such a rare occurrence, old cultivators would vanish for hundreds of years and cultivate. Some even vanished for half a millennia and turned the whole world upside down after discovering some immortal treasure trove. This was what he hoped them to believe at least, it would at least explain why he was asking them to give him basic information.

“If it’s information that senior desires, then we from the Onyx Moon Sect will accommodate your needs.”

“Good but first… let us get out of here, those mermaid people could come back…”

No one responded to his mumbling as they were far too afraid to ask any questions. The ship that they were on had been partially destroyed. The main mast had crumbled and it would be hard to sail back.

Zhang Dong didn’t want to remain here, there was a possibility of a force of fish people coming after them. It wouldn’t be strange if the man with the trident had some importance. His disappearance would be noticed sooner or later, thus it was better to get to the demonic cultivator island.

“This ship is in a bad state…”

“My apologies great senior, we will repair it as quickly as we can!”

The captain that looked like an old pirate with metal teeth started sweating the moment Zhang Dong looked over the ship. Yet before everyone could start clearing out the broken chunks of wood, they were told to stop.

“That won’t be necessary, just point me to the demonic island, there should be a port city there, right?”

“Y-yes senior but how…”

The captain was clearly confused but before he could pose the question he felt a massive surge of spiritual energy washing over the entire ship. It was purple in color and was formed from some strange Dao that he didn’t understand. His body hair shot up as a strange uncomfortable feeling coming straight from his soul took him over. It was the same for everyone gathered here.

“You don’t need to worry about your ship, it will reach the port in one piece, now point me in the right direction and don’t waste my time.”

While talking the ship started moving, it jolted up into the air as if it didn’t weigh anything as Zhang Dong lowered the gravity around it. With the weight lowered it was quite easy to make the whole thing float up and even reach speeds comparable to a core formation flying sword. To the people here this was a shocking display of might, making such a large boat able to float withotu any assistance was not possible just for anyone.

“Ah, y-yes, it’s that way…”

The ship captain pointed towards a destination and Zhang Dong quickly pushed the ship in that direction. While he had his system map, the lands of the demonic cultivators didn’t show up there. He only had some general information but needed these natives to act as a GPS for the time being.

“Now relax, none of you will die if you are useful, tell me then, who is the strongest person among the demons? Have any of the old sects fallen or has it been quiet?”

While standing at the foremost deck and steering the ship forward he listened to the old man explaining. He knew that the people referred to the strongest masters as ‘demons’, if Wang Long had appeared here he would probably be given that nickname as well.

“As you wish, Senior. There has actually been a big change recently, The Crimson Sword Demon had been defeated by a newcomer and taken the crown as the strongest. He had been given the name Chaotic Demon due to his extreme illogical tendencies…”

“Chaotic Demon… do you perhaps know how this person looks?”

“No Senior, we only know that he is a man of youthful appearance that has been probably gained by unsavory means…”

“You have to know some rumors? Could it perhaps be this person?”

Zhang Dong was almost sure about this Chaotic Demon’s true identity. It had to be Wang Long but he needed to be sure. His nemesis could have just been hiding in a brothel instead and this person was just another monster that took the recent chaos as a means to take power. Thus he produced an illusion of Wang Long’s appearance from the time that the two battled.

“I-I’m not sure Senior, I have never met the Chaotic Demon, his identity is shrouded in mystery and not many people have lived to tell the tale…”

“So you don’t know? How about you? Does anyone recognize this man’s face?”

Everyone started looking at the life-like creation that was presented before them but no one was able to answer. They were all living on the fringes of the demonic lands, it was impossible for them to have seen someone as important as the Chaotic Demon. The more important issue here was that they weren’t able to answer the question which put all of their lives at risk. One wrong answer and the man would crush the entire ship with them on it.

“Really? Nothing… well that is disappointing…”

Zhang Dong frowned about the lack of information, after he dropped these people off he needed to check out the city they came from to gather more information. To him it was nothing but to them it was a fight for their survival. Finally the girl raised her head and shouted out as if her mind was made up.

“S-senior if I may speak!”

“Go ahead.”

“...T-there is a person that could know what the chaotic demon looks like and he hails from my sect.”

“Oh?”

He could see the grandfather sending his granddaughter several messages that he would normally not be able to hear. It seemed that the two were in quite some trouble and this was a hail mary pass from the youngster to get them out of it.

‘Hm, interesting…’

A note from Kuropon

Thank you for reading!

Don't forget to follow, favorite, rate.

Donate | Discord |

Chapter 518

A note from Kuropon

I'll be taking a little break so the next chapter will come next week.

‘What are you doing Meifen? If we bring this demonic master back with us, he could destroy the whole sect!’

‘But grandfather, we were unable to retrieve the treasure from the sunken temple, if we return as this the grand elder will use us as fuel for the next ritual. It’s better if we use this old monster and escape…’

‘You’re playing with fire my granddaughter but I can’t deny the truth in your words…’

‘...’

‘They really like to scheme in the demonic lands, don’t they?’

Zhang Dong read through the hidden messages that these two quickly sent to each other. There was an old technique to send encoded sounds right next to a desired target's ear. The sound waves were encoded and impossible to hear by anyone other than the desired target. This encryption was far too hard to get through even by powerful masters, thus they didn’t fear him overhearing their scheme.

This wasn’t true for him though, with the help of Bob that worked like a machine the encryption could be decoded. It was presented to him as writing on his system screen, he was seeing a chat conversation between these two that intended to pull one over him.

‘At least it seems that this grand elder had actually seen this Chaotic Demon before. They intend me to stall for them while they make a getaway…’

‘It would be great if this old monster just killed that grand elder bastard, we wouldn’t need to leave then…’

‘That would be the best-case outcome, my granddaughter but please leave the talking to me, you have never been good at acting.’

‘Thank you, grandfather.’

The two were only trying to survive so he couldn’t fault them for going through with this dangerous plan. He did not appreciate that they were willing to have their entire sect wiped from the face of the planet though. If he was truly an old evil monster and overheard this conversation, then following the usual cultivator rules they would die for besmirching his name.

‘Glad my sect isn’t like this…’

He could not imagine his faction members selling each other out like this. There was a certain level of trust between the seniors and the juniors. There was also a lack of death penalties for not fulfilling tasks from senior members of the sect that would produce these types of people. It was clear that the demonic sects took things a lot more seriously than the orthodox ones.

Zhang Dong decided to skim through the hidden messages that everyone was sending to each other. It was surprising how some of them were disrespectful when thinking that he wasn’t able to hear them.

‘Hey, what’s with that guy's chin…’

‘I know… why is it so angular? And that beard looks strange…’

They were mostly commenting on his appearance that he might have had too much fun in creating. Wang Long might have even been able to figure out that it was him by the meme he took inspiration from. Yet his aim was not to meet with his nemesis but to get information about the lands. Then after returning his people could create a perfect plan for assaulting the demonic cultivators.

‘I should ignore them. Will those fish people be a problem? Didn’t expect them to be there, if they appear while we are transporting our army, it might be a problem…’

The captured merman was in his spatial treasure. He was able to function out of water but there were side effects. His spiritual energy started decreasing and his body also shriveled up to an extent. It was clear that he was keeping himself alive thanks to having a high enough cultivation.

‘This means that their forces shouldn’t be able to infiltrate the mainland, that is unless they have something to flood it instead…’

It was clear that even the stronger members of this faction couldn’t live well under regular air. They needed water to remain strong and would be unable to push into their lands without going through rivers and giant lakes. Yet there was another possibility as it was apparent that these lands were becoming flooded. The sea wasn’t this deep before but if it was an effect that would continue was also unconfirmed.

‘Perhaps I should farm a smaller group and create a teleportation gate instead? These people live in some kind of port city, should I use their sect to hide? That might not be the best idea, they could sell me out instantly.’

One of the possibilities would be to grab some hidden land from this Onyx Moon Sect. They probably had some free space where he could create the teleportation devices. By slowly bringing in more of his people it would be possible to move the army here while ditching the sea route.

Yet these demonic sects only answered to power, he was clearly a strong cultivator but this wasn’t enough. The people wouldn’t risk offending the powerful demonic cultivators that existed here. The quality of the top demonic masters was higher than of the regular ones from the mainland.

They gained power by surviving horrific encounters. At the end of their journey, they were basically cockroaches with various ways of staying alive. They were powerful enough to win against their orthodox sect counterparts.

‘I guess, I’ll need to find a hiding place for this plan to pan out.’

‘Hm… maybe this chin is too big…’

While contemplating his new plan he started stroking his short white beard. He had wondered if he should grow one but always thought that he should wait until he was older.

“So, is that the city you fare from?”

“That’s right, great senior. It’s the Silent Moon city.”

From the distance, he could see a massive number of boats. Even before reaching the shore, they started to show up here and there. There were regular people here, not everyone was a demonic murderous cultivator. The core always consisted of the commoners that lacked the ability for proper cultivation. With how low the concentration of Qi was in these lands, these people were quite weak.

The ship covered by the purple haze was sticking out like a sore thumb. Everyone down on the ground could see it and the ones in power quickly became aware of his whereabouts. This was fine as before getting in range he scanned the entire area with his spiritual sense.

Just as he had assumed this Onyx Moon Sect wasn’t all that strong. There was only one nascent soul master in the entire area. From what the old man informed him, this was their main stronghold so there would not be any reinforcements coming.

‘While they only have only one nascent soul master, this sect is more similar to a clan from the Empire.’

This large island in the north of the empire had limited space. Fewer people lived here and of course, the clan and sect sizes would follow suit. This sect was considered on the tail end of the hierarchy as the stronger forces consolidated to the center of it. There he would find the Chaotic Demon and all the other nascent soul masters that were at the great formation level.

‘So you require at least a nascent soul master to form a faction here, makes sense…’

Demonic clans and sects were far more bloodthirsty. The only thing being able to keep them from attacking was power and this was in the hands of nascent soul masters. They would allow the clans and sects to exist while the underlings funneled most of the resources towards the leader. They would live but would be left with scraps and probably unable to gain anything that could threaten the leader's position.

At first glance, it wasn’t anything special, just a large collection of wooden houses that probably belonged to the various fishermen. The coastline looked strange, the water was reaching up to some of these houses that were flooded. This was probably due to the invaders from the northernmost reaches that could control water. He would need to monitor the situation and see if the water levels continued to rise.

Behind what looked like the fishing district was a more traditional-looking city with all the usual buildings. They didn’t look to be in the greatest condition, the walls were slowly crumbling, the roofs had holes and even from here, he could see a few fights breaking out in the streets.

‘I guess the demonic sects don’t really care about the living conditions of the regular people.’

When it came to the mainland sects, it would be seen as a weakness if their cities were in bad shape. They needed to at least have a proper exterior for when the various strong masters visited. Even if the sect was weak it needed to look wealthy and strong from the outside. Instead, they would force the weak and poor out or try hiding them in slums. Here, on the other hand, no one seemed to care.

Then somewhere in the middle stood a large pagoda. It was the most eye-catching building of them all and also in the best shape. This was probably the residence of the sect leader and perhaps also the inner sect disciples. The welcoming committee was also already coming this way. They consisted purely of core formation masters and quite a few women were mixed in.

‘Are they trying to throw demonic beauties at me?’

It wasn’t strange to attempt to lower a person’s guard by sexual means. It wouldn’t be hard for a lady of the night to slice a person’s throat during the act. Yet this only worked against inexperienced cultivators and not powerful cultivators such as him. This was more of a courtesy from their leader that probably sent them to figure out his motives.

‘I guess this is it.’

Finally, he was at his destination, the large ship was lowered by him so that it wasn’t that far away from a pier. As he lowered himself to the ground he thought back to his decision of acting as a being of power. Normally an infiltration mission would be done while hiding but after the last few failed ones he decided to do the reverse.

His new identity of a powerful old monster that returned from a lengthy cultivation session would keep most people away from him. He already knew that demonic cultivators wouldn’t search for trouble with their equals. They would slowly examine the situation before deciding to strike.

‘I can always go with plan B if things turn for the worse.’

Zhang Dong’s main reason was to gather information and perhaps see if he could figure out Wang Long’s whereabouts. The people that were approaching him would help him with that, even if they didn’t want to cooperate. Before the powers on the island would become aware of his presence he would fade away and come back with a whole army. Then finally he could end this charade and bring Wang Long to justice.

A note from Kuropon

Thank you for reading!

Don't forget to follow, favorite, rate.

Donate | Discord |

Chapter 519

“We from the Onyx Moon Sect greet the honorable senior. Our Patriarch, the great Demon of Immolation, sends his regards and hopes that you will enjoy your stay in our little city.”

‘They do like their extravagant names here, don’t they?’

Zhang Dong was hovering a bit above ground while looking at the group of kneeling cultivators. They were doing their utmost effort to accommodate him. It was the usual, never speaking out without getting permission or directly looking into his eyes. Yet they were still trying to feel him out. If he was weaker than their leader then his life might have been in danger.

“Do you wish us to guide you through our city? We have been handpicked by the great Demon of Immolation to tend to all of your needs.”

The one speaking was a beautiful young lady of around fifty years of age. She was a core formation expert which kept her looks young. The others were a lot younger and weaker. It was clear that they were an olive branch from their leader, if they died it wouldn’t be a problem.

Zhang Dong had heard and also seen that some demonic cultivators gained their power through acts of depravity. It was possible to slowly suck away a person’s vitality along with their Qi during the act. It was a less intrusive method than turning them into blood crystals but it was a lot slower. They were probably testing him to see if he would accept this gift and see how he cultivated.

“Don’t worry, I’m just passing by. One of your people mentioned that an elder could recognize the Chaotic Demon, I just wish to speak to this person and receive some information.”

“T-the Chaotic Demon S-senior?”

The crimson-haired beauty that was keeping up an alluring look, flinched. She had been clearly trained to entice people and never to show her true emotions but even then, she couldn’t hold it.

‘Is this Chaotic Demon so scary? If it’s Wang Long then he would probably go with the dual cultivation method…’

He could imagine Wang Long demanding new women for his acts of perversion. He only saw these people as Ai programs that could be replaced on a daily basis. It was looking good if he could just find someone to confirm his looks.

‘He could have always changed his looks though, so I might not get any information here either…’

There was always a chance of Wang Long changing his appearance. Then there was the use of demonic techniques that could make a person look more demonic and different. There was a reason why these demons mostly looked like scarecrows with loose skin.
“Is there a problem? Was their claim false?”

Zhang Dong turned his head towards the woman named Meifen and her grandfather. They were the ones that made the offer and also the ones that were planning on escaping when it was possible.

“Elder Zhiqiang…”

The woman that he was talking with send a death glare at the old man that acted as if nothing was wrong. There was no time to exchange hidden messages at this moment and from such a close distance, it might even be noticeable. For it to go smoother he also turned towards this Zhiqiang to make him talk.

“Speak up, who is this person?”

“Great Senior, the man that you are looking for is Elder Tang Donghai.”

“Then what are we waiting for? Call this Tang Donghai over, or is there some kind of problem?”

He could see that there was a slight change in their facial expressions when this elder’s name was mentioned. It was faint but he could pierce through the veil to quickly read through their poker faces. Zhang Dong had spent quite a lot of time acting like a stoic cultivator master. It was easy for him to tell if someone was surprised or nervous.

“A problem? I fear that Grand Elder Tang Donghai might be indisposed…”

“Hoh? Is he such an important person to deny me an audience?”

To act properly to his made-up status Zhang Dong raised his oppressive aura against the group of beauties. He didn’t target only them, the ground began shaking as he used the gravitational dao along with his soul dao to make people drop down to their knees. It had been a while since he had to threaten a large group like this but luckily it was working.

“P-please senior appease your anger… w-we must ask for the Patriarch’s permission… Elder Donghai is part of the c-core elder.”

“Hm…”

The curvaceous lady started talking quickly while making her explanation. It seemed that the pair that he rescued was playing with fire. By pointing him in the direction of this Donghai person they were forcing him to go against their Patriarch indirectly. It was possible that he was part of his family, it would be hard for him not to act if it came to a direct confrontation.

‘Is this Tang guy unreasonable?’

He wasn’t really planning to start trouble, after getting his information he would just change his looks and gather more information. After examining the protective formations here and measuring the main sect ground with his spiritual sense, he had the idea of what he was against.

There would be no problem in crushing his enemies but he didn’t want to go overboard in enemy territory just yet. While the demonic cultivators weren’t that tightly knit together they would form alliances if they went against a powerful foe. Their leader could also force them to act which would complicate everything.

‘I bet they won’t go overboard, they have survived here for a long time, this wouldn’t be possible without being cautious.’

“I require information, I’m sure you’re aware that beings like be don’t have much time to spare…”

“I… I will go report to the Patriarch, that is if you allow it great senior.”

“Go then and don’t keep me waiting for long.”

“Please come this way, Senior we have prepared a place for you to rest.”

Zhang Dong just nodded as the welcoming committee split up. The main lady that was previously talking to him rushed towards the large pagoda tower. He and the others headed towards a luxurious-looking restaurant in the more expensive part of the city. When flying there he could see people lowering their heads in fright. No one dared to move and even mothers were holding their children’s mouths to not offend the unknown master.

‘That’s harsh…’

It didn’t look good, the kids were small and malnourished. It was clear that most of the resources were funneled towards the sect and the regular people were having trouble just surviving. This was a stark contrast to how people saw him or other masters in Spirit Spring City. They were happy to wave and smile at him and the others.

“Please sit down, great senior, leave your troubles behind and enjoy our great food and drinks!”

Where he arrived was a large restaurant with a plethora of servants. While everyone was smiling and acting cheerful he could tell that they were all acting. It was obvious that they were fearful of him going wild. If for some reason the food was not to his liking it wouldn’t be strange for the entire place to be extinguished together with everyone working here.

‘Is this how it always has been or did Wang Long’s appearance change things…’

His target had arrived here a few months ago. The city was standing and people were alive so he didn’t just kill everyone. Zhang Dong's biggest fear was that Wang Long would continue to kill people to gain power. After destroying one of the great sects he had become much more powerful.

How much stronger he would get would be proportional to how many spirit points he gained. Luckily he was not the smartest, the points would probably be spent on exotic skills that might not work well together. What a person was supposed to do, was to find a good combination of skills that augmented each other. Then even above that was to actually gain experience while fighting strong opponents and not just spam ranged attacks without an end.

‘Man, they are really fidgety…’

While thinking about his next move he observed the serving staff here. All of them were on edge with their faces hanging low. They clearly didn’t want to be here, the thought of having to serve a powerful demonic cultivator wasn’t that great. If they made one mistake their life would be on the line.

This place was not in great shape, he had already spotted a few unclean spots and signs of corrosion. It didn’t seem that the other side was used to getting many visitors of his stature. All old monsters would find a region for themselves and force people to build them what they desired. There weren’t many at the nascent soul level that wandered around in search of information and friends.

Every task was left up to their juniors while they acted as the last boss. Most of the time they didn’t have to make a move. Even during conflicts, one side would just fork up some resources so that a fight wouldn’t happen. There would have to be a serious transgression to make an old monster fight another one.

‘This food doesn’t look to be poisoned but I’m not really hungry…’

The table was brimming with food that he wasn’t touching. This was to be expected as poisoning was the simplest way to die. No one really expected him to touch it but they still had to waste all of the resources for appearance's sake. Nascent soul masters didn’t require much food as they could mostly sustain themselves with water and spiritual energy.

‘If it was any other place, I tell the workers to eat it instead…’

He wanted to allow the people here to just eat this food or take it to their families. However, if he started acting nice it would be quite suspicious. Either they would think that he isn’t a demonic cultivator or some kind of spy from the empire.

The demonic cultivators hated the righteous ones, if he was discovered all of them would flock here to use him as cultivation material. Absorbing the spiritual energy of a proper orthodox cultivator was much better than creating blood crystals from the ones here.

‘This is boring… are they really going to make me wait? … Are they scheming behind my back?’

After arriving at the restaurant thirty minutes had passed and then soon an hour was approaching. The women even started playing on the zithers and dancing to amuse him, yet for some reason, he wasn’t getting any replies. Normally the elder should have rushed here instantly to give him the information so that he could leave.
‘Is this some strange power move? Is their Patriarch making me wait to assert his dominance?’

This was a possibility, by making him wait the Patriarch was putting himself above the new guest. Without knowing Zhang Dong’s true power level this was quite a foolish move. Perhaps he had a faulty read on him as he was hiding his power level? Or could there be some other reason?

A note from Kuropon

Thank you for reading!

Don't forget to follow, favorite, rate.

Donate | Discord |

Chapter 520

“Tang who is this person? Why did he appear at this moment? Why is he asking about the Chaotic demon?”

“I-I don’t know Patriarch…”

“You don’t know?”

The atmosphere in the room became stuffy after an old man’s body started getting engulfed in flames. It was the Patriarch of the Onyx Moon sect that was known as the demon of immolation. He was talking to the elder that the unknown master was asking for.

“What’s with this timing? Could it be a coincidence?”

The old man started scratching his chin with one of his thin fingers. Suddenly a knock on the door made him extinguish the flames that were making everyone sweat.

“Patriarch, the honored guest is waiting for you…”

“Tang, you better take care of this in secret… This person seems to have a grudge against the Chaotic Demon. We don’t know what he will do if he finds one of his bastard's acolytes here.”

“Y-yes Patriarch, I will keep it a secret, I had my people prepare the Enticing Pavilion.”

“The Enticing Pavilion? Yes, that should give us time, let him stay there until our esteemed guest has left, don’t let the two meet!”

“It shall be done!”

…

‘Should I just storm their sect ground? This is getting suspicious did something blow my cover?’

He wasn’t sure what was happening, normally no one would make a scary demonic cultivator like him wait this long. Yet he was stuck in this restaurant that was playing gaudy music and watching some women perform hip dances. For someone with a wife that looked a lot better than this, he wasn’t quite impressed.

‘Could they think I’m up to no good and are already preparing to attack me?’

It was hard to tell as the people here didn’t trust anyone here. Demonic cultivators could turn into enemies at a drop of a hat if it suited their needs. It was hard to imagine that they would just attack him out of the blue. Yet this was not out of the question, perhaps they were preparing a trap at the next place they would lead him to.

‘If they invite me into the sect's territory I need to be careful also I should speed this up. The less time I give them the better.’

“Enough, how long are you going to keep me here, where is that elder Tong!”

Acting like an offended master wasn’t hard. He only needed to slam his fist into the table while releasing some of that energy. With his Dao being able to affect souls his aura become even more bizarre. The people here had the feeling that their vital energies were being sucked, if they continued like this they would have their vital energies sucked out!

“P-please Senior, Elder Tong is just a busy person…”

“Is he too busy to meet someone like me? Do you want me to show you what happens to people that make me wait? Maybe I should talk with your Patriarch, what was his name again, Demon of Immolation or something like that?”

The people in the restaurant dropped down to the ground. They all knew that the person they were up against could turn them into dried-up corpses in a matter of seconds. There was no way for them to escape other than pleading. Luckily for them, the sliding door burst open and finally, a person from the sect appeared.

“Please, Senior appease your anger, Elder Tong is expecting your arrival and will answer all of the senior’s questions, I will guide you there!”

It was a young man in a lavish-looking robe. Zhang Dong could tell that he probably belonged to the core disciples of the sect. The robe was similar to the one that Meifen was wearing but it was more intricate. It was a clear distinction between their ranks.

“So you finally decide to show up and you still want me to follow?”

Yet he still needed to show his displeasure, they did make him wait. This elder Tong didn’t seem like someone that he should be considerate about. If the sect leader was the only nascent soul master here then this elder should have been a pinnacle core formation cultivator at most.

“T-this…”

The young man dropped down to his knees as expected. Even though he had his head down, Zhang Dong could tell that his face was showing something else than remorse. It was clear resentment towards him that was performing the act. This young man was probably of the young master variety and wasn’t used to not getting his way. most likely he had a silvery tongue but it was impossible to use it with tons crushing down on his shoulders.

‘I’m having more fun with this gravity Dao than I expected… maybe there is another way to extract them without gathering the rare boss drops’

‘A possibility exists.’

‘Bob? How unusual for you to speak up by yourself. What did you have in mind?’

‘It is possible to gain the power of origin through absorption of the human soul core.’

‘Wait… you want me to extract it from their souls or something?’

‘Affirmative, it is possible to proceed as long as a soul core exists.’

‘Can you be more specific Bob?’

‘A soul core is what the user understands under the term soul-divinity that is formed once a nascent soul is created.’

‘I see, so I can gain insight into the Dao if I absorb souls… I’m sure I’ve absorbed some souls that were on that level though, don’t remember gaining any knowledge. Wait, or was that because of my soul core?’

‘Affirmative.’

It was a strange sight for the people around Zhang Dong. A young prodigy appeared and was instantly forced down to his knees. Even now he was getting surrounded by a strange purple haze and getting crushed. The person performing this task though had his eyes pointing up as if he was thinking about something.

‘So, now after my soul core had formed into that seed thing, I might be able to absorb Dao’s via soul divinities?’

This wasn’t something that he was inclined to do. It wasn’t different then what the demonic cultivators were going through. If a soul of a person was destroyed then they could not be brought back or reincarnated. But he wasn’t sure if that was even possible or not just some kind of legend. While souls and ghosts existed, there was no way of telling if something like an afterlife was there.

‘Even if you reincarnate, if your memories get erased, are you even the same person… I guess this isn’t the time to worry about things like that…’

He was undecided about absorbing people's souls to gain their powers but this was not the place for it. What he needed to do was find Wang Long or clues to his whereabouts. This could also be a dead end and his opponent could have already escaped somewhere else.

The initial trace was the Chaotic Demon that recently appeared and apparently turned the whole demonic island around. During his stay in the tavern, he continued to ask about this person and was told many stories. For some reason, they were mostly positive but he knew how to read between the lines. It was clear that they feared this cultivator, perhaps his influence was even strong here.

“Fine, you may have your pitiful life, now don’t waste my time anymore.”

“Thank you, my lord, for sparing this one's life.”

The young man started bowing while showing a fake smile. Animosity was oozing from his whole being as Zhang Dong could see through that fake smile. It wouldn’t be strange if he wasn’t led into a trap now. Yet he wasn’t worried, the people in this city would not be capable of holding him or killing him. Perhaps if multiple of their best masters ganged together they could have a chance.

‘Was I always this cocky?’

Zhang Dong moved his hands behind his back and started floating a few centimeters off the ground. While following after the young man he continued to look around. Even though he was strong, there was always a chance of something going wrong. After the string of easy victories, he had been becoming a bit more confident in solving all of his issues. If he could only get to Wang Long before he became more powerful, then all of this could be over.

“We welcome the great senior!”

‘So this is the entrance to their sect?’

At first, he was confused that the area was this small but after getting closer he noticed the folded space. The inside of the large tower would be much bigger than he initially assumed. Only at this range was he able to decode the various layers of formations and this place had a plethora of them.

‘Is their master a formation master or something? Though he would be more of a hothead like Qiang. Usually, the Dao corresponds to how they act.’

There were certain truths in the world and this corresponded to Daos. Some personality traits were attributed to a person's mind Dao, fire for instance was usually studied by cultivators that had fiery characteristics. The wind was mostly studied by people that liked to travel a lot and the water Dao to the calm and collected.

Yet there were also exceptions, it was possible to get proficient in a Dao that a person wasn’t suited for. This could be achieved with the help of treasures and magical items. This was a demonic cultivator, he could have unearthed some kind of high-level mantra that used flame energy for cultivation.

While he would struggle to go against his nature with a help of a powerful technique or item it was possible to go above the inborn limits. This was similar to how Zhang Dong’s disciples had shifted their Dao towards lightning due to his involvement.

“Hm…”

“Please Senior, come in, our sect welcomes you with open hands, we have a special place prepared.”

He didn’t like how this place looked, there were many slaughtering and illusionary formations everywhere. If he wasn’t a formation master himself he would have probably declined out of fear. If someone without proper knowledge entered this place they could find themselves trapped even if they were nascent soul masters.

“Good, lead the way.”

‘It shouldn’t be a problem but I’m not sure that they want me here. Are they part of this new upstart faction and are testing me?’

There was a possibility of his getting attacked or poisoned after arriving at his destination. His spiritual sense was spreading everywhere but even he was having trouble getting through all the various defensive formations. It seemed that the demonic cultivators were a notch above the orthodox ones when it came to formations.

‘Well then, what do you have in store for me here…’

Finally, he strode toward his destination, with some luck he could get his information and remove himself from the city…

A note from Kuropon

Thank you for reading!

Don't forget to follow, favorite, rate.

Donate | Discord |

Chapter 521

‘They really are overdoing it with the women here… Is this a dual cultivation sect or something?’

Zhang Dong had arrived at the large pagoda tower that was much larger on the inside. There he could see various young and old cultivators running around. The number of female figures was overshadowing the male ones. It also seemed that most of the people in higher places were men of advanced ages.

‘Or are they just taking me to a place filled with women…’

Within a few moments of floating after the young man, he was led to a strange chamber. It was filled with comfy beds and the atmosphere was very flowery. He expected to see more women but besides one old lady and the young man that brought him there, it was empty.

“Is this the person?”

“Greeting great demon, I’m afraid that I’m not Elder Tong but he will be here soon, why don’t you relax and take in the glorious sights instead?”

“The, sights?”

He wasn’t sure what the old woman was talking about but the young man closed the door instead of entering the room. Was this finally the trap that they were planning to spring after getting him here? There were several illusory formations that were at a surprisingly high level but not something that he wouldn’t be able to figure out.

Even now he felt that he was in control of the situation. Without being sure that they were trying to attack him it wouldn’t be wise to lash out. For the time being everyone was bowing and being cordial. Even now the old lady was inviting him for some kind of show.

“Yes my lord, this is a very special chamber all of your deepest desires can be fulfilled here. Please don’t worry about damaging the spirit constructs.”

“Spirit constructs?”

Without elaborating further the old woman’s silhouette started becoming blurry. Her voice started to be distant and the whole place became a haze. At least that’s what a normal person would be able to distinguish if they only used their normal five senses. Zhang Dong could clearly see the old lady leaving the room even when being clouded within the illusions.

‘Hm… are they trying to stall me in an illusion or something?’

The area started turning into some kind of landscape, in a moment the entire place got bright. When looking up he could see the blue sky forming along with a few clouds and bright warm sun. This was quite the powerful illusion as all the sensations were there. The feeling of the hot sun on his face and the gentle wind blowing against his long white hair.

When looking down to the ground he spotted a sandy beach with a whole sea behind it. The palm trees were swishing around and even a few coconuts fell down as some kind of exotic island was formed.

‘Is this image coming from my mind…’

After the formation was initiated he felt that some kind of spell took effect. It connected with his mind and took something out. The process wasn’t dangerous and no critical information was stolen. It was as if the formation was trying to extract something from his mind but that’s all it could do. It wasn’t powerful enough to actually perform any mind control on someone of his caliber.

‘Wait… was that a laugh?’

The longer the illusion lasted the more details were added, soon he started hearing some kind of cute chuckle. When he turned towards the noise his eyes were greeted by quite the spectacle. A large number of curvy ladies in swimsuits were slowly jogging toward him. Their shapely chests continued to bounce in various directions as they made their way toward him.

‘Is this that kind of formation? Maybe I do need to examine it a bit further, I’m not in that much of a rush…’

There were ten women coming his way. Their swimsuits varied in shapes and sizes but each one was barely containing those curvaceous shapes. It was a miracle that nothing slipped out with all the gyrating and shaking action that the ladies were performing. Their faces contained pure joy and they were cleary waving towards him while boncing up and down.

‘I certainly do have a type… or did being with Liena affect it…’

There were a few characteristics that these ladies shared with each other. All of them had a darker skin tone that varied slightly. Along with the caramel skin they also had a lighter hair color. It ranged from light pink all the way to pure white, their eye color was also most of the blue or green variety. Then there were of course the large bouncy chests that made it hard not to stare.

‘So this is what that woman meant by spirit construct.’

While these ladies looked real, they were nothing more than figments of his imagination. He had never left the room that he entered. With his enhanced eyes he could clearly tell that these were just clumps of Qi that simulated real humans. The formation read his mind to create partners that would suit his tastes and they were quite life-like.

“These do feel like the real thing…’

Zhang Dong reached out with his hand after the women finally arrived. His hand didn’t move to any of the bouncy parts, instead, he just lifted a big of those white locks. The texture was quite similar but it could not fool someone with enhanced senses like him.

“Spin around?”

An order was given and the girl started twirling around in one spot without getting dizzy. It seemed that they were able to perform simple commands but would not stop without another one. The clump of Qi that looked like beauty just continued to twirl and only stopped when he called out once again.

“That’s enough, stop… Gramps would love this…”

It would have been nice to visit a place like this before he created a family. Even though these weren’t real people it felt strange. Then there was also the situation he was in. This was a demonic sect and someone could be watching.

“A shame… they even started hula dancing and there is a tiki bar…”

Some new girls appeared, they were wearing leaf skirts and flower necklaces. They started dancing around to something that resembled Hawaiian music. The formation was trying to get to his memories and it was surprisingly able to pull out things from his original life.

‘This formation is dangerous, it lowers the person’s mind blocks by serving them erotic fantasies. Does this sect pull out information from people this way?’

He had to admit that this was one way to gather information from people. Most of what the formation pulled out was something he allowed to be taken. Nothing to his real identity had been unearthed yet. However the more he looked at the bouncy women and the more they tried hugging him, the harder this became. It was clear that this was the intended effect, lower the target's defenses and take from them.

‘The longer I stay here, the harder it will be to keep my mind protected…’

The girls that were here were hard not to look at. It was the perfect harem of maidens that most men would not be able to resist. Yet he needed to see the bigger picture, they were keeping him here for a reason. Perhaps his cover was actually blown and Wang Long was speeding to this location to attack him. There was no time to indulge with the busty babes, he needed to cut this illusion down.

“Enough, I have not come for this! My patience is at an end…”

Thus he turned back into the fearsome cultivator uncle that people here should be afraid off. With a spike in his cultivation, he slashed out with his finger. A gash in this fake world appeared that started spreading in all directions. The women, the island and everything around it turned white before disappearing. In just a second he was back in the same room with no one there.

“Come out, I know you are there.”

He looked towards the wall where normally no opening could be seen. It was another illusion, behind it was the old woman that greeted him. After the fake island appeared this person started meditating. She was probably responsible for keeping this place going. She might also have been forwarding information to the person in charge.

“S-senior, this…”

“Stop wasting my time, I have not come here to be entertained, why are you making me wait? Is there a reason for it? … “

“P-please I was just following orders…”

“So, your Patriarch intends to go against me, is that it?”

“Lord, that’s n-not…”

“Silence, I had enough of you, either bring out that Tong fellow or…”

His act had to continue, this was the last straw that usually broke the camel's back. The person he was simulating would have been enraged. He had been withheld what he wanted for an hour now. Instead of being greeted by the Tong character he was given this world's version of porn. There was something not right here, either they were really trying to pull a fast one on him or there was another problem.

‘Why are they making me jump through all these hoops, just give me the information and I’d be gone…’

Zhang Dong didn’t understand why the other side was risking a fight between two nascent soul masters. Did he masquerading as a middle-stage realm master give the other person enough reason to make an attack? Normally they would be skeptical, it wouldn’t be strange for someone to hide their full potential. Thus he was weary now, in his hand a black blade with an evil aura appeared.

“W-what?”

“Do you think I was born yesterday? You won’t be able to fool this… uh…”

The old woman staggered back while he raised his sword. He was still trying to intimidate his way out of everything but there was a problem. There was still no name to associate with his new persona as he had been interrupted during his deliberation. Lei Yinglo's name was already well known as a demon hunter so he couldn’t use it.

“Fool this… this Hai Ding!”

He pointed his sword towards the shaking old woman while finally coming up with a new name on short notice. Only after blurting it out did he realize just how silly it was. From Lei Yinglo to Hai Ding. It was truly a masterpiece of stupidity that he had to go with now as more people started appearing and trying to appease his anger.

“Lord Hai Ding, please the Patriarch was just trying to …”
‘I guess it’s fine…’

“Trying what? You can’t fool me, you were trying to affect my memories and squeeze information out of this Hai Ding, either get Tong here or receive this blade!”

His cultivation expanded causing the various protective formations to be activated. He was in enemy territory but he did not feel anyone that could threaten him in battle. Perhaps after some roughhousing, he would get the info that he desired…

A note from Kuropon

Thank you for reading!

Don't forget to follow, favorite, rate.

Donate | Discord |

Chapter 522

“What is the meaning of this?”

“That’s what I’d like to ask, Immolation Demon, what are you hiding? Is there a problem?”

“Problem? No there is none my friend, my people will take care of it, let us continue discussing our business.”

The man called the Immolation Demon spoke up while shooting an angry glance at a person that was hiding. The man was wearing a dark crimson robe, and most of his body was covered up along with his face. If a person examined what was under that hood they would jolt in horror. The man’s face was covered in bandages but they did a poor job at hiding the many burn marks.

Just a moment ago everyone in this secret room noticed that the entire tower was shaking. It didn’t take long but it was clear that whoever performed this task wasn’t simple. Immolation Demon was in the middle of making a deal with another master and getting allies in the demonic island was hard to come by.

He had been working to gain the trust of a certain group for quite some time but if another nascent soul master started going wild, it would seem that he lured the other party into a trap. Opposite him were two masters that even he would have trouble battling. They knew this and were taking a risk of coming here to his sect. The thin trust that was built over many years could crumble in a second.

‘What is that Tong doing? … did he make a mistake with the pleasure formation?’

“You have been acting strange since a while ago…”

“Stop joking Venom Demon, let's go back to discussing the event, you both know that we can’t trust the Chaotic Demon.”

“Aye, that’s true. The bastard appeared out of nowhere and started trouble with the devil council, that he would be able to conquer them in such a short time is baffling…”

An old man in a green robe and mist surrounding his face replied while nodding. He and the master of this sect were sitting around a large round table with a third not far away.

“I agree, we need to watch our backs if we expect to survive. The strange creatures that have attacked the mainland are also suspicious, perhaps the Chaotic Demon knows something about this?”

The third person was just as old as all of the people here. His robe was pitch black and his old fingers were of the same color. Due to his skin having this obsidian coloring it was hard to make out the facial features.

“Shadow Demon brings up a good point, could this have been some kind of organized attack? Perhaps we are on the cusp of a great shift…”

“Perhaps but we still need to see if that’s a bad thing or not…”

The old men nodded while the conversation continued. On the outside, a rather panic-stricken Elder Tong had rushed into the room where the strange large chinned cultivator had appeared. The plan was to let him enjoy a nice illusion while the Patriarch and the other esteemed guests exchanged pleasantries.

There were several reasons why he couldn’t rush to this man when he was in the restaurant. At that very moment, he was helping the Patriarch generate a nice atmosphere. His specialty was spewing compliments and defusing the situation. He was a schemer as everyone else but he was in the minority that had survived.

Tong made a mistake, he underestimated the power of this person. After bringing him to the sect he expected the nascent soul master to show some respect and just wait a few hours. The world of illusions was a costly artifact that was quite popular with the old perverted demonic cultivators.

Due to side-effects from cultivating by dual cultivation or by blood crystals, they tended to be more ‘active’ than their orthodox counterparts. Now the formation was forcefully closed and even damaged, it was a complex structure that would take many weeks to repair.

…

“So, you are Tong? Why did you make me wait so long? Did you expect me to use that thing for pleasure?”

“I… I apologize my lord but uh…”

‘This guy is really panicking, must be hard to talk with all that pressure too.’

Zhang Dong was forced to show a bit of his hand by forcing the people here down to their knees. After taking care of the perverted formation and the granny that was running it, this man quickly appeared. It was as if he was waiting outside just to try to stall some more time. It was clear that they really didn’t want him to be here and after causing a small scene he knew why.

‘There are three people at around the same level in the same room.’

After injecting some of his spiritual energy into the formation system he was finally able to scan the entire area. In a hidden room that was behind all sorts of illusory and barrier formations, there were three nascent soul masters. They were probably the reason why they made him wait.

‘They are talking about some interesting things though, thanks Bob.’

‘Connection with the formation established, transferring audio to the user.’

His Ai program was able to infest the formation like a virus and connect to the secret room. While the sound was quite bad he could hear what the three were talking about.

‘There is some kind of gathering of the strongest demonic cultivators in about two weeks, this doesn’t look good.’

The gist of it was that the three were trying to form an alliance of convenience. If this get-together turned out to be some elaborate trap they would try to escape together. With three nascent soul masters working together they could boost each other's speed and escape. Perhaps using teleportation treasures was also possible.

‘Are they luring them into a trap or is this about something else, like the fishy invaders?’

One possibility was that it was Wang Long and he was attempting to gather spirit points by murdering all the strongest people at once. The Chaotic demon that he suspected Wang Long to be had only erased a few top masters before settling down in the middle of the island. Then word had died down before this decree was established.

The other possibility was that he was forming an army. Perhaps instead of murdering everyone to get points, he decided to use them in other ways. Was it possible to unite all the demonic cultivators under one flag? Normally it wouldn’t be possible but knowing that this world was a game, there had to be a way for the hero of the story to do it.

While Zhang Dong had chosen to join the ‘good’ side there should be a possibility to join the ‘evil’ faction. If this was all a game, then the person could probably win it in various ways. The last part was probably getting into the immortal stage, there was nothing holding them back from getting there as a murdering maniac that was a demonic cultivator.

‘I don’t like this, will I have to go there and see it for myself?’

This wasn’t how he thought Wang Long would do things. Normally he expected everyone that could be used as spirit points to be eradicated instantly. After turning the place into a desolate land Wang Long would continue harvesting points to get stronger but do it himself. Could he actually be forming a faction after seeing his sect’s power and unity?

‘He previously evaded the faction part of the system, he didn’t really integrate it with his old sect or use it to make them stronger…’

“Silence, I will have no excuses, just answer my question and do it now.”

While listening to the four old demon cultivators discuss things he was getting all the information that he wanted. Now the only piece missing was to get a confirmation of the looks. Perhaps his opponent would still be overconfident and use his old appearance.

Finally, he produced a representation of Wang Long as he remembered it. The projection had the young man placed in various robes so that this old fart had more angles and variations to look at.

“Is this the man that goes by Chaotic Demon or Demon of Chaos?”

“This… is truly the new master of the devil council but he looks slightly different…”

“Great, now just tell me if this Chaotic demon or devil is planning anything, where does he usually stay? Is it at the center of the island, what’s the name of that city… ah right, Crimson Slaughter City…”

“Yes, that’s the capital’s name, the Chaotic Demon is presumed to reside there along with his concubines…”

After a quick back and forth exchange with the man he had the basic information that he required. Just as before the man was thinking about his lower area too much. After conquering the island he started demanding all the young beauties. Apparently, the switch to dual cultivation was something that he highly appreciated.

‘I guess people can’t change that fast… can you earn spirit points through dual cultivation though?’

‘Negative.’

Bob answered the quarry quickly, it was just a method of regular cultivation. He could still get stronger but it wouldn’t add to the spirit point pool. Yet there was a possibility of another section of the system opening up. He had gotten together with his wife quite fast and didn’t even consider performing those acts to further his power. The method had a clear downside of draining one of the participants of their energy.

“Good, that’s enough, show me to the exit I have heard enough.”

“Enough, Senior Hai Ding?”

The man was clearly confused as what Zhang Dong had asked him were just the usual rumors that everyone knew. He couldn’t complain though, if this was the end of the whole confrontation then he would keep his life. Tong had been panicking for the whole span of the conversation, either he would get killed by the sect leader or by this man if something happened.

‘For once my disguise worked. I bet if In tried impersonating a lesser elder I’d get forced to do some errands.’

It was time to leave, the other three were still prattling on but they weren’t saying anything important. At this stage, they were just discussing how much they should pay each other if something comes up. The one that caused a scene would need to fork up some blood stones if the other two had to rescue them.

“Here is the exit, are you sure you don’t wish to wait join some of our junior sisters for some tea?”

“No, it’s fine…”

‘Whew, I’m ou…’

“Immolation Demon, come out!”

‘What is it now…’

The moment he stepped out through the door he noticed that someone was speeding their way. They were of the nascent master variety and they also had some friends with them…

Chapter 523

“If you don’t come out within a minute, don’t blame me for what will happen!”

“Yeah, come out already, how dare you make us wait?”

‘Who are these people…’

Zhang Dong was right outside the giant pagoda and almost free from his recognizance mission. What he just needed to do now was to find a hidden spot and change his appearance again. Then he could start mapping out the island with his system to prepare the invasion plans. Perhaps even taking some time to look at the sea.

‘Doesn’t matter, their fight seems to be with the sect leader and not with me.’

In the sky, there were multiple nascent soul masters and also a large group of core formation cultivators. There were five nascent soul demonic cultivators, with about twenty core formation experts for each of them. The weaker warriors were spreading out in all directions to prepare some kind of formation.

‘Are they trying to set up a trapping formation so that people won’t leave?’

Before leaving Zhang Dong noticed something. All these people were wearing similar dark robes with a peculiar symbol on the back. It was not a Mandarin character as everyone else used, it was something that he remembered from his old life.

It looked like many arrows moving out from a circle in which a skull resided. This was something that he remembered seeing when playing video games before he appeared in this world. It was something that only someone from the same world would probably be aware of.

‘So they are Wang Long’s new lackeys? Did he perhaps know that I came here or is there another reason? Should I just leave or …’

Zhang Dong didn’t feel that he was in danger yet. When he realized that people were approaching he hid his power even more. To the people floating in the sky, he wouldn’t appear as much more than a core formation expert. He was interested in the reason these people were here. If they were on orders from Wang Long then perhaps this would be a chance to see how he acted as a leader.

‘They do seem rather evil, what’s with all those cocky grins?’

Just as always the demonic cultivators were composed of mostly old men. The five looked like zombies that just crawled out of the grave with how pale their skin was. There was also some kind of strange poisonous aura floating around them.

“What’s the meaning of this? You dare?”

A rather angry-looking voice burst forth from the large pagoda he was under. The top blew the lid as a burst of flaming energy shot up into the sky. From within a single man emerged that was covered in bandages and a robe. With his enhanced senses he could tell that his frame was covered in third-degree burns.

‘Hm… due to some demonic arts an evil cultivator could lose part of their natural healing capabilities. Is this man unable to heal these burns without leaving behind scarring or is it perpetual damage received from the flames he is surrounding himself with?’

Huo Qiang’s flame arts were purer than what he was seeing here. The man that looked like a burn victim probably had a very shaky understanding of the Dao of flames. It wouldn’t be strange if he had forced himself into this realm while suffering through a lot of pain.

‘I guess power is more important than living in pain…’

“Immolation Demon, what’s with that look? Do you know who you are speaking to? Have you forgotten who rules these lands now”

“You…”

Zhang Dong could see the fire cultivator move his head down and begrudgingly clasp his hands together to greet this person. He only did the act after seeing the large logo on the other man’s robe. It seemed that the two had history together, their power levels were close to each other.

‘Old rivals perhaps? Did the other guy grow a spine after joining Wang Long’s side?’

This wasn’t anything new, whenever someone received a strong backer in this world they would see themselves as a superior being. They could shield themselves behind the person or faction that was now protecting them. If someone badmouthed them it would be as if they are badmouthing the backers instead.

“I see that you understand your place, good.”

“Why are you here? Have you come to gloat?”

“You know me well, but watch that tongue of yours! I’m on direct orders from the Demon King!”

“Demon King?”

“Yes, the magnificent Chaos Demon has decided to become the king, the official announcement will come in a few weeks so don't babble it out but I have come for a different reason, the lord demands an offering.”

“An offering?”

“Yes, gather all of your finest women, they will be presented for the lord as his concubines!”

“Concubines?”

‘I see that guy is up to no good as always…’

Wang Long’s overblown libido was known before he even became a demonic cultivator. Yet he was more restrained in the past, most of the time he visited places and picked out a few women to come along with him. It was the same when he appeared in Spirit Spring City to get Liena.

“I will prepare the women, you can leave now…”

“Not so fast, did you think that this is the only reason I came here?”

“What do you mean?”

“Come out, we know you are there, Venom Demon, Shadow Demon!”

‘Oh? Are they in for it?’

This didn’t seem to be only about the women, there were far too many cultivators here for a simple errand. Almost everyone from the nascent soul masters was around the middle stage, they were each other's equals. However, there was one man that was above them all, a late stage demonic cultivator and he was on Wang Long’s side.

‘Will those two just come out in peace or try to flee instead?’

He wasn’t sure what this was all about, perhaps the other side was seeing this as a chance to take out old rivals. The secret get-together was suspicious but it didn’t have to mean anything. Old masters constantly made deals with each other and the three were just making a haphazard truce to help each other.

‘They might even think that that burned guy ratted them out… this could turn into a big brawl…’

It didn’t look that well for the three demons but also the whole sect wasn’t safe. The advantage was seemingly on the side of the new group but this was still the territory of the Onyx Moon Sect. There were various protective formations everywhere that could equal out the playing field against the higher realm cultivator.

“Hey, you there, how dare you! Lower your head this instant!”

‘Uh?’

There arose a small problem, as he was still in his overbearing evil cultivator persona he just stayed there with his face pointed towards the sky. This was not something a junior member of the sect would be allowed to do. Everyone else from the sect had their head lowered and just listened as the elders talked.

“Are you deaf? How dare a lowly…”
‘Oh boy…’

He kind of tuned out what this person was saying while weighing his options. It didn’t look like anyone posed a threat to him so using valuable spirit points to teleport back wasn’t necessary. By the laws that governed this place, he was in the right to teach these people a lesson. Even though they were part of a powerful upstart sect, their leader was not here to punish him.

‘Would Wang Long appear if I defeated some of his people? Weakening his side before the invasion wouldn’t be such a bad idea…’

There were five nascent soul masters, one of them was a bit stronger than the rest but not really a problem. If no other reinforcements came then he could easily deal with them.

“Impertinent insect.”

“Wha…”

The core formation member of this group groaned as he felt a massive amount of pressure collapsing on him. Instantly he was pushed down to the floor, his body began giving out crunching sounds as his bones began to snap. Zhang Dong showed no remorse for this act as he was clearly a murderous individual. There was an aura of death around him, some residual energy from the souls of people he killed was still lingering. They had died with indignation and only worsened this man’s karma in the process.

“What are you doing?”

“What does it look like to you? I’m squishing a bug.”

He looked towards the man that was floating in the sky while performing his attack. Even though the nascent soul master above attempted to suppress it with his own aura, he was unable to. The other two that were hiding in the pagoda were on their way out and also noticed this display of power. His aura was still suppressed making him seem as an early stage practitioner.

“You dare? Immolation Demon, is this one part of your sect? Are you actually gathering forces to go against the Demon King?”

“What are you talking about? This was never about this and you know it, I don’t know that person, he just showed up here…”

“You really think I’d believe that?”

The loudmouth started arguing with the Immolation Demon while the real toughest member remained silent. This was the usual tactic of hidden experts, letting someone take the attention off them to test potential threats. This would put them in a safe position to react if an opponent turned out to be strong.

Of course, Zhang Dong was aware of this as his attention wasn’t on the shouting match. Instead, he focused on the formation that the core formation experts were trying to create. It wouldn’t last long against an assault but it would probably be enough to stop a nascent soul master for a moment and give the other ones time to chase.

“Hey, where do you think you are going?”

To everyone’s surprise, the unknown demonic cultivator that Zhang Dong was masquerading as started walking. He ignored any callouts while making his way toward one of the core formation cultivators that was setting up the formation. It seemed that he was trying to make a run for it so one of the nascent soul masters with the poisonous air around them bolted towards him.

“You shall not escape?”

“Escape? I think you misunderstand…”

The core formation cultivator was quickly knocked out on the spot by a fling of his finger. The same finger was used to interact with a focal point of this formation not to dissolve it, but to make it a lot stronger.

“I’m not the one stuck here with you, you are the ones stuck here with me!”

He shouted while jamming his palm into the unsuspecting nascent soul elder’s chest that was flying towards him with ill intent. The man’s ribs shattered in an instant as he flew back only to collide with the improved formation. One of the enemies was down but there were at least four more that he had to contend with…

Chapter 524

The old nascent soul demon could feel life leaving his body just after receiving one hit. His ribcage was dented inwardly with a palmprint burned over his chest. He instantly could feel strange energy invading his body and it was something that he was familiar with. Yet it was too late for him to call out and warn his allies as his body was siphoned towards his attacker without him being able to resist.

“What are you doing! Stop, do you intend to go against the Demon King?”

“The Demon King? Why would I submit to someone I have never met? Only the strong survive and this king of yours has not proven himself to be stronger than me.”

Zhang Dong replied while his fingers clung to one of the demonic cultivator’s necks. While exposing his divine energies into the surroundings would give his identity away, he still could use it without being found out. If he directly injected them into his opponent's body they would be unable to tell what was happening.

Both the evil energies that these demonic cultivators used and the holy Qi Zhang Dong produced countered each other. If this was a game then both of them would do double the usual damage to each other. In a clash of these powers, the person with the more concentrated Qi would win. The clash would produce a chaotic reaction inside one's body and cause immense amounts of damage if not quickly taken care of.

“W-what is happening to him?”

“Be careful, that person isn’t simple!”

The four men that worked for the new Demon King stopped in their tracks as one of their allies started to act strange. His body started to contort in strange ways as if there was something crushing it from the outside. In a matter of moments, it crumbled revealing his nascent divinity that was unable to flee. The person that was holding him by the neck instantly absorbed this soul without leaving anything behind.

‘Oh… so I even get a list?’

Dao:

|

Percentage gained

Poison

|

8%

Shadow

|

5%

Wind

|

1%

After receiving the tip from Bob he decided to absorb the evil cultivator’s nascent divinity. He was not very versed in Poison or the Dao of Darkness so the gain was obviously higher. When it came to wind he had a higher amount of understanding and probably why he received the least.

‘I wonder if I can infinitely absorb nascent souls to receive Dao boosts? It would make more sense if the person needed to have an understanding of it that I’m not already clued in…’

The Dao was in short the origin of all things. It was a path that the Daoists followed and tried to understand to its fullest. The Daos could be divided into major and minor ones and go even beyond that. Only after understanding these underlying principles of the universe could the cultivator progress further.

At least that was how it was supposed to be. After visiting the old secret ground where his predecessor lived he was made aware of another truth. Normally he would already be able to progress into a higher realm above the nascent soul level. This realm only required the mastery of one Dao, even a lesser one should be enough. He on the other hand already knew three great ones, Holy, Lightning, and now Gravity.

‘It seems that the immortal realm requires people to comprehend multiple Dao’s at once but how many do I need to perfect?’

While he was absorbing the man’s nascent soul he could see his life flash through his eyes. It was as if he relieved some of his most vivid memories in a fraction of a second before the man perished. It was as if some of his techniques had been imprinted into his own soul now.

The Dao of the Shadow was one of the great ones that went directly up against his Holy Dao. Both of those below the Dao of Light and Dao of Darkness were origin-grade paths. Perhaps what he needed to do was to complete several greater paths to gain an understanding of one of the grander origins of this world, then the way towards the next realm would be unlocked.

‘But before I worry about that I need to take care of these chuckleheads…’

“It won’t open!”

“Immolation Demon, are you really going against the Demon King? Do you think you can get away with this!”

“I’ve told you that I don’t know that man! How about you shut up before he kills us all?”

It was funny to see the group of nascent soul masters arguing with each other. This might have not seemed much different than an argument between regular sects but it was. Even now he could see all of these demonic cultivators spreading to the sides, no one from them trusted each other.

Even the ones that were presumably from one faction were already thinking about the most probable way to survive. After seeing how easily he reduced one of them to nothing they were warry. Normally they would attack him with the number advantage yet due to the other three masters here they were unsure of what to do.

‘They think that the mummy guy is with me, so it would be four against four in their eyes… I just need to give them a little push.’

He smiled as he didn’t have a problem taking out these mass murderers. All of them had gained their power by walking on the corpses of others. This whole island would probably be better off if they were gone and then taken under the wing of his own faction. Zhang Dong had the resources for it and was willing to take responsibility for affecting the lives of the people here.

If he just killed the leader and left nothing would really change, just another bloody battle for the leader position would take place and more people would die. The only way to stop this spiral of avarice was to take charge. It would probably take many years to change how these people thought but with time he could see them moving on.

“Now Immolation Demon, Venom Demon, Shadow Demon. All of you strike them down with me, I’ll take care of their strongest!”

“You… I knew you were planning something, don’t think you’ll be able to leave this place alive!”

“What?”

The three old men that had previously spent some time talking out a pact of non-aggression were stunned. They looked as the strange square-chinned man charged toward one of the people that belonged to the new Demon King faction, the Chaos Sect. The speed was astonishing, his strength was on another level as they realized that he was hiding it.

The collision between him and the late stage demonic cultivator caused a massive explosion and was the beginning of the end for them. They all found themselves being attacked by the other group of nascent soul masters. Even the core formation experts were pelting them with long-ranged techniques with a lot of poison.

Zhang Dong was not in a hurry, after confronting the late stage cultivator he allowed his opponent some time. If he was going to go against high-level demonic beings on this island then getting some hands-on experience was paramount. The ones that he faced as his demon hunter persona were mostly at the core formation level of power.

The man shrouded himself in some kind of veil of toxicity. Poison techniques and ones containing venom were very widespread among these demonic beings. For more orthodox cultivators this would have already been a tough barrier to get through. All the poison was one of the biggest reasons why demonic cultivators were victorious against their orthodox counterparts. Even if they lost their opponent could still succumb to the slow-working poison and die later.

“H-how!”

“Hmph!”

He swatted away a mass of poisonous needles that gave out a pungent smell. They could not get through his Qi barrier and thanks to his holy Dao even if he inhaled the fumes they would not be lethal. It was the usual way of the evil cultivator, if a person didn’t directly get infected by the poison then make them ingest it in another way.

Then if those methods failed he also noticed that his shield of spiritual energy was getting corrupted. It seemed that the dao of poison was quite strong, it would even corrode through shields made of pure spiritual energy. Only if he added something like holy energy that could repel them, it would quickly disperse and open him up for an attack.

‘We might have to create some divine treasures to reinforce everyone's spiritual energy or use the fortress as a veil against it.’

While he exchanged various blows he continued to ponder countermeasures against these people. There was even enough time to look at the others, the Immolation Demon was quite interesting. His techniques produced a somewhat different flame, he could feel that some kind of demonic energy was mixed in that would probably corrode anything that it touched.

‘Corrosion… poison… venom… curses… this won’t be that fun for the others…’

These attacks wouldn’t be hard for him to counter but there weren’t that many people able to use divine arts in his sect. Perhaps it was time to bring in some outside help for the next attack. He recalled a certain sect that he had previously helped and they still owed him big time.

‘Divine Fist Sect, was it? They should have enough people to act as backup against these guys.’

It was the sect that he helped before being blasted off to the other world. His sacrifice cost him five years of his family life. From what he knew they had managed to survive the demi-human menace and were one of the small number of sects that didn’t suffer any losses yet. They would be the perfect soldiers to aid him in the coming battle. He didn’t want to involve others but the more time Wang Long was given the worse the situation would become.

“Okay, I’ve seen enough…”

“Huh?”

The man he was fighting with was pressing forward and delivered a devastating hit that seemingly destroyed his spirit barrier. Yet instead of being able to sink the mass of poisonous needles into Zhang Dong’s flesh, his vision began splitting. It took a moment for him to realize that a black longsword appeared to slash him in two equal halves. Quickly he tried activating his escape measure yet before he could his soul started being siphoned away.

Everyone else watched in horror as the strongest member of their group had been taken out in one hit. The difference in power between Zhang Dong and a late stage nascent soul master was just that big. He could easily take them out with a single sword strike and the ones that were left here wouldn’t be different.

“Well then, let us finish this encounter, shall we?”

Chapter 525

Dao:

|

Percentage gained

Poison

|

0.4%

Devouring

|

4%

Curse

|

2%

“And then there were three…”

Zhang Dong looked at the list of Daos that he received after absorbing the last opponent. They didn’t put up much of a battle as he was just too fast for them to react to. All of them fall to his blade and quickly had their nascent divinities absorbed into his seed.

It wasn’t a feeling he was very comfortable with, even though the people he was devouring were evil their lives still flashed before his eyes as their souls dissipated and turned into his cultivation. In reality, it was somewhat taxing on his psyche and he didn’t really want to continue absorbing the souls of these three anymore.

“I’ll give you two choices, you can live as slaves or die here.”

They were still evil beings with no remorse. If he let them be they would probably stand against his people or bring disaster to the less fortunate. It wasn’t hard for demonic cultivators to hide in some cave for a couple of years until everything was over. Then they would just go back to their murderous ways and all the damage they caused would be on his conscience. He had the option to act now and felt that it was his duty to take care of such people.

“Slave?”

“Yes, I’m sure you heard of soul contracts? Submit your souls to me, that’s the only way for me to trust you.”

As always the souls were the key to everything. If he managed to get them to submit willingly then they would be unable to against his will. After the contract of submissiveness was completed he would be able to erase their life with just a thought. However, it didn’t look that most of the participants were willing. The barrier that he hijacked was also running out of juice so two of them began to flee.

“Screw you Immolation Demon, you’re responsible for this! Don’t think you’ll be able to get away.”

There was a misunderstanding between the two masters and the Onyx Moon sect owner. They were convinced that this was some kind of plan and that Zhang Dong was part of it. They would rather take the chance and attempt an escape than to be turned into soul slaves.

One of the people shrouded himself in a bunch of dark clouds that looked like shadows while the other one produced a poisonous fog. Both of them turned around and headed in different directions. It wasn’t a bad tactic, one of them had a better chance of getting away while the other was being chased.

However, the difference between them was just far too large. Zhang Dong could clearly tell that the smoke screens that they produced were just a distraction. Inside were puppets with a tiny soul fragment to keep them similar to the main body. The real masters on the other hand were trying to shroud themselves in various ways while slowly moving toward different locations.

“It won’t work…”

He called out while pointing out with both hands. His fingers aimed for each nascent soul master and soon a ray of light shot out. This time he added his heavenly lightning energy for additional power and speed. The two rays collided with their targets which revealed their hiding spots. The moment they were injured the fakes started to fade away.

“I gave you a way out, you can only blame yourselves…”

His body blurred and the first shadowy figure’s head flew up into the air. One strike was enough for him to defeat a middle stage nascent soul master. The other one attempted to escape but as his friend, he lost his head soon after. Now only the Patriarch of the presiding sect remained. He didn’t move as he saw the bigger picture, there was no way of his surviving if he didn’t surrender.

“I… I surrender…”

Zhang Dong nodded while also siphoning away the next two nascent soul divinities. As long as he was this close there was no chance of a soul getting away. While he didn’t absorb their power instantly he stored them away for later use. Devouring souls was still something he needed to get used to.

“Good, you made a wise choice.”

Without waiting for long he flew towards the man wrapped in bandages. For the technique to work the man would need to lower his defenses yet there was something fishy. Zhang Dong wasn’t a fool and quickly noticed that an attack was coming. Suddenly from various directions, core formation experts appeared. They started chanting loudly while their leader backed away while performing some strange hand signs.

“You fool, do you really think I would just surrender my life to you!”

“Well, no not really…”

In the spot where Zhang Dong was floating a giant orb of flames appeared. It expanded to something that looked like a miniature black sun. Everything in the vicinity started to turn to ashes. The place had been abandoned by the regular citizens so only the buildings suffered.
“That’s what you get for… huh?”

“Why are you surprised? You’ve already seen what I could do, did you think I wouldn’t notice such an obvious trap formation under me?”

“But you were inside…”

“Oh, was I?”

All of them saw Zhang Dong burning up inside the mass of flames. This was just a simple replacement technique. The thing that went up in flames was just a temporary clump of Qi energy that had the outline of his body. He just quickly brought himself into a safe location while the others were focusing on the dummy.

“Your friends could fashion such puppets, so can I.”

This was one of the new uses of his absorbed Daos. The demonic cultivators were extremely good at escaping from a life-and-death situation. They could produce clones that resembled them and were somewhat intelligent. With a little blood and occult magic that was somewhat similar to the magic from the other world, it was all possible.

“No… I am the Demon of Immolation, you shall burn!”

“So you’ve going to resist until the end… I thought you demonic cultivators were supposed to be cowardly…”

This was a surprise to him. Perhaps the evil cultivators on the island were braver than the ones with whom he interacted on the mainland. Those people would certainly quickly try to backpedal and run whenever there was any trouble. These on the other hand were more combative.

‘Perhaps at this level, their minds can’t fathom being suppressed this much?’

He had also not revealed all of his trump cards. What he was using now was mostly his body refining prowess. It was just a combination of force and speed without using his Qi. It wasn’t very flashy and perhaps gave these people the idea that they had a chance.

“You? Who are yo…”

The man found himself with a sword going for his head. Even though his entire body was surrounded by a wall of flames it was of no use. He had clearly realized that there was something wrong with Zhang Dong’s actions but he would not be able to disclose the secret to anyone. Everyone below the nascent soul level was easily knocked out just by his overbearing aura, it was as if they were all waiting to be judged.

‘This isn’t good, I hoped to at least get one of these guys on my side, they could act as a spy and report to me…’

The three nascent divinities were still intact. The three demonic cultivators weren’t quite dead, they just lacked bodies to occupy. Even though he couldn’t bring them under his control earlier this didn’t mean that some information couldn’t be extracted. The nascent soul would slowly dissipate but there still was some time left.

Yet without a body to live in, they would die in the spawn of a few years. Their memories would deteriorate and most likely they would become a vengeful spirit. While information could be extracted now, their bodies were gone, and replacing them would be hard.

‘Now what should I do with them?’

After the fight, he had managed to keep the Chaos Sect’s core formation experts here. They would surely babble out what had happened here if they returned to their base. Yet he wasn’t sure if that was a problem, no one really knew who he was, and there were always strong hidden monsters on the loose.

‘Could Wang Long decide to hunt me down if they report?’

They would probably place him at the great circle level of power and thus he made a good target for spirit points. He did not know how many resources Wang Long needed, perhaps he would be unable to ignore a gift-wrapped bundle of points like him.

Fighting him one on one was something that he wanted. The more people he could exclude from this confrontation the better. Zhang Dong didn’t feel that he could lose but needed to include his sect in the plan as he was going against another faction.

His constant increase in power gave him the confidence in being able to win even against someone with a working system. This didn’t mean that he would be able to successfully lure the man out here. It was more likely that some of his goons would show up instead.

‘That wouldn’t be bad though… the more of his faction members I can take out the better…’

“Hey you there, Tong was it?”

“M-me?”

Zhang Dong looked towards the shaking cultivators and singled one out. It was the man that the grandfather and granddaughter pointed him towards. The pair was now long gone, even before he got into the pagoda tower he could feel them sneaking out of the city.

“Yes you, as you can see, your leader is no more, thus I’ll be taking over for him.”

“Taking over?”

“Yes, guide me to the treasure room.”

“Treasure room?”

“Can you only echo what I am saying?”

“E-excuse me, great senior…”

“Does anyone have anything against me becoming the new sect leader? You can go ahead and speak out now if you wish?”

As expected, anyone that was left conscious didn’t dare say anything. All of them were convinced that if they even opened their mouths they would be dead and then devoured. While it didn’t happen often, sometimes the heads of the sect were killed. This either caused the sect to be destroyed or absorbed into the faction that killed the leader.

“Long live the new Patriarch!”

“Glad that you understand. Now, capture these Chaos Sect members, I’ll decide on what to do with them later.”

“Yes, Patriarch.”

Soon the core formation experts were being carried off into the dungeon while he was going towards the treasure room. To be on the safe side he needed to prepare various countermeasures, if Wang Long really appeared to avenge his people then he needed to be ready.

A note from Kuropon

Thank you for reading!

Don't forget to follow, favorite, rate.

Donate | Discord |

Chapter 526

“What do you mean they vanished? How could that many grand demons just disappear? Clear this issue out before the Demon King notices, we don’t know what he might do if he finds out…”

“I understand…”

Two nascent soul masters were whispering between each other while making sure that no one could hear them. Just a day ago some of their capable masters had vanished without a trace. There was a possibility that they had fled but it wasn’t very probable. After the new leader appeared he did something to all of them, even the thought of angering them brought immeasurable fear and pain.

“We will keep this a secret, nothing can go wrong before the inauguration celebration is over, now go…”

One of the men left after clasping his hands together while this old man slowly moved towards an area of this castle that he despised. Not so long ago an upstart appeared in these lands. He could not be stopped and old monsters continued to either be killed or recruited into the new faction he created. His name Demon on Chaos was created due to the incoherent way he acted, it was as if the man had totally lost his marbles due to some kind of failed cultivation attempt.

His might was very true and in just a month he had managed to conquer this island that belonged to the most ruthless people in the empire. In the middle of the island, there was a huge active volcano. Around it, the largest settlement that housed many grandmasters had survived for many millennia. Once divided now they all stood under one banner and the recruitment drive was moving forward.

The man had chosen a strange title for himself and was ordering everyone to show up for his coronation. This old man here that had lived for almost a thousand years knew the real reason behind it. Everyone that arrived would be forcefully integrated into the new sect. The reason wasn’t fully known to him but their new young leader had a certain disgust for the main empire. There was a large possibility that they would all be attacking the lands of the orthodox sects and the days of carnage were upon them.

‘In a way it's exhilarating…’

This old monster wasn’t even against participating in wanton slaughter. In his eyes, it would be a grand endeavor if they were able to conquer the whole empire. The biggest reason why no one had attempted it was due to hubris. The demonic grandmasters just couldn’t work with each other.

After attaining the nascent soul level most of them fractured off to create their own factions and rule their own cities. No one was willing to submit and even if they did, the other party just had a potential assassination threat under their roof now. Only when the patriarch attained a level that could be not denied did larger clans and sects arise and this was one of them.

“Old fart Ling, I reckon that everything is moving according to the schedule?”

“Yes, Pat… I mean, Demon King”

“Good, I really wouldn’t want to have to disciple and ugly bastard like you…”

“I see…”

The old man looked at the handsome man with jet black hair. He was sitting on a throne made from obsidian skulls. They all belonged to people that he had killed, the technique that he used somehow turned their bones pitch black. In his lap, there was a very beautiful woman that had her chest revealed and pressing into the young lord.

She was not the only one here, all the beauties from the cities were forcefully brought over. On a daily basis, he would go through them one by one. From time to time he would pick out permanent harem members while the others were discarded like half-eaten food that he was bored with.

The women were never the same after, they seem to lose part of their soul and become unresponsive even to their family members. It was some kind of dual cultivation method that drained them to the point of becoming lifeless husks. The ones that he fancied remained somewhat able but it was clear that they wouldn’t live long lives either.

“Don’t disappoint me, you know what happened to your predecessor.”

“I won’t my lord, your wish is my command.”

“Hah, look at your fear points go up, that’s how it's supposed to be, I should have ditched that old sect a long time ago!”

This old cultivator didn’t know what the young demon was talking about. From time to time he would mention things like involving numbers, stats, and achievement points. The old monsters that were subservient to him had no idea what to make of it so they just assumed he was crazy.

“What are you still doing here? Are you the type that likes to watch?”

His face remained unchained but he wanted to go over there and give the demon lord a smack. Yet when he did there was a strange feeling of dread washing over his body. It was as if any thoughts that went against the new demon king would be identified by something. This old man even tested it out and he got goosebumps or migraines each time.

“N-no… I’ll excuse myself…”

After seeing the blank expression on the woman’s face he turned around to walk away. He could only sigh at the fact that an old mater like him had been turned into an errand boy in the twilight years of his life. If he didn’t think there was a chance of the young man actually being able to conquer the empire he would have probably taken his own life already. The only thing keeping him together was the chance of seeing the death of the Long Clan before his life was over. If there was even a small chance of that happening, he was willing to sell his soul to this devil.

‘We can’t let anything happen or I’ll be dead before I see this Empire fall, this Wang Long is crazy but he might be crazy enough to kill that blasted Emperor.’

The old man smiled while leaving the large gaudy castle. As long as no word reached his ears Wang Long would not act. After conquering the demonic island he had become a lot lazier. What he needed to worry about was the deadline that was in a few weeks. A few deserters weren’t that much of a problem but they still had vanished. This needed to be checked and if they were found they would be offered to the new king.

…

“Is this all that you have?”

“Yes, Patriarch.”

“Stop calling me that, I’m not your leader.”

Zhang Dong, who was disguising himself under a new persona, gave out a sigh. At this moment he was going through the Immolation Demon’s library. He used the time he had to absorb all of the knowledge here, faction names, political deals, and secret undercover organizations became known to him.

‘These demonic cultivators should be stronger than the ones in the Empire if they put their problems aside…’

The old Patriarch was a cautious man and he had gathered a lot of information before his demise. There was a comprehensive list of all potential threats right here. All of the known weaknesses that could aid in defeating the various clan and sect masters were listed down. If he didn’t know better it would look that this demonic cultivator was trying to take over the demonic island.

‘Perhaps he was running an information guild, there were some strange letters mixed in that he didn’t dispose of yet.’

There was some insider information from the capital city. This city was built around an active volcano that actually produced some spiritual energy. There was probably a smaller spirit vein there that these evil cultivators were battling for. They could not come to an agreement so it was a huge area divided into something like city-states.

‘That is before Wang Long arrived… It’s as if this had been created for someone with the system to conquer it all. An everlasting stalemate and only a system holder would be able to tip the balance to one side…’

He didn’t really need to do anything besides touching the books with a finger to absorb all the knowledge. Yet this wasn’t even that useful as by absorbing the old sect master’s nascent soul he had already learned most of the important techniques by progressing his Dao.

‘If I had the time, it would probably be better to create a coup. Power gained through pure force is always built on a shaky foundation… I wouldn’t be surprised if all of them start running after he goes down…’

Without needing to think much he realized that even though Wang Long had gained a faction for himself, he was still alone. More help would have been offered to him from his old sect where he had a protective grandfather. Here, on the other hand, the other demonic cultivators would take the first chance to betray him.

‘If he is still alive then he must have bought something from the store against poison and curses, I won’t believe that they wouldn’t try to at least kill him a few times.’

From what he knew about the new demon king, not many people really liked him. He was a blank slate, a person with no background or backing. Would the old masters of this land just roll over and die? Would the people that invested in them not be angered by the new upstart?

‘It wouldn’t be strange if they offered him women with poison inside of their bodies. Using people as sacrifices and containers with curses isn’t that strange around these parts…’

There were many ways for a person to die in this world and the bedchamber wasn’t anything different. The new king was known to be a huge pervert, he had an unsatiated taste for the flesh of young women. Yet he was still alive so they had to have not been successful. Either Wang Long anticipated all the traps or used the system to take care of this problem.

‘He didn’t seem that smart, so using spirit points is more likely…’

This lessened the ways of taking care of his problem but didn’t change much. He had learned some Dao concerning poison but it was not something he was willing to use. His holy Dao would probably be the best way to counter any evil techniques. It was also probably the reason for Wang Long’s choice of changing cultivation methods. The evil energies were the bane of his holy Dao but it also went both ways.

‘That about does it…’

After getting all the information from the stacks of records and books he was ready to leave. He felt slightly bad about killing the leader of this sect but they were still his enemies. War was coming and there was one less nascent soul master to kill his people. These people had no love for their old leader though and would probably just be absorbed into another faction soon enough.

‘Maybe I should see that capital city, the diagrams that are here are fairly old…’

Yet as he was about to go towards the next destination he stopped, there was something strong coming here and it was coming from the sea…

A note from Kuropon

Thank you for reading!

Don't forget to follow, favorite, rate.

Donate/Patreon | Discord |

Chapter 527

‘This is…’

Zhang Dong looked at his map, there he could see a reddish tint that looked like fog. It was an indicator that something that didn’t belong to this Empire was coming. They were coming from the dead sea filled with monsters that he had to pass to get here. The water elements were out of order and when floating out to get a better look he could see a massive tidal wave coming.

‘Of all the times…’

There was a problem here, the master of this area was now dead. His nascent divinity made its way into his seed and was already nourishing it. The protective formation that he overloaded to keep the other masters here had also been damaged. These people didn’t have the know-how or resources to establish it again.

‘Can these fish people even come on land… those sea creatures didn’t seem to like the sun too much.’

He felt a bit responsible for what was awaiting the city residents that didn’t have anything to do with the Onyx Moon Sect. If the deep sea creatures were able to climb on land they would certainly destroy the coastline. The demonic sect members would probably abandon the people living here and prioritize themselves. They would surely give up their land if it meant survival.

‘This might also be a good chance to see what these fish people can really do…’

While floating in the air he looked at the terrified citizens. The tsunami wave was foreshadowed by a large dark storm that blocked out the sun. Some of the cultivators were already starting to flee while others were waiting for his move. Zhang Dong in their eyes was the new Patriarch, they didn’t know what he would do if they just fled without receiving an order.

For the time being, he decided to stay, he could just not let these many people die while he was here. Even though the people living here were brought up with a certain lack of morals that wasn’t their fault. They were mostly victims of their environment and were trying to survive. The young kids that were still not corrupted by this demonic island still deserved a chance.

“Look out, the wave is coming, run!”

“It’s too close, we won't make it in time!”

“W-wait, what is that?”

People that were closest to the scene were panicking. Their boats that their life depended on were getting capsized. The whole pier would be instantly destroyed after the huge wave collided with it. However, a strange purple haze appeared out of nowhere. The massive wave of water collided with it but couldn’t get through.

This wave of energy started spreading to all sides while quickly halting the water from moving forward. While from the outside it looked miraculous the person performing this act was straining himself. Even though he was a pinnacle grade nascent soul master, contending with this much water wasn’t easy even for him

His Dao that concerned water was high but it was not at the level of these sea dwellers. He needed to use his newfound Dao of gravity to lessen the strain on his spiritual energy. Then slowly the force that created this wave would balance itself out. In the end, only a smaller part of the city was partially flooded with the wave not hitting as hard as it normally would.

Everyone gathered here knew who was responsible for this task. It was a very strange sight to behold as these people were not used to being saved. Already they were wondering what the cause for this act of bravery was. Did their new leader just want to show off and garner sympathy before he betrayed them? They just couldn’t see him doing it out of generosity, he probably needed the city for something and was just defending it for his own selfish reasons.

‘They really look confused…’

To Zhang Dong, this was a strange sight to behold. Normally people that he saved would have already dropped down to their knees to worship his good dead. These people on the other hand seemed to be waiting for some kind of punchline. He could only imagine the life they could have led to this point that would produce such a reaction.

“Just go back inside of your houses, there is nothing you can do here.”

His voice spread through the entire city which confused the residents even more. The way this new Patriarch acted was strange, to say the least. They all saw him floating toward the pier and he was even helping some of the people that were hit by the smaller wave. All the rubble that had anyone trapped under it started slowly floating up as if it had no weight.

‘Hm… are they changing their tactics? Interesting… do they really need a connection to the sea or water?’

While he slowly approached the shore that was hit the most he continued to look at the map. There he could see the enemy dots going for the flooded part of the city. Previously they were hidden away by the giant wave but when it wasn’t able to flood the whole city they changed their directions. He could already feel a large number of sea creatures coming this way, some of them were already crawling out of the murky depths.

‘Giant lobsters and crabs? Is that a turtle?’

What emerged were huge versions of regular sea life. They weren’t that strong but they were many. Behind them he could also see other creatures thrashing around but unable to move forward. The ones that had the basis of fish couldn’t move forward, probably the pier wasn’t flooded enough to allow them to advance any further.

The winds picked up and the thunder above them started crackling as the wave of sea monsters flooded forward. If his previous enemies the demi-humans were a small force of elites then this was the reverse. It was a monster wave tactic that looked like a beast stampede. Luckily the monsters weren’t all that strong with only a tiny fraction achieving the sea king level that he previously encountered.

“You really shouldn’t have brought this storm over with me around…”

There was no way he could get rid of the water that was slowly rising but he could still attack the person that was causing this effect. Water was something that allow electricity to travel through and it was the same with lightning. Yet these bolts of lightning wouldn’t be able to pierce that far and only beings closer to the surface would be affected. Luckily for him quite a large amount of these beasts were just crawling out as if they owned the place.

Taking ownership of the storm wasn’t hard, while his Dao of water was below the sea dwellers the dao of air and lightning wasn’t. They could better control the rainwater inside those clouds but when it came to the winds and lightning he came out on top. With the mass of clouds above him it was easy to commence the attack and turn this whole place into a light show.

The people had already started evacuating and running so they were in no danger. The monsters on the other hand started getting bombarded by blue bolts of energy. It was as if lightning was raining down and quickly electrocuting any of the creatures that dared to venture outside the water.

Everyone covered their eyes while looking up into the sky. There within the clouds, they could see the elusive master covered in a bubble of energy. Lightning bolts were connecting with his body but he did not react. He just floated there while looking down at the beasts that were quickly becoming cooked. Even this massive number of creatures was unable to take a step into the city that this man was protecting.

‘Hm… are they retreating?’

Zhang Dong continued to observe, after the initial strategy failed the sea monsters started to retreat. The ones at the nascent soul level were pushed forward but he could feel that they weren’t at their full power. The one that he defeated earlier had quicker movements, with so much lightning energy combating the water energy their fighting power dropped.

‘Those mermaids really don’t like to come outside?’

Even when the larger sea monsters appeared their masters were still just hiding inside of the water. Did they expect to defeat him with these trash mobs that he could easily kill off with the lightning storm above? Or were they trying to make him use up his spiritual energy while defending the city?

His new friends from the Onyx Moon sect weren’t doing anything helpful though. The common residents were quickly fleeing but they were just looking out from within their sect grounds. It was clear that they weren’t honest when they were calling him the Patriarch. Only if he gave out a proper order would they probably carry it out.

“What are you all standing there for? Assist the Patriarch!”

‘Oh?’

To Zhang Dong's surprise, there were actually some of them that decided to aid him. A smaller number of core formation experts and foundation establishment practitioners jumped in. They gave him some ranged support but weren’t really able to cause long-lasting damage to the large monsters.

‘Are they trying to suck up to me?’

From an outsider's perspective, it seemed that Zhang Dong was winning. The waves of sea beasts continued to fall to the lightning strikes. What would happen to them if the scary demonic being like the one he was playing survived this onslaught? What would happen if he took out his rage on the people that didn’t even try to lift a finger. Thus after the small group of cultivators jumped in, the others weren’t far behind.

‘Their expressions certainly tell a tale…’

Zhang Dong went through a few battles with his own sect members. The members of the United Element Sect didn’t look this meek. These people were just desperately trying to fight for their life without even knowing if a victory here would mean anything. If the new Patriarch decided they could have already been dead due to hesitating in the first place.

‘Is this what Wang Long’s army will look like when we face them?’

Fighting against people that were basically forced to fight for their own lives wasn’t something that he enjoyed. The demi-humans weren’t much different as after their leader vanished they started to abandon the fight. These were the types of enemies that he and his people would need to go against.

Yet the fight needed to continue, he had already made it this far and there was no going back. Either Wang Long and his new demonic sect would come out victorious or him. The other Empires were only a diversion that he couldn’t let himself be distracted with.

Chapter 528

“W-we won?”

“How could these many monsters fall in such a short amount of time…”

“It’s all thanks to the new Patriarch!”

The people from the Onyx Moon Sect looked with awe at the massacre that took place. Even a single one of those huge monsters would have been a catastrophe but all of them were now dead. The whole shoreline was riddled with sea creature corpses that were filled with spiritual energy. To these demonic cultivators that could use the beast cores to cultivate this was a bounty worth dying for.

They couldn’t make a move though, even though they had contributed to the fight it came late. The man that almost single-handedly killed them all was still floating up in the air. His figure was engraved into the people's minds, he just stood there like a pillar with his chin raised high.

‘Hm, are these people summoner types or something?’

Zhang Dong was the senior that everyone was looking at now. The storm clouds were used up and finally dispersed after the vast majority of the enemy forces were now gone. What he could feel now was a small bunch of them still hiding inside the water. They were protecting what seemed to be the leader.

They were really biding their time and only using the mindless sea monsters as a fighting force. After he cleared out most of them they just started to back away. It was clear that they would probably retreat back into the sea, that is if he didn’t stop them.

‘I should probably not lose more time here…’

His reason for coming here was not to battle these monsters. Even if he was victorious he still felt that battling them under the sea would be disadvantageous to him. As long as they remained there, he didn’t feel that they were much of a threat. After this defeat, they would probably think twice about going to shore.

‘At least now I know their tactics and weaknesses, they really don’t do well out of water.’

The tidal wave that caused parts of the city to flood was already retreating. Water elements that previously swarmed from all sides were slowly dissipating. Without the sea creatures to intensify these water elements their plan wouldn’t work. They needed to cover the lands with seawater that boosted their might and also allowed the many sea monsters to survive. Without it, they didn’t pose that much of a threat.

‘I guess they aren’t sure what to do yet, I’ll have to give them a reason to leave…’

In his palm, a blob of purple energy appeared and it was combined with an orb of lightning. The construct started expanding but didn’t go above the size of a basketball. The core was constantly getting squished to contain more energy and this was made a lot easier with his gravitational Dao.

After a moment the attack was sent flying towards the location of the enemy leaders. Zhang Dong figured that they didn’t think that he was able to sense them. This was probably the reason why they didn’t leave yet. Now, on the other hand, a massive wave of energy was coming their way.

Three of the giant sea monsters that he previously demolished were sent out to block it. The first one suffered an instant defeat as the energy balls just shot past through its chest. Then when it collided with the other two it finally exploded.

He could not hear what the merpeople were saying but he could feel that they were retreating. Even though they were deeply submerged under water, the explosion produced a massive pillar of water to shoot up. The cultivators that were with him were quick to retreat as this also produced a massive wave that crashed into the pier once more.

‘Huh? Is there someone really prideful with them?’

Even after the warning shot was sent and three of the huge nascent soul sea creatures were dead, the merpeople didn’t retreat. Instead, he could feel that he had only aggravated the leader into a frenzy. They seemed to be calling for more sea creatures by sending some kind of signal through the sea, if he didn’t stop them then another wave would be approaching them.

‘Are they perhaps very easily irritable?... If so then couldn’t I just use them?’

His mind started to spin as he realized something. For all intents and purposes, he was a demonic cultivator now. These sea dwellers weren’t attacking the Empire or any lands that he owned. Their aim was the island where Wang Long resided. If he managed to point them in his direction then perhaps they could actually aid him in his next endeavor.

While he didn’t want to send any spirit points toward his enemy, it wouldn’t matter in the grand scheme of things. With another force attacking his new base Wang Long would be forced to send out his people to protect the lands. Even if the merpeople lost they would probably weaken the demonic armies.

‘Okay let's try this…’

“You dare go against a proud demonic being like me? Do you think you can just enter the demonic island without dying? Come out!”

With a grand shout and show of power, he flew towards the spot that the last of the merpeople were in. While his enemies would be stronger underwater it didn’t mean that he would lose to them. The leader this time around was at the upper levels of the nascent soul level. Just like before they were holding a trident and didn’t look much different than the old man that he apprehended. He wasn’t the only one with that weapon, there were two others that were closer to the middle stage.

“You conceited air breather!”

“I’m the one being conceited? What about you? How can you hope to defeat a demon like me? You inferior sea creatures need to learn who your betters are!”

“You dare insult our noble race?”

“Noble race? You are nothing more than seafood to us and our lord Wang Long! He will soon set out to eradicate your inferior race of beings. But at least you have your uses, the meat from that other one did taste delicious… I’m sure elixirs made from you stinky fish mongrels will be worth a lot of blood crystals!”

“Y-you, what do you mean by that… “

Zhang Dong started talking while exchanging some blows with the three trident holders. The sea creatures that were with them attempted to fight him as well but he was just too slippery. Then whenever they closed in he just needed to release a burst of electric energy to stun them for a moment.

His little performance was working and he continued to kill off the mindless sea monsters that were being controlled by these people. By taking his time he was giving them some hope in resisting. If he just wiped the floor with them his plan wouldn’t work too well. They needed to at least think that they would have a good chance of winning a war with the demonic cultivators.

Soon enough he started exchanging blows with the mermen. To his surprise, they could use some strange underwater martial arts. They lacked legs and had to use their fish tails which were actually an advantage here. Their speed was tremendous and if Zhang Dong’s cultivation level wasn’t vastly above them he would probably struggle.

“R-retreat, we must retreat and inform the Queen…”

“You want to retreat? But I won’t be able to eat you if you do that, your fate is to become our food, even if you flee the demons will come for you, our King will eradicate you all!”

He continued to belittle them while knocking out the two weaker mermen. They quickly made their way into his spatial treasure but for the man that was left to watch it seemed as if they were getting devoured by a demonic being. Soon he was escaping while trying to use the sea monsters as shields.

‘Finally… I hope this works…’

The enemy leader had decided to turn back. The speed that he was running was truly astonishing. Zhang Dong felt that he would have trouble chasing after him when being in all this water. His flight technique wasn’t created to work that well under the sea.

‘Will this guy report it to this Queen? If it works out they will attack this place again and probably force the demonic leaders to act then that leaves this leaderless city…’

This was a conundrum that he wouldn’t be here for. There was only so much that he could do by himself. These people that lived in the city always had an option to leave now that their leader was gone. This was also something that he needed to make them aware of. He was not going to stay here to protect them, his place was with his own sect and not this city.

“Listen well because I’m not going to repeat myself.”

After the battle was over he turned around to look over the whole city. Quickly the cultivators and regular citizens trembled in fear. They all quickly went down to their knees, they all knew that there was no way of going against such a powerful old monster that they thought Zhang Dong was.

“I am not your Patriarch or part of the city, I don’t know if those creatures will return or not but you will have to take care of them by yourselves. Use these corpses if you wish, they matter not to me in the slightest.”

The message was short and clear, he would be leaving now and they were free to do what they wished. He could not stop any pillaging attempts or in-fighting to get into their old leaders' private chambers. All of them were aware that without a nascent soul master to back them, there was no way for this sect to survive. The only option would be to join another power while offering some gifts or to give up cultivating altogether.

“But remember this, those sea monsters might return here, some of them have survived…”

He would leave them with a warning. The message was clear, they had a limited time of getting out of the city that could potentially be invaded soon. The sea monsters that were killed were a source of food that would probably last for quite some time. What these people needed to do was to pack up and retreat to the mainland.

‘I hope this goes well…’

Even though the enemy of his enemy was his friend he wasn’t sure if he was making the right decision. What the merpeople would do was still a mystery but he did point them in Wang Long’s direction and could only hope that they would point their tridents towards his throat.

‘I need to find a safe spot for the teleportation array…’

Soon enough he took off while leaving everyone in the city stupefied. While speeding away he could sense some people rushing towards the dead monsters while others quickly abandoned the city their lives were now up to their choices.

Chapter 529

“This place is really a shithole…”

Zhang Dong gave out a sigh while looking at a giant sandworm attacking a bunch of traveling merchants. The monster in itself wasn’t that strong as it was on the lower spectrum of foundation establishment but there was more than one. The people it was attacking were fighting back and actually winning but this didn’t take away from the fact that this was a place not meant to live in.

He had ventured out of the coastal city and began his main infiltration mission. First, he needed to find a good spot to bring his troops in and then scout the main city layout. Wang Long’s whereabouts were known to him but he could always flee. With the system in his grasp, there was always an option to teleport out. However, there was a way to block the escape and this was thanks to his hacked system and Bob.

This was one reason why he was willing to move in with his whole army. They needed to surround the entire area and bring it under his control. Only then could he use a faction option that would prevent his enemy from escaping. Only then would he be able to have a proper one-on-one battle to end it all.

In theory, he would be successful but there was no way of knowing if Wang Long hadn’t advanced passed him already. This was a possibility with his new demonic techniques that ignored human suffering while giving the user imaginable power. Normally even demonic cultivators didn’t go overboard, there was a certain limit of how much a human soul could handle.

If too many evil acts were done in a short amount of time, the user could suffer a blow to their psyche. It wasn’t strange for such a person to go on a rampage before becoming fully mad before a quick death. Yet Wang Long possessed the system and its store, it wouldn’t be hard to find techniques in there that could prevent the user from being taken over by heart demons.

But it didn’t seem that everyone on this island was a being filled with murderous intent. The people he was looking at didn’t seem much different from the ones back home. Their Qi was demonic in nature but that was just the side effect of their cultivation method. They mostly used demonic beasts to nourish their power.

It was quite the cycle, the beasts would eat smaller creatures and also humans to gain their own cultivation. Then cultivators would hunt them for the same reason, sometimes they would come out victorious but sometimes the beasts caused widespread massacres. Both sides were eating each other just so they could survive for a bit longer.

‘I won’t need to help them at least, good. The Qi in the air is faint but it is slightly tainted with demonic energies.’

One thing was for certain, while there were fewer cultivators and people living in these lands. On average, they were stronger than the people from the mainland. Stealing Qi from the defeated enemies was a lot faster than absorbing it from pills or air.

‘Didn’t expect to meet those two though, they really made a run for it…’

One of the reasons that the demonic sandworms were being slain was due to two certain bodyguards. They were the grandfather and granddaughter pair that he had run into at open sea. Just as they claimed they made a run for it the moment he went to the restaurant. Now they were acting as caravan guards while going towards the next big settlement.

‘That old fart could use a flying sword… is he perhaps scared to reveal his true cultivation level?’

The man was just one core formation elder. Without a proper backing, he would be seen as an easy target to steal Qi from. If both of them pretended that they were weaker then the enemies that would appear would also be weaker.

‘They will probably try to lay low in a region owned by a different demon or sect… but that’s not something I should worry about, this place will go through a big change after I’m through with it…’

While Zhang Dong felt bad for turning these people's world upside down, it was a necessary evil. He didn’t fool himself into believing that everything could be taken care of without any bloodshed. This he could only minimize by putting himself in more danger. If he did things half-heartedly then perhaps more casualties would arise. Thus while camouflaging himself up in the clouds he ventured into the huge desert.

‘This Island really doesn’t have much going for itself, does it?’

He had examined a few maps that he got from the port city. This vast desert area covered almost half of the island's surface. There were a few large settlements near pockets of underground water that were spread out between each other. The merchants that he saw earned their money by traveling between these huge cities.

One of them he could even see from here. Its walls were truly massive as they went for around two hundred meters up and were slung around the city like a giant snake. All around it, he could also see many monster carcasses that belonged to sand worms or huge beast variants that looked like scorpions.

‘No wonder they only have one nascent soul master per location, there aren't that many to go around…’

For the time being, he decided to gain altitude while ignoring this city. With little to no resources, there wasn’t much to go around even for the leader of such a city-state. It was probably more useful for a nascent soul master to create their own cities for funneling resources towards them instead.

‘I wonder if the citisens would migrate to the mainland if they could?’

It wasn’t that easy to travel from this island to the lands of the orthodox sects. There were many deadly barriers that prevented anyone from leaving. The most deadly one was the barrier of poisonous mist that also affected souls. Only powerful cultivators could resist it and enter the lands rich with Qi.

“Hm… I don’t think that I'm even powerful enough to affect these natural phenomena… I would probably need to go a step beyond.”

The fabled immortal stage felt like it was around the corner and yet also really far away. If he divided known cultivation into stages then the immortal realm would be at stage three. For now, he was only stuck at stage one while stage two had been locked by the people that created the rules.

‘I wonder what will happen when I finally get there…’

Zhnag Dong stopped in mid-air and looked in all directions. He could see a good chunk of the island that was probably bigger than the planet that he originally came from. When glancing from here he started to worry. Not about if he could defeat Wang Dong but what would happen after that victory.

After beating the Demi-human Emperor he felt that this war wouldn’t pose much of a problem. His true enemy was still Wang Long and not the setting that was created to achieve a breakthrough. The true meaning behind this would only be revealed after he ascends just as the person in the secret ground mentioned it.

‘What will happen to them?’

He asked himself this question several times but he didn’t know the answer. What would happen to his family if he was forcefully rejected from this world. Would they be able to continue their lives without a worry or would another system holder arrive that could potentially destroy them. Would this world perhaps be reset by an administrator and destroyed?

All of these unanswered questions were slowly getting to him as he didn’t want to end it. Yet unless he cleared up things here then the whole place would be destroyed anyway. If he waited for too long Wang Long would quickly amass so much power that it wouldn’t be possible to win. This was his best chance at victory and he needed to take it.

Thus he sped into the distance while consulting his own man for directions. He had marked a few spots that were close enough to the capital city where the Chaos Demon was supposed to be. The meeting with all the demonic leaders would be taking place in less than two weeks and he needed to prepare. That event could be a dead end but he could not ignore it. Wang Long was said to appear and if he actually managed to attack before he organized his people then he would have a leg to stand on.

‘Wish my dear brother could step in to cover my ass but I’m not sure I can trust him.’

The work on the walls to keep out the demi-humans was still an ongoing project. He wanted to let his people build up defenses before coming over here in full force. If he abandoned the project then there was a possibility of demi-human remnants causing some trouble. Yet this could be a risk that he needed to take.

‘This looks like a good spot…’

He finally stopped after spotting something interesting. While the outside looked like a scorching desert there was something underground. Quickly he turned into a glowing drill that plunged itself into the ground. There after going through a layer of about a hundred meters of sand and hard rock he burst forth to a large open cavern.

There wasn’t that much air in here and he couldn’t feel any wind but it was something that he could work with. After gathering a bit of Qi onto his finger he produced a large glowing sphere of light. It was flung up to illuminate the whole place but as a side effect, it awoke the original inhabitants of this place.

“Good morning I guess?”

This place was partially dug up by sandworms, it looked to be a resting place for their kind. There were large tunnels going in many directions as well as eggs. It was a breeding ground for the monsters that plagued the desert.

“You’ll have to excuse me, but I need this place for my teleportation array, would you be so kind to leave?”

“GUOOOH!”

One of the larger variants opened up its huge mouth and instantly dived for the glowing human. Zhang Dong didn’t dodge but instead just surrounded himself with a thick layer of radiant Qi. The moment the teeth collided with it the worm's whole head exploded along with part of its body. It was still an evil monster and not able to stomach the holy energy that he radiated.

“I guess that’s a no?”

Some beats gained some intelligence with age but these monsters were certainly not one of them. Before he got to work on the array he needed to get rid of the inconvenience. The parts from these sandworms could also be used for various elixirs, pills, and even weapons.

“Well then, it’s time for some worm extermination!”

He shouted while pointing out with his finger towards the wiggling beasts. On its tip, a radiant glow appeared once more. Soon a beam of light erupted that split apart into many smaller ones that gave chase. In a matter of seconds, the entire area turned into a graveyard filled with worm entrails.

“Hm… I think I’ll need to purify the air … those worms stink…”

Zhang Dong shielded his nose with his spiritual energy after the massacre was done. Some cleaning would be in order first and soon after it was time to get some of his people over and take the fight to Wang Long.

Chapter 530

“Team Alpha reporting in, Patriarch!”

“Good, as you can see this place needs a lot of work, I managed to plug up most of the holes but those darn worms keep wandering back in…”

Zhang Dong had spent half a day clearing out the worm nesting space. The cavern was really huge and able to even hold large-scale ships inside of it. This seemed to have been a naturally formed underground cave that the sandworms just expanded even further.

He underestimated the characteristics of these territorial beasts. Even after all of them were gone along with their eggs, more continued to appear. It wouldn’t be strange if this was the main habitat of those monsters and they always found their way back here. It looked like they were dead set on living in this large area even if they continued to die.

For this very reason, Zhang Dong had to bring out Bahamut for some help and also place protective formations in the main tunnels. Normally it might have been a good idea to just find another place but there were reasons that he decided to stay. One of them was due to time constrictions, flying around these unknown lands would be quite tiresome.

Then there was the real reason why he wanted to stay here, it was the tunnels. They were quite huge, large enough to allow even an Argonaut class ship to go through. These tunnels went through the entire desert and he had already sent out a few probes with Bob’s Ai on them to map everything out.

These probes were able to hide their presence from the beasts roaming the tunnels. As long as they didn’t bump into one of them directly they would not be discovered. His system map was quickly becoming filled out with the underground structure and his Ai program could even point out the quickest path towards his destination.

“Leave it to us, Patriarch!”

“Quick, bring in the teleportation base, we will begin assembly now!”

A group of around twenty cultivators arrived through the small teleportation gate that he created. They brought along larger parts of a similar one and through it most of his army would be going through. For the time being all of the resources would be moved towards this area so that this war could come to a close. When the island of demons is finally captured then it would probably be all over.

‘They sure work fast… I should leave it to them.’

Another nascent soul master arrived that he wasn’t that familiar with. Huo Qiang didn’t want to be stuck in a cave if there wasn’t much fighting to be had. Zhang Zhi was also busy with other things and both of them would only move when the time was right. For the time being they needed to remain to clear out the Demi-human remnants.

Zhang Dong on the other hand needed to continue to map out these tunnels. After throwing a few more orbs forward he sped into one of the tunnels. When passing into the passage he felt the protective barrier around him that would block out even nascent soul worm beasts.

‘There are other large caves like this one, maybe I should look into those too.’

Thus for the time being he turned into a sandworm hunter. He spent a few days going through the tunnels and clearing out the large open spaces. There he would establish more bases where his people could start preparing. Even if the tunnels proved too small to travel through it didn’t matter. They could always just burst through the rocky underground and approach the main city directly. This would of course give their positions away which was something that he wanted to avoid.

“Bahamut, remain here and help clear out any of the monsters you come across.”

Finally, a week had passed since he arrived here and only a bit of time remained for this assembly to commence. Zhang Dong found himself at the edge of the desert and at the beginning of a poisonous forest. The trees looked to be alive and carnivorous, many demonic beasts that fed on the flesh of people resided here and were a natural barrier between the main demon city.

“GAO!”

His golden dragon returned to the underground while his people continued to transport resources. Within a week all of them would be here and then his battle plan could start. The only troublesome thing was his golden fortress. It could not fit through the gate, the only way of getting it here was through direct teleportation that spent spirit points.

It was quite a large number which would lower his escape chances later on. It would be able to get here but moving it back to a safe location would be impossible. Unless he found a large spirit stone mine there would be no way of running. With how this place was a barren wasteland that lacked almost any spiritual energy, that would probably not happen.

‘Could a nucleus be here somewhere? There might have been someone that started out as a demonic faction member in the past.’

There was only one chance of getting an injection of spiritual energy. If he managed to find a spawning point of a system holder then it was possible. Yet scanning the entire landmass as he did in the old days wasn’t feasible. For now, he needed to focus on the mission at hand.

‘This looks quite ominous…’

He looked at the mass of malicious energy and gave it a prod with his finger. Thanks to the various Dao’s that he absorbed he was somewhat able to keep the poison from entering his body. It was only a temporary measure as he could feel the miasma slowly working its way in. If he didn’t cleanse it with his holy energy then it would slowly fester and create problems later down the line.

“Let’s get this over with… first is this gloomy forest… then I think there is some kind of lava lake and something similar to the shadowlands I encountered before…”

Normally someone that attempted to traverse through this way would consult some travel guides. There were certain spots that were safer than others. Some strong demonic monsters were territorial and only stayed in certain specific parts. However he wasn’t here just to get to the other side, he was trying to figure out the layout while also finding a flight path for his army. Even though this was a dangerous place he didn’t believe that it could block his entire force from advancing.

“It’s better to be safe than sorry, if some capricious immortal created this place then it could prove troublesome…”

Thus finally he flung himself into the deadly mist while also wearing a different disguise. His old face was already known as people came asking about him. Before leaving the port city he had altered the protective formation. It was possible to integrate something similar to a listening device. Through this, he was informed when a few nascent soul masters paid a visit after he left. The elders there were quick to give up all the information that they desired, it seemed that they were looking for him.

Yet from the conversation that he overheard it didn’t seem that Wang Long had ordered this chase. It was more probable that some sect members were trying to investigate the disappearance of their powerful members that just vanished. Now his face would probably be plastered all over the assassination guilds with rewards.

‘Just as I expected, they fear him enough to leak the information, if I’m lucky he’ll be stuck snorting some pill dust off a girl’s behind while we attack.’

While delving through the poisonous fog he noted down the monsters in the vicinity and had Bob instantly inform his people of the topography. His system map could also work in both ways, he could relay information onto a holographic representation and send information directly. There was a slight lag but it would be enough to inform anyone that followed after him.

The monsters here were mostly up to the core formation level with some ‘beast kings’ existing occasionally. They sectioned off these forests into zones that could be avoided. After he was done with the preliminary scouting then some of his sect brothers would move in. They would draw up the safest path for the coming armada and if it was necessary then create a battle plan in which the flying ships could take out the largest monsters.

‘This miasma doesn’t go up that far so we should be safe but some of those monsters might possess ranged capabilities.’

On his way to the end, he took out some lesser creatures without them even realizing that he was there. If he wanted he could probably lay waste to the entire region by himself but then his location would become obvious. Thus he finally arrived at an area covered by shadowy night, even from here he could feel the screams of decrepit souls.

‘Wish I could just absorb them like before…’

After giving out a sigh he dived right in. Thanks to the knowledge of his soul Dao he could remain hidden even to these immaterial ghost beings. Even though he could not take in their energy directly anymore they would not be able to harm him. The strength of these specters came from their numbers and the fact that not many people understood this type of difficult Dao.

Without them being able to form into something substantial they could only slowly drain their victims of energy. This area wouldn’t prove very difficult to venture through as long as everyone remains in the vicinity of the protective formation. But he also made sure to extinguish some of the larger specters that were on the cusp of becoming something stronger. With that out of the way, he finally arrived at the cusp of the next area that was covered in magma.

It was a truly gigantic active volcano that was spewing up deadly ash into the air. But there was some kind of veil created in the gigantic city around this massive mountain that kept it at bay. The outline of the dome shape protective formation was easy to make out as the ash continued to swirl around it but was unable to pierce through.

“So that’s it… the city of demons…”

It was hard to make out due to the swirling ash and hot air but the whole inhabitable area was composed of several cities. It was said to contain around three hundred million people within itself and all of them were cruel in nature.

“This won’t be as easy as I hoped it to be…”

Even without going in, he knew that there were layers upon layers of protective spells everywhere. If he ventured another hundred meters forward he would be walking into several deadly traps. Up in the air, he could also spot a bunch of grumpy-looking Chaos Sect members that were probably clued in about the man that saved the coastal city.

‘Luckily they can’t see me yet, here goes nothing…’

While hiding his presence he slowly approached the volcanic area after scouting out the area it would finally be time to take the offensive and finish this meaningless conflict once and for all.

Chapter 531

‘That about covers the outside, now should I call it a day or try to get in…’

Zhang Dong looked was sticking to a large tower that was situated on the outskirts of this Demon City. There were six others just like it and together they created a hexagram formation. These towers looked more like occult monoliths and in each one, a nascent soul demonic creature resided. For him that could mask his presence, it didn’t pose a problem as the guardians were still unaware of his presence.

Even though these monsters were quite strong they were not actually meant for battle. This was quite the occult protective measure that would use their life force to protect the outer city. If a problem arose then the hexagram would activate to defend the city with evil soul-draining energies. However, now that Zhang Dong was here it would not pose a problem. Thanks to his knowledge he had rigged this protective measure that would surprise his enemies.

It took a few days of sneaking around but he managed to go unnoticed while jerry-rigging the six spires. None of the nascent soul masters were aware of his presence as they had other things to worry about. While he was being secretive more people continued to arrive. They were all around the level of the Immolation Demon that he had met before. The assembly was soon going to take place which made things more complicated yet also gave him a better chance to infiltrate.

With so many nascent soul masters arriving it was impossible to check for everything. There was just not enough manpower to go around. This Chaos Sect was still new and these masters that arrived would probably be given a choice soon. Either they joined the sect or they would be eradicated.

‘I wonder if they know what is going to happen there or if they don’t think that Wang Long is capable of dominating everyone?’

There were some old monsters that didn’t enter the city and remained at the outskirts and outside the formation range. Some of them were weary of going inside the city as they were suspecting some foul play. Even though the war for supremacy was supposedly over some were not convinced.

‘It wouldn’t be strange if he created some kind of occult ritual to suppress everyone, it wouldn’t be hard to get with the system…’

The people that lived in this world still tended to underestimate system holders. Zhang Dong knew that immortal grade techniques were almost nonexistent. To everyone’s knowledge, there wouldn’t be anything that would be able to dominate multiple nascent soul masters at once. This would require a huge amount of spiritual energy and preparation. The city was a mish-mash of renegade cultivators that didn’t like each other. It would probably not be possible to hide such a formation without everyone knowing.

‘No one would suspect an ancient technique to pop up that didn’t require preparation but if it’s the system we are talking about, then it’s possible. If Wang Long had gathered enough points then it’s a possibility…’
From his investigation, he knew that Wang Long went on a large killing spree. Many masters of demonic arts had fallen to him and also huge sects both here and back in the empire. Even though he was getting fewer and fewer points from weaker enemies, he was killing people in the millions which could make up for it.

Yet this was just a theory, for all he knew Wang Long could have nothing planned out at all. It was possible that they were just throwing a giant party to announce the rise of the new demon king. Perhaps they would just give them an ultimatum which could potentially make things easier for his forces. If during the announcement the nascent soul masters began causing trouble, then it would be the right time to attack.

‘I won’t really know unless I sneak into the city and listen to the rumors or go further in…’

It seemed that Wang Long was taking the whole Demon King persona quite literally. The whole city was built around an active volcano that was being held back from exploding by several contraptions. Yet even then the owner of this city decided to place a huge castle inside of the huge basin of molten lava that was inside. Even from outside, he could see the tip of the castle which had a large number of black towers. It looked like it was created from an assortment of swords that were somehow glued together.

This reminded him of the past when he went through some of the system store options. There he remembered finding large structures that could be purchased with points. This thing was probably one of them, perhaps it was similar to the golden bastion that also generated some passive resources. It wouldn’t be strange if he decided to get it due to his new faction and was using it as the main headquarters. Perhaps it also had a teleportation feature as the golden fortress that he had.

‘Shit, if that thing can help him escape then it complicates things… Bob, can you block that thing from teleporting?’

‘Not enough information to make a statement, the user will need to examine the object to make a proper estimation.’

‘I thought as much…’

During his last battle with Wang Long, his system Ai had enough time to examine him. Through that, he was able to counter the teleportation feature. Yet the castle was a separate object, it could perhaps be able to escape if he had enough points.

‘Bob, how long would you need to examine that thing? Would it be possible to do it during the battle?’

‘Can’t make an assumption without examining the target, inadequate data.’

‘Yeah, I thought so…’

Zhang Dong would need to get closer and at least touch the castle for Bob to predict the time needed. It would be a numbers game, the more resources he invested into the blocking system the faster and better it would work. The big question here was if he had more juice than his opponent.

‘He must have spent most of his points on that castle… maybe this announcement is actually about that… but if that’s the case I need to attack before it starts…’

After thinking through the options he decided to risk it. It was important to figure out what was really going on here. Was he hosting this meeting to forcefully recruit the demonic cultivators or to kill them for points. If it was the latter then the best choice would be to announce it and quickly attack before Wang Long has enough spirit points to counter Bob.

‘Before going in, I should probably call in…’

Zhang Dong brought up his system window from which he selected Zhang Kuo that had somewhat turned into a personal secretary.

“Give me a report, how are things progressing?”

“Yes Patriarch, we have started the process of bringing in the large-scale ships. The help that we asked for from the other sects is also on the way, they will arrive later but we should be able to keep everything within the time frame.”

“Good, it will take a bit longer on my side and I might not be able to contact you for a day or two.”

“I understand but Patriarch, shouldn’t you return we could send the spy unit out and…”

“That won’t be possible, they aren’t trained in going against demonic formations yet, I’ll have to do it myself.”

“I understand Patriarch…”

After a quick exchange between the two, he had an idea where he stood. From the exit of the desert, it would take at least one day for his army to arrive at this massive city. This wasn’t the same for his golden bastion that could be teleported in a lot closer. He had already created a location for it to sawn in. Regretfully he did not have enough points for it to emerge within the city, if that was possible then conquering it would be a cakewalk.

‘Maybe if I played more Strategy games this wouldn’t be happening…’

Zhang Dong gave out a sigh while looking out into the distance. He was still the most suited candidate for this espionage mission. Sometimes he wished that he could just relax and send out his minions to do his biddings while he enjoys the good life. Instead, he was stuck going through smelly poison-filled environments for days without end.

In some instances, he had to encase himself in dirt and mud to evade peering eyes. After going through this entire area he needed to switch his clothes three times already. This was not something a leader of the sect should be doing but he didn’t trust anyone to do a good enough job with such an important mission. Perhaps when the danger passed and Wang Long was gone he could relax while his sect members carried out missions against the other empires.

‘How should I do this, sneaking into the formation as I am might be possible but what if I bump into the wrong person…’

There were a few ways of going around this problem, one of them would be just keeping to the shadows and not sticking out. Then there was the second option of staying in plain sight while in a disguise. The second option gave more freedom but more eyes would be on him for the entirety of the infiltration mission. It was also less of a hassle as he would not have to constantly look over his shoulder.

‘But who should I impersonate…’

This was the big question but quickly he had the answer. There were many people entering this city, many demonic cultivators were on their way to pay tribute to the new demon king. He just needed to pick up one that didn’t stick out too much and take their place. With his disguising technique this would be an easy task, the only possible problem was entering Wang Long’s faction territory.

‘Bob, can you hide me from his system or not?’

‘User Wang Long’s faction is at a lesser development stage than of user Zhang Dong’s, hiding presence will be possible.’

‘Nice, finally some good news, I guess building all those lady cafes to keep people happy was not a mistake'

Thanks to faction systems he could analyze and identify anyone that was outside of it. As long as they were in his territory scanning was available and this was his way of finding out potential spies. With the help of his AI he would be able to pose as a regular demonic cultivator he just needed to find a good face to impersonate.

‘Hm… that one looks promising… they also made a stop before entering the city…’

Not far from here he spotted a flying ship from a demonic being. For some reason, they had decided to make a stop here and the person in charge was moving away from the rest. It was the perfect chance to make his move…

A note from Kuropon

Thank you for reading!

Don't forget to follow, favorite, rate.

Donate | Discord |

Chapter 532

“I just can’t relax, what is that maniac up to? Should I just run and leave a body double instead? No… they would figure it out instantly…”

‘This guy is quite talkative…’

Zhang Dong was keeping himself hidden while looking at an old-looking cultivator. From a quick scan, he could see that the person was a middle stage nascent soul cultivator. His Dao was a mix of the people that he already faced and not something that he couldn’t emulate at this point. It seemed the man had gotten nervous and decided to take a pee in the forest.

He arrived on a large ship that looked like it was filled with ghosts. It radiated faint spirit energy and was filled with multiple decrepit souls. This was actually a good fit for Zhang Dong as ghosts and spirits were aligned with his Dao of the Souls. The man also had some treasures that utilized phantom energies which were right up his alley.

‘Doesn’t feel right to attack a man that is taking a piss… but oh well, the guy has probably murdered countless people, the stench of evil is quite noticeable.’

Within a flash, he found himself behind the unsuspecting man. Right when the demonic cultivator noticed his head was already flying. Zhang Dong surrounded the area with a bubble that wouldn’t allow any screams to escape. The man’s corrupted nascent divinity that looked more like an evil spirit couldn’t even react as it was quickly taken into his seed along with the techniques he studied.

Dao:

|

Percentage gained

Phantoms

|

0 %

Demon Summoning

|

2 %

Curse

|

1 %

‘Dao of the phantoms was it? Not really that useful at this point…’

The Dao of Phantoms was lower on the totem pole than his Dao of Souls. Due to this, he was unable to gain anything on that particular path. The Demon Summoning one was a first and as the name stated he would be able to summon evil creatures to do his bidding. This was more of a ritualistic summoning and not the kind seen in RPG games that were instantaneous.

‘Good, no one noticed… Let’s check the loot…’

He looked at the dead body that was being dissolved before him. The robe that the man was wearing was quickly put through a cleaning spell that he learned from the other world. Without using it he would need to contend with a smell akin to mothballs. The man had a lot of rings and talismans which didn’t really do much for his safety. Some of them had even cracked as they were unable to defend against the powerful killing slice.

‘I hope this guy didn’t have any intimate relationship with his people… let’s see, his name was, Fang Jingguo?’

Luckily Zhang Dong was able to read the man’s limited status screen before he kicked the bucket. He belonged to the Phantom Devil Cult and was its leader. There were a few secret techniques in the man’s spatial ring along with some personal letters that let him figure out a few things. It didn’t seem that he had any relatives in the sect and mostly spent his time cultivating but there was only so much he could learn after absorbing the knowledge from the notes here.

‘I guess I should head out… how did the guy walk?’

After turning into the old pale man he assumed a slouched position. In his right hand, he had what looked to be an old walking cane. While holding it the attention was drawn to the colorful golden and platinum rings on his fingers. Thus for the time being he tried mimicking the old man’s walking style that he examined before the beheading.

‘Zhi, I’ll be infiltrating the enemy city and won’t be able to contact you for a while.’

‘Be careful, Sir.’

‘I always am.’

Zhang Dong was sure to send a message to his people, even if he didn’t come back he was sure that they would continue with the mission. He wasn’t quite sure what he would do inside, if luck was on his side then he would take the chance to take out his nemesis. It was always easier to defeat an enemy that wasn’t expecting a confrontation.

‘This would be a lot easier if that chucklehead of an older brother helped me, but he might be part of this system like that other demon king…’

Long Qing the Azure Emperor wasn’t willing to help and at this point, Zhang Dong had become weary of his existence. The man was the first on the list of being part of the administrative gang that could destroy the world on a whim. Yet without him reaching a power level above the limits of the setting, he didn’t think that the hidden overlords would act.

“Cult leader!”

“Mmm…”

When he arrived back he was greeted by hooded cult members. No one dared to look him in the eye and just waited for him to slowly board the ship. Thanks to the rules in this world Zhang Dong was somewhat confident in his disguise. Even if he acted a bit differently than the old cult leader no one would be able to call him out on it. Demonic cultivators were prone to violent outbursts so no one in their right mind would pester them without having a good reason for it.

“Why is the cult reader so silent? Is he mad?”
“Stop spouting nonsense, if he hears you then you’re a goner, just shut up and let’s go.”

It wasn’t that difficult to find the man’s personal cabin that was radiating quite the strange energy. While walking he spread out his senses in all directions and overheated people whispering between each other. It was not something he would pick up without the system’s help which probably gave them the guts to gossip about their boss.

“I see, so he is a cranky old man that is easily irritated?”

After sitting down in this gloomy cabin he looked out through the window. There he could see the ship gaining altitude and heading towards one of the main gates. There they would probably be inspected and then let into the city.

‘Did this guy bring slaves as gifts to the new sect? I can also sense some demonic beasts…’

This ship was quite large and in some rooms there were ravenous bests chained up. Even now he could feel their animosity not dying down. Besides them he could feel a group of young women, they weren’t strong in any way, probably just offerings to the perverted Demon King.

Normally he would be glad to rescue these people and even let the creatures out. Yet this was a mission that he couldn’t fail. His resolve needed to be steeled as on the inside he expected to see far worse things than slaves. The city was huge and a place where one's life was worth less than a grain of rice. With millions of citizens everywhere it was hard to remember that life was actually precious.

“Halt!”

‘So it has begun…’

While remaining in place he watched the outside. There his new cult members were handing out some identification papers along with a few barrels of blood crystals. It was clear that the new sect was on the rise and all the other ones in high positions were trying to weasel into their good graces. To many, this was a chance to make some good connections that might allow them to prosper in the future.

“Phantom Devil Cult? Where is your leader?”

“H-he is in his private quarters, the cult leader is very old and frail so we…”

“Silence, bring him out.”

“A-as you wish…”

‘What is this about? Did they realize that I replaced the guy? Was someone watching when I killed him?’

The person that gave the command was only at the core formation level. There were a few nascent soul elders nearby but they were keeping their presence hidden. Normally if there was a problem they would call for more help so it didn’t look that he was in trouble just yet. If something went wrong he could still just escape as long as he wasn’t in Wang Long’s main faction zone he would be able to teleport out normally.

‘No, perhaps they just want to flex a bit…’

He had been paying attention to other ships that were at other entrance points. There he could see the gatekeepers going overboard as well. Some of them were even making the demons bow. In front of the massive sect there was nothing but death if they didn’t bow their heads.

This was similar to the old days where his Zhang Clan had to do the biddings of the Dark Palm Sect. The ones with backing could bully even the strong. If he went out of line he could expect those hidden masters to appear. It was better to just step out and be nice, this new persona that he was using didn’t mean anything to him. If he could avoid conflict by bowing his head, then it would be fine.

“What is this commotion about? You wanted to see this Phantom Demon?”

“Master, we were about to…”

“Be quiet, I heard it all.”

He at least needed to seem like a nascent soul master. It wouldn’t be hard for any of them to overhear the conversation. The core formation guard flinched a bit the moment he saw the master appearing out of the blue. Even though he was trying to keep it together it was clear that this man wasn’t used to this position of power.

“You are, Fang Jingguo?”

“Yes, that's what seems to be the problem, we have come just as the Demon King ordered.”

“You dare?”

“Ah my apologies.”

During the conversation, he made a blunder, for this reason, he decided to perform a little bow towards where the Demon Castle was.

“I should have not mentioned the great Demon King’s name without an honorific. Was that all, can we proceed into the city? I’m sure the Great and wise Demon King doesn’t like to wait. ”

While bowing he made sure to use some of his spiritual energy to envelop the guard. The difference in spiritual energies was just too vast and the man would quickly start to feel uneasy. It wasn’t truly an attack, it was only meant to instill fear into this core formation guard. Luckily it worked and they were quickly accepted into the city after getting some disgraceful looks.

“Ah yes… let them through, everything checks out.”

The man quickly accepted all bribes while also quickly letting the cult into the city. After the old man with the came appeared he started feeling anxious. It was this fear that forced him to hasten the process from which he was hoping to get some more bribes.

‘So this is the City of Demons… looks like a great place to spend your retirement in…’

Zhang Dong wanted to give out a sigh while going through the gate. What he saw behind it was more than he had expected.

Chapter 533

“He’s a dead man…”

“Stop, he might notice, you want him to kill both of us?”

Zhang Dong was looking at the hidden messages between two cult members that were a bit higher on the totem pole. They were now looking at a trembling cultist that was begging for his life. It was the same person that had interacted with the gate patrol and apparently the man he was impersonating would normally be mad. It was due to this person not being able to take care of the situation without the cult leader being involved.

This conversation spying feature was quite handy, he didn’t know people liked to gossip so much when around others that could wipe them out with a fart. He was of course unwilling to just kill a person for trying to do their work. Not like this person was without sin but he still didn’t want to turn into a person that would murder people for no reason.

“Get up you fool, make sure that this doesn’t happen again.”

Thus he just pretended that he was preoccupied with other issues. His gaze was focused on the giant city and the various dark buildings that were mostly made of stone and bricks. The bowing cultist in question was not let off without getting tossed against the ship's wall by his aura though. He at least needed to do the absolute minimum to not give himself away. A few broken bones and collapsed organs would quickly heal for someone as strong as this man.

‘Hm, I think I’ll need to stay with this bunch of murderers for a bit longer. If I split up during the night they will know that I’m some kind of spy quickly…’

The large ship was beginning to dock at a large shipyard with multiple other flying vessels. All of them were hovering in the air and were just connected to the ground by massive chains that were thicker than a grown man’s thigh. Other unsavory demonic cultivators were slowly coming out and heading to various inns.

“This way cult leader.”

Zhang Dong nodded as another cult member appeared to guide him down. It was up to these people to get all the information and take care of all the busy work. It was already paying off that he chose this way of infiltration as he could take a good look at the inside of this grand formation.

‘It’s a layered one, there are multiple barriers with the strongest one being right around that volcano.’

Yet there wasn’t that much that he could do from this vantage point. When the time was right he would need to sneak up to every barrier. Then after interacting with it he would find out the way to disable them. There were several ways of disabling such barriers and it depended on the type it was.

From what he could tell the outer barrier was being supplied with energy by the hexagram of towers. On these, he worked from the outside but he would need to find the corresponding control nodes to truly disable them. When everything was prepared the forcefield would vanish when his troops attacked.

‘That’s the easy part, the harder ones are at the center of the city and that castle, but we can also use brute force.’

There was only so much that he could do in the few days that he had. It was the middle of the day and before it became nighttime he probably couldn’t even head into the city. Yet it didn’t seem that anyone was concerned about safety all that much. There weren’t that many guards and the Chaos Sect was showing off their power. Even now he could see them parading on the streets to forcefully make stronger cultivators appease their hubris.

‘You give them some power and they lose their mind, I wonder if any of them realize that their sect might not exist after a week…’

It was strange to see the people exert their proxy power. Even the nascent soul masters had to keep to themselves, if they killed an important family member of an elder from the strongest sect, they would have a lot of explaining to do. Some of them were also here to join up with the new giant but while they couldn’t attack any sect members from the Chaos Sect, there were other targets.

“What are you looking at?”

“You dare speak to me in that tone? Who are you to block the path of this demon!?”

He could see the guests squaring up against each other. Two groups were looking at each other with animosity in their eyes. Both sides were on edge and probably all that bottled-up rage from bowing to the upstarts was fueling their actions.

‘Are they succumbing to their demonic nature? Some demonic cultivators are said to have things like demonic hearts or physiques that with time drive them insane. It doesn’t look like the guards will lift a finger, they will probably take the loser away later… if there is anything left that is…’

Everyone looked at the group, one side was composed of very muscular-looking individuals that had all sorts of tattoos covering their bodies. The other side on the other hand looked like some gathering of old wizards. Yet even though they were talking smack at each other nothing seemed to come of it.

‘I guess they are just blowing off some steam, no one is stupid enough to start a large brawl right after coming to the city of demons.’

“Cult leader, I have our accommodations ready, please walk this way.”

Finally one of the cult members returned with a piece of paper. On it, he could see an address to some kind of hotel. Probably the rooms were distributed depending on the worth of the strongest person. With him being a middle stage nascent soul cultivator, the hotel would probably not be the best or the worst, something in the middle.

‘This is a peculiar looking place… I hope the rooms are better than the exterior.’

After wandering through the city for around thirty minutes they finally arrived at a large spire. The thing looked like a spiky cactus made from hardened molten lava. It was quite the building that fit the gloomy city filled with murderers and thieves. On the way here he witnessed crimes being performed in broad daylight. The city guards didn’t react even when the citizens were being beaten.

They clearly had no use for the non-cultivators or people with no backing. Only when someone had some sort of token would they come to their aid. It looked like the city was also divided into smaller districts ruled by smaller clans that were similar to criminal gangs. These tokens differed between these districts which were also separated by large walls. Even the building's shape was different and the ruling gang’s characters were plastered everywhere.

‘I thought Wang Long was supposed to have united the city…’

While climbing the tower that looked like it was created in some fetish dungeon he took some time to look everywhere. This area was about in the middle of the outer city. The stronger the faction a person was with the closer to the inner city they were able to stay.

His entourage was forced to rest on the lower levels while he received one whole upper level to himself. Without wanting to bump into any other demonic masters he quickly entered his room and ordered not to be disturbed. This room at first glance didn’t look that bad but after spending time in the Azure Palace and his own well-established sect, this place looked like a dumpster.

Outside his window, he could feel the demonic energy rising in the air. The concentration of Qi was a lot higher here but it was at the level of the lower regions on the mainland. This was probably to a spirit vein existing somewhere in that volcano and being mostly contained to that area.

‘This Qi is also different, it’s corrupted with a strange demonic essence, if a person cultivates with this, they probably won’t be able to learn the usual cultivation methods. There might be a way to alter the vein but that depends on the reason for this corruption.’

While looking out at the setting sun he contemplated the validity of this invasion. When his troops arrived a lot of people would die. Even through the short walk through the city, he could see innocent people just trying to survive. They were just forced to act in a certain way due to their surroundings. Even this spiritual energy that was floating was one of the causes as it would reinforce the more animalistic nature of a human being.

‘I need to stop thinking about this or I’ll never go through with this attack…’

In his mind, it was wrong to just attack without a proper notice. People could then choose to evacuate if they were just civilians. Yet here he wasn’t sure if that would even amount to anything. The lands around the city were barren and filled with many demonic beasts, poison, and soul-sucking phantoms. The people would have more luck trying to wait out the battle instead of fleeing outside of the city.

‘I can only minimize the destruction and focus on that castle…’

Luckily the vast majority of the evil cultivators and their lackeys were in the inner district and the gaudy-looking castle. Even with the barriers in place, he could feel the evil energy radiating from afar. Thus the main plan would be to quickly make their way towards their actual enemies while the citizens fled into the underground.

The city seemed to have a vast expanse of underground tunnels all over the place. It was probably another zone that was even below the outer city in status. While it was populated by the poor it could probably shield everyone from a lot of explosions that would be happening on the outside.

‘That is if they evacuate in time… I guess it’s time to leave, the sun is down.’

While looking out through the window he identified a few points of interest. He had also spotted some of the sects and cults that had arrived wandering through the city. This was also his plan, there was no reason to abandon his disguise if it allowed him to walk through the city. Only when he arrived at the critical locations would he fade into the shadows and get to work.

‘First I need to get to those six nodes that link to the obelisks outside, then I’ll take a look at the inner city formation if I can get past it…’

His eyes gazed upwards towards the active volcano and the castle within. There his enemy resided and it was already hard for him not to just storm the entire place alone. If he could take care of Wang Long himself then no one would have to suffer…

Chapter 534

“You dare go against the Phantom Devil Cult!”

“I dare! Why would our Crimson Fiend Cult be afraid of your little cult?”

“Little? You really have a death wish, brothers to arms!”

‘Why do these things keep happening to me…’

This was supposed to be the easy part of the job. He was already inside the outer city and ready to visit the tourist attractions. First, his attempt of heading out by himself was thwarted by his new cult members. He did not expect some of them to wait in the city even before he already arrived, it was a blunder on his side.

When he was out on the stroll through the night city he was approached by a group of six. They were quick to surround him to scare off the common people and made a large scene before he could even react. This was probably the usual procedure and he wouldn’t be surprised if the real Phantom Demon that he took the body over ordered them to do this.

Of course, this behavior brought over some trouble. His brilliant plan of going into a random restaurant where he would ditch his new entourage backfired. While there they bumped into a rival organization that was supposedly in a prolonged war with their side. Even their leader was here and now both sides were insulting each other.

‘This guy is also a middle stage cultivator.’

The current opponent was slightly stronger than the man that he assassinated to infiltrate the city. Perhaps he had gone through some kind of minor progress in his cultivation method and was feeling confident. From the way the old man was smirking in his direction it looked like he was itching for a fight.

“You look kind of pale,old fart. Maybe you should go back and get some sleep. You should be thoughtful of your age.”

“Ho…”

“A lackey dares to talk to me?”

The person that was the leader was called the Crimson Fiend. His body was large and he didn’t look that old. He was quite muscular but without any definition. Compared to Zhang Dong's more uniform physique he looked like a powerlifter. There was a lot of fat on his body which made him look out of shape.

‘The crimson part probably has to do with all those red tattoos, they look like they were made from blood…’

He had to raise his walking cane to block an attack on one of his new followers. The man jumped in to protect him from being insulted but was somewhat out of line. A junior could not just raise his voice against a powerful cult Patriarch.

This was quite risky, with the newfound Dao’s he was somewhat able to mask his Qi to imitate the corrupted one. However, he would not be able to do it if he attempted to use one of his granted techniques. Unless he limited his own battle prowess there was a possibility of being identified as an orthodox cultivator with pure Qi.

“What does a man that called his cult by his stupid name want with me? Go away, I’m busy, how about you save some of that energy for when you meet the Demon King.”

“What’s that supposed to mean, you old crow?”

“I don’t know, how about you use that empty head of yours for a change?”

Zhang Dong still was not sure about the way this old demonic cultivator would talk. He could only assume that he would be irritated with the provocation and throw a few insults back. Yet while looking around he might have made a mistake. The people that were with the Crimson Fiend were taken back while the ones from his side were in awe.

‘Wait… was this old fart the type to talk shit only when weaker people are around him? Maybe he turns into the silent type when around people at the same level as him?’

This wasn’t a bad assumption as the Crimson Fiend looked surprised as well. Perhaps the Phantom Cult leader would just ignore the obvious provocation as he wasn’t willing to risk a battle breaking out. As an old person, he would probably be able to judge his opponent's character to an extent that Zhang Dong wasn’t able to in this case. The large man looked like an irritable kind but he at least thought that the two had a history of insulting each other.

“You old fart, you think I’ll just let you insult me to my face, in front of all of these people? Have you gone senile?”

The demonic cultivator was not backing down but if he lowered his head then he might not be able to come out of this unscathed. In this city showing weakness was a sin and he wasn’t sure if this musclebound idiot wouldn’t attack him if he indicated any type of fear. If he stood his ground and showed that he was confident in his power then the other man should just back away.

‘This is hard… how do you tell someone to screw off without offending them too much?’

Zhang Dong was not the best at diplomacy, most of the time he was the person with the biggest fist. This reminded him of the earliest goof that he created with the Dark Palm Sect when he didn’t bow before their envoy. While he was not in danger of losing his life here it would hamper his mission if he got in trouble.

“You insulted me, so I’ve insulted you back, why can’t you understand a simple thing like that? Now that you do, go away. I don't have the time to argue with you.”

‘There I didn’t even call him any bad names… he should be content at leaving it, right?’

Zhang Dong wasn’t really afraid of losing to this blockhead but there were a lot of eyes on him. The priority was to get out of here without a fight breaking out. It was possible to knock out the bulky Crimson Fiend with one punch but then he would probably get some strange looks from the peanut gallery here. There were also hidden masters everywhere, their allegiance was neutral at best and if they saw an opportunity they would take it.

“Hey, where are you going, I’m not finished with you.”

“As you said earlier, this old man needs his beauty sleep, so you can have this place all to yourself.”

‘There, I’ll just make some fun of myself to make him feel better.’

He could hear some of the people from his side chuckling while the other side was getting madder. Yet he was already making his way out of this restaurant, there was no reason for that idiot to push it. There was no reason to start an unsanctioned fight in the middle of nowhere. Without the permission of the Chaos Sect that ruled it would be a slap to their face if two outside factions engaged in warfare on their territory.

“Y-you… I challenge you to true death combat!”

“W-what did he say?”

“True Death?”

“Is he out of his mind?”

Zhang Dong’s face remained behind the hood of his robe. He was not sure what this true death combat thing was but it didn’t seem that it was a good idea. From the name, he could only speculate that the things at risk were their nascent divinities. If one side lost they would die and be erased from the face of the planet. Perhaps they would even be turned into blood crystals for the other party to absorb.

“Are you drunk Crimson Fiend? What nonsense are you spouting?”

“What old crow, did you think I wouldn’t have the guts? Come, face me if you dare!”

‘This idiot is really confident for some reason, there might be more to this than meets the eye…’

Zhang Dong didn’t like how this man just pushed for a death duel. It was quite an unreasonable request, one that a demonic cultivator would normally never take. There was a possibility of some outside help or a secret that let this man be confident in victory. Could the man that he was impersonating be weakening? Maybe he had some kind of condition that this Crimson Fiend was aware of?

‘This guy was awfully easy to kill for a middle stage cultivator… perhaps his age was really getting to him?’
That was the simplest explanation and probably also true. This Phantom Demon was really old, perhaps even over a thousand years old. People that were adept at soul-related techniques were always good at prolonging their life. This might have been the case, Crimson Fiend was slightly stronger and had a powerful body. On the other hand, Phantom Demon only could utilize his phantom arts while his body was in a bad state of slow decay.

‘He could also have some kind of treasure to counter his nemesis, perhaps this had been already planned beforehand and he was just looking for an excuse…’

“Why should I listen to the prattling of a madman? Go fight a cow if you want.”

There was no reason to save his nonexistent face. The man he was impersonating would quickly disappear after he removed his disguise. Even if they laughed at him he didn’t care, what he was here for was the mission. Also if he used the right words he could simply weasel out of it. The other old monster would probably see through the strange act of the Crimson Fiend and applaud him for seeing through it.

“Are you afraid?”

“No, I’m just not a buffoon like you!”

“Hah, this was getting interesting old man, why did you have to spoil the fun? This won’t do, I even prepared an arena already…”

Suddenly one of the hidden masters made himself known. It was a man at the late stage of the nascent soul level. His face looked serpentlike and his eyes were quite narrow to the point of seemingly being closed. Just as he had expected there was some kind of ruse here and this person was responsible. Normally that would be it but there was a problem, the robe that he was wearing belonged to the Chaos Sect.

“How are you going to make it up to me, you two? I have invested good crystals into all of this.”

The man appeared next to the Crimson Fiend that moved his head to the side. It was strange to see this meat monster acting like a little mouse when approached by a predator. Yet even Zhang Dong needed to be careful as he could not just ignore someone from the Chaos Sect. If he conducted himself in an improper fashion then they would have an excuse to restrain him, or even attack.

‘It’s fine… this is going to be the last infiltration mission that I take part in…’

While giving out a sigh he prepared himself for the worst. If he played his cards right then there might be a way to smooth things with this snake bastard. Bribing was always an option and he didn’t care much about the belongings that he lifted from the cult leader. The big question is, if this man was willing to listen or if he already decided their fate…

Chapter 535

‘Why does it always have to be some kind of arena?’

Zhang Dong found himself walking into an underground crime den that was in possession of a huge battle arena. The city that was already huge and housed multiple off millions of people also had a vast array of underground tunnels and structures.

It hadn’t been long since they left the restaurant in which he got into a verbal argument with Crimson Fiend. It was clear that this rather musclebound idiot was planning to kill the Phantom Demon that he was impersonating. It seemed that he even had some kind of agreement with the Chaos Sect member that pulled him towards this deathmatch.

He wasn’t left with much of a choice as the man wouldn’t take a no for an answer. There was a point at which Zhang Dong could not refuse. The other party could call in more support from their sect and even attack him if they wanted. At that point, his cover would be blown as he could not risk going to their version of prison. Crimson Fiend that was part of this charade was grinning through the entire thing and now both of them were slowly floating to the center of the ring.

“Ladies and Gentlemen, my name is Li Zhong and today we will see a very special bout between two masters. They have been at each other's throats for hundreds of years and today one of them will finally fall!”

The man from the Chaos Sect revealed his name while announcing the sides. His face was truly something that should belong to a snake. It wasn’t just a mirage; there was probably some kind of beast bloodline running in his veins. Zhang Dong could tell that it was due to a body refining technique that made him somewhat similar to some of the demi-humans he faced not so long ago.

“Are you mad old Phantom? Did you really think I wouldn’t get to you eventually?”

The man that looked like a strongman was standing before him with a large oversized hammer over his shoulder. The face of the hammer was wider than his entire head and would probably decimate a regular person from the weight only. It was clearly a heavenly treasure that was radiating some kind of bloody aura.

‘The weapon absorbs blood to get stronger? I guess it's a fitting weapon for a meathead like that.’

Zhang Dong didn’t reply as he just scanned the surroundings for potential trouble. The snake-like man was a nascent soul master at around the level of the Crimson Fiend. It wouldn’t be surprising if he decided to jump in to help his ally if something went wrong. There were also two early stage nascent soul masters that barely made the cut, probably some people that the Li Zhong trained as they had similar features.

‘His disciples? Would they jump in if the Phantom Demon started winning? How much of my power should I use…’

The silence that Zhang Dong gave Crimson Fiend only made the cultivator fume with rage. From his perspective, it looked like the old man was not taking him seriously. This wasn’t that far off as Zhang Dong didn’t think any of these people were his opponents. The only problem was that he couldn’t just attack people from the Chaos Sect. If they jumped in to save their friend and he killed all of them, then his infiltration mission would end.

‘I guess I’ll need to make this fast and not give them a chance to interfere…’

His original plan was to prolong the fight to not raise brows. Yet if he took too long in defeating Crimson Fiend then there was no telling of what the other party would do. There were some attacking formations on this ring that could be activated or they could be in possession of hidden treasures with curses. It wouldn’t be hard for masters to perform hidden attacks without giving themselves away.

‘I bet they will try to attack me if this idiot starts to lose…’

“You won’t be able to keep that smile on for long!”

The angered Crimson Fiend looked towards the announcer that was taking his sweet time. These two weren’t even trying to hide the fact that they were working together. Soon the snake nodded and made the announcement.

“I see that the Crimson Fiend is getting impatient, the bets will be closed. Let us start with the match!”

‘They won’t even ask me if I’m ready huh? I guess I’ll need to make a spectacle of this so that they won’t seek me out for more trouble… Not like it's impossible for old farts to progress further… luckily I came prepared.’

Zhang Dong expected things to go wrong and for this occasion, he had made a few treasures. The demi-humans were quite the source of weaponry as their bodies were in a sense high quality treasures. With the help of some of the commanding officer's bones, he had created a fitting weapon for someone like the Phantom Demon to use. It wasn’t the only one that he created but this fit his current persona the most.

The match started with a smack to a loud gong. The moment the battle was on he pulled out something that looked like a staff made from human bones. Its top part had a skull with a large protruding horn. It belonged to one of the tribe leaders that his sect had slain and it could produce several effects.

“That’s not going to help you! Now die old fart!”

“Idiots that charge in never live long lives…”

Demonic cultivators normally weren’t fools but the more they progressed through the ranks the more they were consumed by hubris. Even though they should be aware of their own deficiencies they tended to overestimate themselves if they were convinced of their superiority. This was the case during this clash, the man charging at him was assured of his victory.

From the sides, he could feel the gazes of many people but the ones that he was paying attention to were the two nascent soul masters. With his current level, he could tell that they were waiting for something. Their auras were already quickly rising as they were up to no good.

The man that was charging at him expanded in size. His entire body which was a mix of fat and muscle became a lot more muscular than before. With the increase in size came a side effect of his skin turning crimson. In a matter of moments, the man didn’t look like a human anymore and was more similar to a devil with a complete set of black horns.

‘So that’s why they call him the Crimson Fiend?’

The demonic energy around the man became really thick and quickly filled the entire area. Black smoke that looked like volcanic ash started blocking out the view. This was certainly all a ploy to allow his allies to act as it didn’t take long for them to launch their hidden techniques toward Zhang Dong’s location.

‘Transparent needles coated in paralyzing venom?’

To block this attack he just raised the occult-looking staff that was in his right hand. A shroud of green flames surrounded his entire body that halted the needles from connecting with his neck. They were quite small and made from expensive materials but his enemy seems to be waiting for this opportunity.

Perhaps this hidden attack was not meant to work but just took the focus of the Crimson Fiend that was already swinging the giant hammer down on his body. If the weapon connected there would be nothing left of the man once known as the Phantom Demon. Yet no one could have known that the old man was already dead and they were fighting someone that was far more deadly.

From within the gray shroud, the man that looked like a red demon emerged. His body looked like it was burning up as a small number of fire elements gathered. His target was the decrepit old man with the staff that looked like he would collapse at the smallest tap.

Yet suddenly a ferocious mass of green flames erupted. These flames did not burn the flesh, no instead they aimed at the core of what this Crimson Fiend was made of, his eternal soul. The man was in shock, it was as if he was separated into two existences the moment the burst of green energy collided with his body.

The Crimson Fiend could see his body moving forward while his spirit remained behind. He knew that the Phantom Demon was versed in wielding wraiths and creatures like phantoms but he did not expect him to be able to directly affect his nascent divinity. This one attack of his was capable of separating it from his main body that without it around was just a mindless husk.

It continued to perform the last action that his brain sent but instead of colliding with the old demon it just clobbered the rocky ground. The entire place shook along with the audience which was mostly unaware of what was happening.

A loud shrieking sound escaped from the blast of green flames that turned into ferocious demonic skulls. This sound was coming from above and the audience finally noticed what had transpired. When they looked they could see the Crimson Fiend’s nascent divinity being ravaged by these green phantoms that were clearly produced by the decrepit old man.

Zhang Dong was floating to the side as he left an afterimage behind in the spot the hammer hit. To others, it looked like it was some kind of phantom but he only utilized his astonishing speed that even a late stage nascent soul master would not be able to fathom.

His Dao of the Soul was a higher form than the one that Phantom Demon was using. While he could not truly summon demonic phantoms that would eat up his opponent's nascent divinity he could produce a similar effect. Only a person that was efficient in the Dao of the Souls would be able to see through this ruse. Yet there was no one like that here, to them it looked like the demonic green ghosts were just eating up a defenseless Crimson Fiend.

“Was this what you wanted to show me, Crimson Fiend? I am not impressed…”

Zhang Dong watched as the simulated phantoms devoured the soul while he used other ways to apprehend that nascent divinity along with the increase in his understanding of the demonic Dao.

“Hm, shouldn’t you announce the winner, young man?”

He called out to the Chaos Sect member that could not understand the situation that unfolded before him.

“...”

After his victory, he returned down to the ground where the intact body of the Crimson Fiend resided. It looked like the large man was just sleeping as there were no visible injuries. Without a nascent divinity or his soul, it was just an empty shell of his former existence. The only use for him now was turning it into blood crystals…

Chapter 536

“The winner is… Phantom Demon…”

“If this is all then I will excuse myself. I will also offer the remains of the Crimson Fiend to the wonderful host.”

Zhang Dong in his disguise performed a little two-handed clasp while slowly removing himself from the arena. His winning came as a shock to almost everyone here and mostly to the man that looked like a snake. There was nothing he could say though as the win was achieved fair and square. Also by giving up on the blood crystals that could be harvested from Crimson Fiend’s corpse he was showing his allegiance to the Chaos Sect.

“Brother Phantom, you have truly shown me something interesting today, I will gladly accept this offering…”

The man just nodded while the two nascent soul masters that threw poison needles toward him moved closer. Both of them were wearing black hoods over their faces but he could clearly tell that they were weary of him. All three knew that this old man before them wasn’t that simple and they had attacked him already.

‘It wouldn’t be strange if they attacked me now… but I bet they still believe that I won’t cause them any harm while in this city…’

Normally a fight would ensue as they had tried to kill him and he was aware of it. They also saw him repel the poison needles but for the time being, he needed to show proper decorum. This was the fate of people with less backing, even if another party was weaker they could not fully act against them. At most he could give them a slap or two to assert his dominance but leaving it like this allowed the other party to save face.

“My old bones are tired, I will have to rest.”

Zhang Dong was left alone for now but in the future, it wouldn’t be strange if the person called Phantom Demon got assassinated. The other party created a grudge that demonic cultivators liked to hold on to. All of them knew that if the power dynamic shifted then the people from the Chaos Sect would find themselves being chased down by the green phantoms.

‘They are letting me go for now at least… it wouldn’t be strange if in a few days they try organizing something though…’

There was no one stopping him as people moved their heads down as he floated towards his current cult members. The people from his own cult were quite surprised at the increase of people of their own master. Perhaps some of them were slowly realizing that there was something fishy. Then there was the danger of him being assassinated by the snake cultivator. The longer he remained in the city the harder it would be for him to act.

“All of you return to the hotel, I need to take care of a few things.”

“Cult Leader?”
The main servant looked toward him as if he wanted to say something but after one glare he slumped his head down. He would not allow this chance to get away from him. This was the time to sink away into the darkness of the night and sabotage the protective formation from within.

Thus the moment he found himself in a more secluded location he sank into the shadows. His face was already known but not like he needed to worry about being stopped by anyone. Word of his overbearing victory would probably reach the ears of other similar sects. They would probably keep their distance due to the spike in the power of the person called Phantom Demon. Everyone would have to re-evaluate his potential before approaching him again.

“...”

‘That’s about it and not too soon…’

Zhang Dong stepped out of an empty alley that was occupied by a rotting corpse. This was not of his doing as he had just used this passage to get back into the city. Only now when he was alone and going through these streets did he realize how bad of a state this place truly was in.

Only the main streets through which large clans or powerful cults went through were in a presentable state. Everything else looked worse than the slums that he remembered from all the cities he visited in the Empire. He was someone that liked to wander through his own city to see how his citizens were living so this was quite shocking.

‘Does that bastard's faction system not show him the state that this place is in?’

This was the big question, his points would plummet if he started treating his people like garbage. Only if the approval rating and happiness of his people were above a certain threshold would he be able to gain anything out of it. It didn’t look like Wang Long had the same problem which could originate from their personalities.

‘This system tends to change itself depending on the user…’

There was one explanation for the difference. While he wanted to play the good guy and help the people, Wang Long was the opposite. His system gave him a faction that he could nurture by good deeds. Wang Long on the other hand probably received the reverse of it, the more miserable his people were then the more power he acquired.

‘Maybe he gains points if people worship him instead of liking him?’

While Zhang Dong was receiving his own kind of worship it was more of the positive kind. It wouldn’t be that strange if Wang Long was supposed to be his opposite, an evil god that his people feared. It was a different kind of fanaticism that could be troublesome to deal with

The people that his side would be going up against were backed up against a wall filled with spikes. They probably didn’t really want to fight but the fear of death by the new Demon King was too strong. In their eyes, it was more likely to come out alive if they followed orders instead of trying to flee.

‘Yet if I manage to break their belief in their leader then they should quickly flee…’

While there were positives in using fear like desperation to survive there was a big drawback. If the faction led like this saw their leaders failing they would quickly abandon them. If they saw a way out of their predicament they would certainly take a chance to flee or even join the battle against their oppressor. It wasn’t strange when despots got stabbed in the back in their time of need.

‘I guess that just means that I need to quickly win that one-on-one to end this war quickly but will that guy be as stupid like last time?’

Zhang Dong looked back towards the remains and with a swipe of his hand set them ablaze. While watching the flames fill the dark alley he began to worry more. It would be fine if he could just end it all with just one fight but he had to consider other possibilities. Wang Long could tackle everything in many ways and there was also a chance that his enemy had become a lot stronger than before. He had rushed here but this didn’t mean that Wang Long couldn’t have gotten enough spirit points to reach new never before seen heights.

‘That takes care of the outer city, should I stay for that assembly or just cut my losses now…’

He was slowly returning to the hotel that he should be occupying without revealing his face. It wouldn’t be hard to escape from this place as the outer barrier had been altered from both sides by him and he could move out without a problem. The days in these demonic lands were mostly cloudy and shrouded in shade which made concealing techniques easy to use.

‘I should first confirm what I already know before making a decision…’

Within a few moments, he traversed the city’s shadowy alleys without anyone being the wiser. Even slipping back into the hotel he was occupying went unnoticed. Ever since his battle with the Crimson Fiend, he noticed an increase in guards and Chaos Sect presence. The snake bastard that started this farce was clearly watching his moves. Luckily the sentries he had sent weren’t all that great and he would be able to evade their gazes with a few easy tricks.

“Cult Leader, you called for me?”

“Yes, explain to me again, when will the assembly take place and when will we be allowed to enter the inner city.”

“Yes, Cult Leader! We will be able to enter the inner city in three days, the Chaos Sect will…”

While listening he confirmed the information that he already knew. The gathering of demonic cultivators would take place in the inner city in one of the old main sect buildings. This one had been taken over by the Chaos Sect that was now in power but used to belong to one of the other demons that was now dead.

The old buildings were trashed during the takeover but were quickly rebuilt within a few weeks following it. Everyone seemed to work quite fast when they were fearing for their life. Apparently, some of the builders had been killed to motivate the others that didn’t sleep all that well through the entire procedure.

This meant that he would not be entering the Demon King castle. Instead it would be hosted in the new inner sect courtyard where the announcement took place. Even these cultists had no idea what would happen. The man that he was talking to had given him some concerning information.

“That is all, you can leave, call me when the time to enter the inner city comes.”

“I obey, Cult Leader!”

The man left quickly which caused Zhang Dong to ponder his next move. Infiltrating further into the fortified sect was quite risky. For the time being, he was safe but the closer he got to Wang Long the more probable his discovery became. There was a possibility of him not being able to teleport out to safety even with a large number of points. If he was forced to engage his opponent on his home turf then he would probably be as good as dead.

‘The whole plan could go down the drain if I’m too cocky… it would be better to not push my luck anymore…’

It was the smart and more logical thing to do. He already was able to examine the inner city's barrier which would also help during the attack. Yet it still wouldn’t be easy and a lot of his own people might have to give their life for the cause. His somewhat inflated sense of justice and drive to save lives was somewhat pushing him to risk his own life instead of the sect members that he built up.

‘If I survive this then my wife will probably kill me herself…’

Chapter 537

“Is everything ready?”

“Yes, Matriarch… but are you sure that you should be here? The Patriarch gave orders that you should remain in the main sect…”

Zhang Liena looked at a somewhat nervous-looking Zhang Kuo who wasn’t sure what to say. The lady he was talking to was not someone he could control, only her husband had the leisure to give her orders. Even the second most powerful person Huo Qiang was just shrugging while Kuo tried to seek some aid.

“I will do no such thing!”

“Ah, yes Matriarch…”

“Haha, you’re scaring him, Liena.”

“Grandfather?”

Zhang Jin was also here and so were many other nascent soul cultivators and members of the United Element Sect. All of them were gathered here for the coming war but they were a bit ahead of the schedule their leader had prepared for them.

“Elders, the Patriarch has given us specific orders. Are you willing to break them?”

“Zhi, stop pretending you’re probably itching to aid our glorious leader the most, if it weren’t for that silly sense of duty of yours you’d have stormed that city already.”

Huo Qiang laughed while smacking Zhang Zhi on the back.

“Just give it up, we are going to go ahead with the plan if you want it or not…”

Zhi looked towards all the other nascent soul masters that were in this meeting room. Even if it went against his beliefs he couldn’t deny the fact. What these people were doing was something that he had to agree with. Their judgment was correct and this was probably the best way to serve the Patriarch, even if they all got punished in the end.

“Well then, if we all agree, let’s continue with the meeting.”

Zhang Kuo nodded while pointing to the holographic map. There all of them could see the barriers and monoliths with the beasts inside. It was something produced by their leader that had decided to scout out the area like a footsoldier.

“As you might know the last time the Patriarch contacted us was a few days ago, if we go by the schedule the grand assembly that will include all of the Chaos Sect elders and the Demon King will take place in just a day…”

…

‘So far so good…’

“Next!”

The guard to the inner city looked at his credentials and after some eyeballing allowed him and his group of cult members to go through. This time around though he was only allowed to bring five people in at most. The rest would have to wait in the outer city for his return. This was quite a dangerous feat as the minor cult members would have a hard time defending themselves from any Chaos Sect outer disciples.

‘Are they really going to try something drastic? This doesn’t look that well for me or all the others…’

Some of the nascent soul masters complained as they were not allowed to bring in certain weapons or people. Zhang Dong had to use a special technique to hide the contents of his spatial ring as well as have Bob shield him from any outside system scanning.

The inner city was surrounded by a huge gate and four even larger gates. A person could only enter through them and only if a person from the inside opened the way for them. Even a nascent soul master would not be able to break through from the sky as an invisible force field surrounded everything.

Yet now he was on the inside and his brain was already working on a way of getting through these defenses. This one wasn’t as easy as the other one but as always there were ways to get around everything. In each gate resided a nascent soul presence and with their authority, the guards were able to open and close the gates.

Thus the first way of getting around this defensive barrier would be to rob these four masters of their gate-opening privilege or somehow copy it. Yet this was probably not something that would work in the long run. It wouldn’t be strange if this privilege could be stripped by the sect leader within a moment of a fight breaking out.

He could also try going to the source of the formation that was directly inside of the sect they were going to be attending. In there he would probably find the main control unit of the formation. These huge barriers always needed some kind of power source so if he wasn’t able to overwrite the array he could always try destroying its source.

‘I will only know when I get there…’

Time was slowly running out for him as the closer to the day of the assembly the more in danger he was. Even if he wasn’t discovered he didn’t think that this gathering of masters was anything favorable. There was a possibility that nothing would happen to him and he would just have to swear allegiance to the new master.

‘A soul curse is more likely though… it might be possible to resist it though.’

The most likely scenario that would play out was some kind of slave contract between the current sect. They were the only superpower with no enemies around them. To solidify their rule the next move would be to get all the nascent soul masters on their side. The Demons would not join them for no reason though as all these evil cultivators were quite prideful. Only if their lives were threatened would they change their allegiance.

“Cult leader, our accommodations are this way.”

“Mhm.”

He just nodded as his attendant guided him in the direction of the main sect. The state of this city was a lot better than the slums on the outside. There was actual order here and people seemed to be conducting themselves in a proper manner. The demonic energy was still strong here, even though they were trying to hide it there were certain spots filled with murderous Qi.

‘I guess the biggest difference is that they clean up after committing a murder…’

For someone of his caliber, he could tell. There were areas that had been patched up but marks of conflict were visible. Even if all signs of blood and gore could be wiped clean the lingering souls of the deceased weren’t that easy to get rid of. Some of their spiteful energies continued to fester in a few spots.

Luckily he could not see the snake-like person that he had a run in a few days ago. Even without him, Zhang Dong noticed that some eyes were on him. His quick victory over someone that was ranked at a similar rank probably raised some eyebrows.

A lot of people were probably wondering how such an old fart like him could have increased his power without giving it away. The demonic masters prided themselves in having an extensive spy network. The person with information and backing was always the one that was victorious. In all likelihood, if he didn’t replace the old man the Crimson Demon would have attained victory.

‘The way they are looking at me… this isn’t necessarily a bad thing…’

To test out his claim his head quickly turned to the left where one of his supposed new fans was trying to measure his power. The person looked like a young woman but the aura she was giving off seemed to put her somewhere over half a millennium in age.

“What do you want?”

“No… I…. excuse me.”

The granny that was somehow able to keep her youthful appearance panicked, bowed, and quickly escaped his gaze. The other masters that were in the area followed suit out of fright. It was clear that Zhang Dong, who was impersonating the old man, was dangerous. Thanks to this he would probably be able to evade a lot of potential drama and discourse.

‘At least they won’t seek trouble with me, they are unsure of the Phantom Demon’s true power now, they won’t risk it.’
This would give him some freedom against the other strong demons but would probably not work against the Chaos Sect masters. Those would probably be less scared of any backlash of prodding the old fart. Yet even they wouldn’t go overboard as angering a demonic master of this caliber was never a good thing.

“I’ll call for you if there is a need.”

“Yes, Cult Leader.”

This time around they were organized in larger more pristine buildings and not a huge hotel. There weren’t really that many powerful demonic masters here. Together with him, there were only twenty, not really such a large force. However considering that they were all demonic cultivators and in one specific location, this was already a huge force.

‘Well then, I should think about my next move. Bob, are you sure that Wang Long won’t be able to see me?’

‘Discovery is possible, the user must stay out of the range of the other system user by approximately twenty-five meters.’

‘I’m not sure if that’s close or far…’

If Wang Long kept to himself and didn’t interact with the demonic cultivators then he would be safe. Yet if he decided to shake everyone's hand or even come closer to where he was at then his cover would be blown.

‘Perhaps it would be better to not go to that meeting… but would sending one of the cult members in my place work?’

He didn’t have any techniques that could produce clones of himself but he could change the aura and appearance of other people. There were five cult members with him and they were at least loyal to him. One of them could take his place in the assembly while he used this time to go through the encampment. This would be a one-way mission as he would be abandoning this place after he got to the barrier.

‘It’s risky but going somewhere where all the old demonic monsters gather is even riskier…’

Thus he hatched the plan for the next day. After calling over one of the core formation cult members that was closest to his height he began with an explanation.

“You wish for me to take your place, cult leader?”

“That’s right, you don’t really think we can trust these Chaos Sect members, do you?”

“But what if they discover it…”

“Don’t worry they won’t, your disguise will be perfect, not even the Demon King himself will be able to see through it.”

The cult member nodded but he wasn’t quite convinced. Luckily the fear he felt towards this old man Zhang Dong was impersonating was greater. There were of course soul binding spells keeping him in check as well. At least that is what this person thought as this curse would have vanished after the Phantom Demon had died.

“Good, now stay still, this might feel strange but bare with it.”

Finally, the time to act was almost there. The last mission to take down the barrier and then perform the surprise attack was upon him.

Chapter 538

‘I don’t think they are expecting any trouble, the security here is worse than in some mid-sized sects.’

After spending some time in the inner city the time for the assembly of demons was upon him. While the others that came here were forced to attend it he decided to do something else. Instead of going himself, he had transformed one of the cultists into the older man he was impersonating.

The disguise was intricate and probably no one would be able to discover the foul play that was taking place. No one actually was that close to the Phantom Demon, the cultist that was acting as him already knew all of the mannerisms his Patriarch had. This person could probably do a better job impersonating the cult leader than Zhang Dong could.

To augment the core formation cultist’s power he lent him a few treasures that would allow him to exude a nascent soul-like aura. Not many people would be able to tell that it was coming from the treasures instead of his own nascent soul. Before anyone would, he was planning to already be done with his mission.

“Into the closet, you go…”

After shoving one of the guards into a cramped space and taking his clothes, he changed into a new disguise. This already felt better as he didn’t need to walk awkwardly as a decrepit old man with a bad back. It was one of the guards patrolling this large sect compound and someone that was allowed to get close to his next destination, the treasure powering the grand array.

From the outside, this looked like the usual sect palace filled with various golden patterns. He wasn’t sure why all of these people liked to flaunt their wealth and decorate everything like this. Even the cultivators of the demonic variety liked to put dragons and flying fish on the walls just with more black here and there.

The layout was very similar to all the other fortresses to the point of making them look like they were being copy pasted. Perhaps there were just a few working variants that were considered the best and everyone just made a slight variation to it. Thanks to this he knew that what he was looking for was in the lower areas of this compound.

With the help of his system map, he could tell that this place had a spacious underground. He could feel a faint tint of corrupted Qi coming from below that was being hidden from people with a lesser spiritual sense. But he could tell that if he manages to go through one of those closed gates that he would arrive closer to his destination.

“Greetings, Senior.”

“Open up the gate.”

Before him, there were two guards but luckily for him, he had turned into someone that was in a higher position. Thanks to this they could only bow with their heads while opening. Even if they found something odd with this situation they couldn’t really call him out on it. The demonic cultivators were really overbearing to the point of killing people below them for the faintest transgression. They were gambling with their lives if they asked him about his reason for being here which they were unwilling to do.

This large gate was already in a more secluded location that was kept hidden away from the nascent soul demons. It had a strange demonic dragon that looked like some kind of phantom than the usual serpent type he was used to seeing. There were signs of rebuilding so perhaps this was something that was decided on by their new leader.

The doors slammed open without creaking too much as everything looked to be brand new. On the inside, he was greeted by more people that were wearing similar robes. This was in reality one of the entrances to the core sect region. There were various disciples wandering around with their chests puffed out as if they owned the place.

Yet it wasn’t all pleasant, after a few steps he heard some shouting. The disciples weren’t the only ones here, there were also various servants that were tending to their needs. Just as he was passing by one of them was getting kicked around by an angry young master. There didn’t seem to be a good reason for this and a group of two other young lordlings was grinning not far from there while their servants remained quiet.

‘Is this some kind of way they go about their stress levels?’

At first, he thought the young man delivering the beating was angry but soon his furrowed brows shot up and were accompanied by a grin. He was clearly enjoying himself and the person that he was hitting was even of a higher cultivation level than he was. Most of the time the servant was also a bodyguard.

“Learn your place! How dare you embarrass me and lose! What good of a dog are you if you can’t even perform?”

“Please y-young master, show mercy.”

While he didn’t like what was happening here this was not his fight. The commotion was actually a blessing in disguise as it brought everyone's attention to the beaten servant. With the help of this young master he went unnoticed and was able to delve deeper into this underground inner sect.

There was a whole new biome down here. The space was vast and out in the distance, there was something like a miniature sun. This place wasn’t as extravagant as the dimensional regalia but it could still house tens of thousands of people without there being worry of running out of space.

‘So they are living lavishly here while the rest of the people on the island struggle?’

This place was comparable to larger sects. There were lush forests and even herb gardens along with small lakes with high-quality water. Everything that a disciple could need to advance was here. The only difference was the type of Qi that filled out this area. It was somewhat affecting the plants giving some of them monstrous traits.
‘The Evil Qi is stronger here but the source should be there…’

Just like the palace above, there was another castle right here. This one was occupied by some rather unsavory individuals that were radiating massive amounts of demonic Qi. It was actually surprising, he did not expect that many experts to be still here after they were supposedly cleansed by Wang Long and his forces.

‘Perhaps they aren’t here by their own volition? There is something peculiar about their souls but I won’t know for sure until I get closer…’

While still using his hiding technique he tried to identify the robes of the people here. The one he grabbed from the guard would probably do him no good here. He needed to get his hands on one that would allow him to get into the innermost secret chambers of this Chaos Sect.

This wouldn’t be such an easy endeavor as realistically speaking only a nascent soul master would be able to get in. While Zhang Dong was strong it would still be risky to take a person like them out. He was lucky enough when the Phantom Demon decided to separate from his ship but here there were more eyes everywhere. A spike in spiritual energy or him putting up a shield to hide it could be noticed.

‘There isn’t much time left, I only have half a day until Wang Long comes here, it would be better to get out before that happens…’

There was of course another way that didn’t require killing anyone. Either he could just sneak in while wearing his current attire and hope for the best or take the form of someone that was busy. There were probably many senior disciples and elders that were in secluded cultivation that could be used for this tactic. The problem was figuring out which one of them would be able to get the closest to his destination without causing the ire of others.

While this area was the inner sect the ones he needed to go to was for the core members. For that, he would either need to take on the form of one of the masters or disciples. Yet there was also a third option. He remembered the scene that occurred when he first appeared here, a lot of servants were living together with their masters, and it would be possible to sneak in if he took on the form of one of them.

‘That’s probably the safest option considering their power…’

It would be much easier to knock out a servant than a core disciple or an elder. They would probably be situated in areas that weren’t monitored by anyone as their worth wasn’t all that great. This took him to a large structure that looked like an inn.

‘A lot of these people are under the effect of curses that aren’t active, they must be the servants.’

Of course, demonic cultivators wouldn’t trust anyone. Thus their servants would be forced to agree to a slave contract on their souls or die. From what he heard this could even happen without them agreeing when they were weak and young. Such a servant would slowly be groomed into bodyguards that would have to forfeit their life for their owners if they ordered them to.

‘Let’s see, is there anyone or should I just try something else.”

Zhang Dong listened in on the various conversations that the people here were having. With his enhanced hearing and cultivation he could somewhat separate his attention between the various groups. What he was looking for is someone that was on some kind of errand and after a moment he found him.

“Here, don’t forget to be quick, you know that the young master doesn’t like to be kept waiting!”

“I know…”

There was a servant doing delivery of some sorts. He was handed a spatial ring along with some kind of talisman. This he had seen being carried by other people around this sect. It was probably an identification table that would allow him to pass through some of the checkpoints.

‘I guess this guy is as good as any…’

The plan was simple. First, he waited for the man that looked to be in his mid-thirties to leave the servant quarters. When he was walking through one of the more secluded locations he made his move. Within a second his target was knocked out and stripped of his clothes. To keep his body hidden his dimensional regalia replica was used. If no one was able to find the original servant then his disguise would be almost perfect.

‘Hm… demonic qi reinforcement pills and some shitty techniques, this young muster can’t be much higher than a foundation establishment junior…’

With everything in place he left the hidden alley and headed for the large core sect building in the distance. With some luck, he would be able to just get in and quickly take care of his task. In reality, he wasn’t even planning to interact with the servant. Even if the young master came searching for him Zhang Dong would be long gone, the time to end this infiltration had begun.

Chapter 539

‘I should have practiced this mimic skill a bit more…’

Zhang Dong was making his way through the inner Chaos Sect while in his new disguise. This time around he was a man that looked to be around forty. In reality, this person was closer to a hundred and only a foundation establishment late stage practitioner. With his advanced age it would be quite hard to reach the core formation stage as the older a person got, the harder this became.

‘Perhaps that’s why he is only a servant? He would have a better life in some of the lower regions where core formation is rare…’

His new disguise was a bit problematic as he couldn’t even fly on a sword to his destination. Yet before he exchanged himself for this person the servant was keeping up a fast pace. Probably if he delivered these pills and scrips slowly he would receive punishment.

‘I just need to get in and find a core disciple to impersonate.’

Zhang Dong’s main concern was reaching the thing that powered the formation. His current disguise along with the identification plaque that he got from the unfortunate servant would allow him to progress further inside. From his experience, the hard part was getting through a checkpoint but once in it wouldn’t be that hard to move around.

Core sect elders were mostly trying to prolong their life and get to the next level so they didn’t pay that much attention to what was happening outside. Their disciples were even more focused on progressing their techniques as their growth was more palpable. They would certainly not be that quick to investigate servants running around as there were other things to be done.

“Did he send you out for another errand, Liu Chen?”

“Ah, yes…”

Zhang Dong approached the gate and was surprised that one of the guards knew who he was. There was a certain look of pity in the man’s eyes when he looked his way. This probably meant that Liu Chen, who he was impersonating, didn't have an easy life.

When he knocked out the servant there were certain injuries that didn’t fully heal yet. He even had to mimic some of the wounds on his face that indicated that he had been recently punched. Probably if he actually ran into this young master it wouldn’t be strange if he had to get smacked a few times for his mission to succeed.

“Go in then, young master Yichen should be out at the training ground.”

After bowing his head Zhang Dong was able to get into the core sect compound. This one was also behind a grand wall that stretched almost all the way up to the ceiling of this underground. Above on the wall, he could see core formation sentries with ranged weapons patrolling even as he went in.

‘I expected their defenses to be lax, they should have transferred more guards towards the assembly.’

He had hoped that everyone, even the disciples would have been forced to pay their respects to their new leader. Perhaps Wang Long didn’t like sect gatherings and forbade everyone from participating?

This might have been the reason behind this place being filled with demonic disciples and their masters. It just seemed to be an average day for them if some weren’t commenting about the demon king’s arrival then he could assume that he wasn’t even coming here.

‘The training area should be that way…’

Normally the plan was to avoid the young master to whom this servant belonged. Yet as always his luck when it came to infiltration wasn’t all that great. Where the training ground was so was his next destination. Only after passing through it would he arrive at the main sect building where his mission would end.

‘Bob, are you sure that this is the best route?’

‘Affirmative.’

‘Great…’

He had found a map of the entire sect compound on the servant. There were some markings done by Liu Chen that probably indicated where the young master of his liked to hang out. The servant probably got the map to help him find this Yichen before he got another beating. Thanks to this he could order Bob to simulate the safest route of getting there and all of the paths went through the spot this young master was at.

‘Is there someone else I can change to… this might become troublesome if I start getting beat and this brat breaks his arm on my face…’

Zhang Dong’s body refining skill was at the peak of this world. It would be somewhat hard for him to get injured by anyone below the nascent soul level. To anyone below it would feel like they were hitting a slab of metal instead of flesh. He would really need to go with the punches to make it seem believable if the confrontation occurred.

Regretfully this place wasn’t really suited for taking out people. There were a lot of open spaces and a large number of people were going back and forth. The fake sun that was illuminating the place would also make most of his shadowy techniques lose most of their impact.

Luckily for him, the robe he was wearing was identical to every other servant. It wouldn’t be that hard to cover his face and blend in with the crowd. Thus after silencing his own steps and breathing he decided to blend in with everyone else. It seemed that looking at attendants in the face was not something the young masters would do. This gave him the opportunity to move toward his target with more ease than he expected.

‘I’m practically invisible to these people…’

It was as if he was water and they were oil. No one was interested in him after they realized his robes belonged to a servant. There were even special walkways for servants like him through which he could avoid contact with most of the disciples and elders.

When passing through he could see the usual facilities everywhere. Cultivation caves, herb gardens, and pill pavilions. It didn’t really look any different from any other sect even though the buildings were a bit less kept from what a person would expect to see.

‘Well… that went better than I expected…’

To his surprise, after arriving at the training grounds there was no trouble. The disciples were just training and battling each other to gain more experience. For a moment he expected one of these young masters to run up to him with their palm outstretched. Yet even after going through the whole way, there was no one that stopped him.

It seemed that taking on the role of a servant was a lot better than impersonating an elder or a disciple. No one that mattered probably even knew who he was. They weren’t expecting any infiltration attempts either and perhaps they thought that no idiot would even try impersonating one of their personal delivery boys.

‘Well then, now comes the interesting part.

When he arrived at the main compound he quickly evaded the praying gaze of the other guards. Instead, he hugged the wall like a frog and started climbing up. This place was another checkpoint yet this time around it was too dangerous to try and get in through the main gate. Instead, he would use all of the skills that he gained to not get detected.

He wasn’t sure what it was but for some reason, the path before him had opened itself up. When he went through the guards were not paying attention, all of his moves were silent, and progressing through this checkpoint proved to be an easy endeavor.

His good luck continued as he pushed further into the core sect. There he found an underground labyrinth. Yet to someone of his knowledge it was obvious that if he went with the traditional way then he would be stuck in there for days. It was a clear trap for the non-initiated and a secret path was there for him to be discovered.

With the help of his senses and also his system he was quickly able to discover an out-of-place entrance. It was hidden behind several illusory arrays that after being cracked opened up to a flight of stairs. From that point onwards it was smooth sailing and within an hour of him passing through the checkpoint, he finally arrived at his destination.

‘It doesn't seem that there is anyone here, could it be that they haven’t really had time to prepare this place for spies?’

Even though he was a one-in-a-billion master it was still strange that it was this easy to get here. The only explanation that was plausible was his timing. This sect had been taken by Wang Long not so long ago.

It wouldn't be strange if the people that knew this place in and out were all dead. Wang Long might have not thought ahead with his plans and had everyone that was competent replaced. This would leave the new people to pick up the slack, without proper plans of the area it would take years for even a master to figure out this whole place.

Only with the help of his cheat system was he able to condense all the knowledge from old books and texts to come this far. Others would need expectantly more time to get a grasp of everything around them.

‘There really doesn’t seem to be anyone here…’

Even though he had a hunch it was still best to wait and see. Only after spending some time scanning the whole area with the help of his system and his sense did he decide to reveal himself. The area he was in now looked like a giant chasm with lava coming out of it, yet the lava wasn’t quite red but instead looked like corrupt dark blood.

‘This must be a corrupt spirit vein, the demonic radiation is truly powerful but…’

He trailed his eyes forward and could feel that this was not the spot with the most energy. That went further in the direction of Wang Long’s new castle. Luckily spirit veins of this caliber couldn’t just be absorbed by the system. They would need to go through some kind of process of purification before this could be attempted.

All over the walls, he could see strange occult symbols that the energy-gathering formation was composed. It was responsible for the grand formation working and if he disabled it then the inner city shield and even the one around this core sect area would be easily breached.

“I guess I should put a timer on this and get out of here…”

The last phase of the plan was upon him. After hacking the formation he would be able to leave. Finally, the time for the last battle was within hand’s reach.

Chapter 540

‘That should do it…’

It wasn’t easy and he wasn’t sure if his cover wasn’t already blown but the formation was prepared. He had placed a backdoor into the whole system that would allow him to destroy the formation even from outside. This should be enough to catch the Chaos Sect members off guard and shift the tide of battle if the need arises.

‘It is still too dangerous to contact the others at this stage.’

His system was still being blocked by Wang Long’s own faction zone. Unless he got out of it it wouldn’t be possible to inform everyone of his feat. If he spent enough points it would be possible but it would also alert his enemy to his presence. After that happened all hell would break loose and he put himself at a disadvantage when being inside their main camp.

‘I need to save all the spirit points for the battle, I don’t know what might happen'

Zhang Dong had managed to remain unseen by his enemies that were probably too busy with the new sect management. It was still possible to make his way out of here through the same way that he came in. Even if the fake Phantom Demon was discovered it might not be traced back to him. It was smooth sailing if he made it out into the outer city, from there were many escape routes that he had saved within his mapping system.

This whole thing reminded him of the time he was building up the new sect city. At that time he had chosen to remain there to monitor the situation. With the help of his system, he was able to easily discover spies before they could even make it in. His counterpart Wang Long didn’t seem to have the same worth ethic.

It seemed that he liked to rest on his laurels and indulge in the carnal pleasures of the flesh. Probably if his enemy took it seriously then it would have been impossible for this infiltration mission to go this smooth. Yet there still existed a small possibility that when he went outside troops of nascent soul masters could be waiting for him.

‘It still could be a trap so I should keep vigilant…’

With that in mind, he raised his awareness to its maximum while escaping from the underground spirit vein. Yet just like before not much had changed, the path was already open and with some knowledge, he was able to close everything behind him to make it look like he was never there, to begin with. Soon he found himself back outside with no one being the wiser.

His expectations of finding an elaborate trap with twenty or so nascent soul masters trying to lead him into a trapping formation didn’t come through. It really seemed that Wang Long was not expecting anything to happen. Perhaps he overestimated who he was going up against or the person grew complacent with the amount of power and prestige he received. Perhaps he was so convinced of his own superiority that he didn’t even see Zhang Dong as a proper opponent.

‘He might also have convinced himself that even if he loses he could just start over somewhere else.’

With the help of the system, it was possible to teleport out to another part of the empire. Wang Long probably still had a save point to the old sect he destroyed. No one could really follow him there if he decided to escape. With the new demonic cultivation and the system, Wang Long could continuously level up at a rapid pace. Zhang Dong, on the other hand, could only turn to resources like spirit stone and his faction and even then he would fall behind, thus his best bet was to end it here before everything got out of hand.

‘It was good that I kept this robe and token, I just need to sneak out.’

The appearance of the servant Liu Chen was kept. He had not delivered the pills that he was supposed to but this wasn’t important now. It was unlikely that the sect would be looking for a runaway servant. The young master that Liu Chen was serving was probably too busy to even care.

That is what he was hoping though but finally, his luck was about to run out. When he was making his way from the core sect area and through the training ground he noticed a commotion. A circle around two shouting people was forming and he was going straight through it. Even though he was hiding his face behind his robe someone called out to him.

“Hey isn’t that Liu Chen?”

“I think it is him!”

For some reason, the disciples turned in his direction. The place was filled with what looked to be teenagers that were mostly at the higher points of Qi condensation. In the middle of this circle were two snotty-looking brats. With one glance he could tell that they were prestigious young masters.

One of the young masters wasn’t alone. A brutish-looking man that looked like some kind of battle-hardened warrior was standing behind him. From what Zhang Dong could tell the man was hiding his power level. On the outside, he seemed to be a foundation establishment late stage practitioner but in reality, he was a half-step core formation expert.

“Liu Chen, where were you?”

“I…”

“Never mind you idiot, get over here!”

“Hah, so your dog actually showed up? At least he got a spine, not like you Yichen!”

“Shut your mouth Haoyu, I know you did something to keep him away but your rouse didn’t bear fruit, don’t think you can weasel out of the bet now!”

“Hah, you always had a vivid imagination Yichen, do you think my battle slave would ever lose to that servant of yours? “

“We will see!”

‘What the hell is going on here…’

Zhang Dong had seen the commotion from a mile away but he expected it to work in his favor. While the kids were cursing up a storm he would just slip past them and be out of this sect in no time. Only now was he able to hear the names of the young master in question being mentioned. It was of course the one that he was supposed to deliver the pills to. Perhaps the delivery was just a pretext to get him over to fight this mountain of muscles.

“Liu Chen what are you doing, get over here!”

“Ah yes young master…”

He had to quickly get into character as he bowed before the sixteen-year-old. The youths here were probably related to the nascent soul masters to be able to be in the inner sect area at this age. It was clear that Liu Chen’s young master had a feud with the other guy. Yet Haoyu was pulling a fast one on him. The servant he was using was far above the level of Liu Chen who was a late stage foundation establishment warrior.

‘This Haoyu is grinning too much, I bet he planned this thing out and got a fighter to win the bet.’

It was probable that the servants were limited to a certain level. Liu Chen was a true late stage foundation establishment practitioner and the man behind Haoyu was faking it. He was wearing some kind of treasure that was masking his true level. Not many people would be able to detect the ruse.

After going through the audience he could see that more people were on the side of this Haoyu fellow. When comparing the two young master’s cultivation they were around the same. They were probably unwilling to go against each other directly. One of them would probably not get out of it unharmed, either dead or crippled.

Perhaps this wasn’t the first time the servants were forced to fight for their young masters. The bet probably involves the transferring of cultivation resources and would leave the loser with a hit to their pride. To many this was still the harshest punishment they could receive, being mocked and disrespected.

“I…”

The group turned to the open field where the usual training ground was. There were teachers here but they didn’t seem to care. He could even see some of them placing their own bets. This was probably not the first time the disciples cleared out disputes between each other like this.

‘This Liu Chen must have had a hard life…’

The unhealed wounds on the man he replaced now started to make more sense. It was not that he was getting beat by the young master but instead he was forced to battle other servants. Perhaps he had been on a winning streak that convinced Yichen of his own superiority.

‘Should I win or lose?’

There was nothing that he could really do. If he started running now the whole sect would be on to him. It wouldn’t be hard for him to win in this situation but it was also risky. The other side might have been cheating but if he showed more power than he was supposed to then he could also get into trouble.

‘I think I’ll have to sweat for this one…’

There was no escaping his fate, the disciples were already gathering around them. Luckily no nascent soul masters were paying attention. Going back to foundation establishment level martial arts wouldn’t be so easy. However, constricting his power levels would just be proof of his control.

“Don’t you dare lose, Liu Chen!”

“Master Yichen’s servant looks so weak compared to master Haoyu’s.”

“I’ll bet my bloodstones on young master Haoyu’s servant!”

“Me too, that Liu Chen is barely standing up!”

The other disciples clearly knew of Liu Chen’s recent bouts. It could have been the case that other people from Haoyu’s faction had tried to weaken Liu Chen with other fights. Even when they lost if they managed to injure the only battle slave Yichen had, it would be enough. This Haoyu had clearly prepared the stage for a decisive win.

“You have my apologies but I must follow the young master’s orders.”

The large man spoke up to him as if he was assured of his victory. He was probably ordered to either kill or cripple Liu Chen in this fight. It was supposed to be a show of might for the other side. There was no animosity in the tone of his voice and Zhang Dong couldn’t fault the reasoning. The man was only doing things to survive and if he failed his life would probably be in danger.

‘I guess if this sect falls it won’t be such a bad thing…’

When looking at the young children here he could see that they were already too far gone. Their morals were skewed by the years of infighting and a massive superiority complex. It would be hard to straighten them out at this point but if he could then he would like to give them a chance.

‘Okay, let’s get this over with…’

Chapter 541

“Liu Chen don’t you dare lose or I’ll kill you myself!”

Shouted the young master whose servant Zhang Dong was impersonating. He wanted to do nothing more than go and slap all of these kids in the face. They were all teenagers and apparently already corrupt down to their bones. He could see the glee in some of their eyes that would probably be hard to correct even if they switched factions at this very moment. Yet before he could contend with that problem he needed to first get out of here.

“Kill him.”

Young master Haoyu was a bit more composed but even he was part of the group. Zhang Dong could clearly see through the system what the youth said to the burly servant. Even though none of them needed to die here it was often the case. In the demonic sects not many masters tolerated failures and depending on the occasion they would not accept it.

In this case, Liu Chen and the other servant would be fighting for their own survival. The young masters on both sides hated each other and they made a spectacle of it. There were far too many people gathered here, it would be a hit to their face if they lost which was still the main reason anyone existed in this world.

‘I wonder if I can ever get people to realize that fame and prestige aren’t all that great…’

He wanted to do nothing more and to explain how a simple life might be a lot better than one filled with wealth. Yet at this very moment, the large servant was already charging his way while surrounding himself with some strange red energy. This energy was filled with negative emotions which allowed the man to boost his power even higher.

There was a small problem here, Zhang Dong didn’t really know what this Liu Chen was good at. The man didn’t have many personal belongings on him, these were probably kept at a safer location where the other inner disciples couldn’t get them. He was probably wary of carrying too much money or resources that were meant for his own progress.

Thus Zhang Dong wasn’t really sure what this servant was good at. The only clue that was in his possession was Liu Chen himself that was still knocked out in his spatial treasure. A quick examination revealed some of his proficiencies and that he preferred palm attacks to other means.

‘His dao of shadows is the most proficient as well… but this doesn’t always mean anything…’

He was unsure how to react, should he just go for it and knock the big guy out in one hit? Yet that could draw unwanted attention from the elders and teachers that were watching the scene play out. At this point in time, he couldn’t just reveal himself as his escape route was not clear. Wang Long could have already arrived on the scene and might also have a way to block any teleportation attempts.

For this reason, he needed to make it look authentic. People in the training areas had been performing some basic techniques that he could copy. The only problem would be his position, as a servant he would probably not be allowed to learn high level techniques that others were using. For this reason, he needed to go with something more basic but refined to make up for the discrepancy in tiers.

“Hah, look at him just standing there! Did he just give up and accepted his fate?”

“That might be true, maybe the servant is tired of working for someone like Yichen.”

The group that was on Haoyu’s side started cackling while looking at the fight. Zhang Dong was still processing the situation and thinking about a good strategy. His hands were lowered as if he had given up on the bout. The large man didn’t stop though, he was ordered to kill and that’s what he would do. His large fist which was covered by crimson energy quickly descended at his opponent's head.

Suddenly there was a change, as the fist was only a few centimeters away from Zhang Dong’s face he stepped to the side. It was as if the path of the blow had been read and he used the least amount of effort to evade it. This was his answer to his problem, instead of going for flashy techniques he would win with the basics.

The cultivators in this world were enhanced, martial artists. When they started out they focused a lot of their time on perfecting their basic martial skills. Yet as they progressed to new heights they tended to forget about the foundations of their power. Regular techniques like reading the flow of combat, and searching for cues a body made were forgotten. Instead, they trained in performing large-scale attacks with the help of their Qi.

To win this battle he didn’t really need to be stronger than his opponent. It would be fine if he could just read him and counter effectively. Just like that after dodging the large blow he surrounded himself with a thin layer of fake demonic Qi. This was to boost his power while also protecting his own body from the red energy that would try to invade his body and harm it.

Soon the large man felt a palm strike his side. Even though there wasn’t a lot of power behind it he felt like vomiting. But he would not be defeated this easily, the muscles that he was so proud of were like armor and he was also hiding his true power. This amount of damage he could still contend with.

“You…”

His first opened up as he spread his fingers into the shape of a claw. His fingernails expanded in both length and thickness as he attempted to shred his enemy. Yet even when performing these strikes at an alarming pace Zhang Dong was able to see through every faint and small movement and react accordingly.

To not make it too obvious he showed a concerned face as if he was barely managing himself. The exchange of blows continued and both parties were receiving damage but one of them was clearly losing.

“Young master Haoyu’s servant is losing?”

“How is that Liu Chen this lucky? Was he hiding his martial skills all this time?”

“Did he just stumble over a rock to dodge that flying kick?”

Zhang Dong didn’t think that he was the best actor but he tried to remember any actions that might help him in this situation. He wanted to appear as being lucky but also with enough skill to win this fight. If he could sell his victory as just being lucky then it was fine. The other servant couldn’t really reveal his true power for long as the whole bet would be forfeit and that was also what he was aiming for.

‘He tried a few times but hasn’t made it too obvious…’

The large man had been boosting himself with that half-step core formation power from time to time. It was clear that Haoyu had instructed him not to make it too obvious. If Zhang Dong played his cards right then he wouldn’t even need to deliver the final blow to this meat head. What he needed to do was to make him angry enough to reveal his true potential.

“Did Liu Chen hit his head and get enlightened or something?”

The young lords that were watching the fight started watching the fight without blinking. They were still only Qi condensation practitioners that could learn a lot. To them the way Liu Chen dodged every attack was quite intriguing. The footwork in itself was something not many masters were capable of. Yet it would probably be impossible to copy as both of the fighters were already high ranked foundation establishment adepts.

‘Common, I know that you want to do it…’

For his next attempt, Zhang Dong performed a bicycle kick to the face after getting his other foot grasped. It was a nice hit to his opponent's chin that was unable to defend himself. His mouth became filled with blood and one of the teeth inside his mouth had been snapped in half. The man could not believe it, how was he losing to someone he should be able to kill with one hit.

“Y-you…BASTARD!”

‘There we go! Give me that rage mode!”

Finally, his tactic of annoying the other servant with smacks to the face had borne fruit. He could see all sorts of veins popping up on his body as he transformed into his true form. It was clear that the man was only a half-step core formation practitioner for a reason. The form he was taking on was incomplete and hard to control. The demonic arts he was using swayed towards the emotions garnering rage and anger. In short, he was a berserker that had a short fuse.

‘Here he comes… hope someone will jump in before it gets out of hand…’

“H-hey, that’s not something a servant should be capable of doing… he is above the foundation realm…”

Zhang Dong made sure to shout out what was going on to make the others act quicker. The young masters that were looking at him were pushed back by the spike in cultivation. To people of the lowest realm, a half-step core formation master was enough to make them faint.

“Haoyu I know that you were a cheating bastard!”

“I don’t know what you are insinuating, I had no idea about this either!”

“Shut up you liar and admit your loss!”

“Never!”

‘Those two fuckers…’

While the two were arguing with each other he was still getting assaulted by the enraged muscle head. Evading these savage attacks wasn’t as easy now. With him hiding his true power there was a limited assortment of options thus the only reasonable thing to do was, to make a run for it.

“H-help!”

“Hey shouldn’t we stop the fight, Liu Chen looks pathetic…”

“Yeah…”

The other kids from the group started laughing as he burst forth from the group and made a run for it. While this might have not been the best way out of this situation it gave him a chance of running.

‘The teachers aren’t interfering either… this really is a hellhole for learning…’

It didn’t seem there was anyone to punish the young masters. They would probably work it out between each other and no one cared about the runaway servant that was now only an amusing sight to behold.

‘I guess this is as good a time as any…’

With the fight now being a big farce, he decided to bolt it for the main gate. There the guards would probably help him out with this situation and perhaps even allow him to escape to the other side. When outside he would finally be able to move past this debacle and join in with his army…

Chapter 542

‘Good the coast is clear…’

Zhang Dong was planning to run towards the exit gate while being chased by the enraged cultivator. Yet due to him having to lower his cultivation level he wasn’t quite able to do it. Instead, he sidestepped into an empty alley where his pursuer was quickly knocked out while no one could see it.

The man was now stuck within his spatial artifact with the other servant he apprehended. Luckily for him, the idiot that was charging after him was radiating a negative aura everywhere. It wasn’t hard to heighten his battle prowess in a situation like this without alerting the nascent soul elders around him.

‘Let’s go.’

“Liu Chen? What was that commotion? I heard that there was a fight at the training ground”

“Oh you know, it was the usual…”

While he had not received any real damage during his bout he made it seem that he had been beaten up. The guards here were not informed about the details so after a glance, it looked like he had gone through the usual. Thanks to that they gave him the nod and he was able to leave the core sect area. The young master probably had other things to worry about as he was now owed money.

His mission was mostly over now and after he left the inner city he would more than likely be safe. What remained was to travel to the upper inner city and finally escape. Thus he made his way through the streets while shedding his Liu Chen disguise as fast as he could. Instead, he went for one of the many guards that would have the clearing for leaving this inner sect.

‘I don’t think I have much time left…’

On his system window, he had a countdown timer to when the meeting with Wang Long was supposed to take place. Yet just like before the security around this place was lax. The people that were performing these tasks didn’t seem to care much or were unable to think that they were being infiltrated.

‘I guess randomly taking over a sect and forcing their inhabitants to work doesn’t work that well…’

There was a difference between the approaches that he and Wang Long took. Zhang Dong had slowly built up the trust in his clan and with the other families before their sect was formed. The vast majority of the core sect was in awe of his power and strong character. There wouldn’t be many things that they wouldn’t do for him and their trust could not be easily broken.

Here on the other hand it was power gained by force. It wouldn’t be strange if all of the Chaos Sect members surrendered instantly after their new leader was defeated. Even if Zhang Dong wished for a battle between him and Wang Long the man in question would probably not agree to a fair confrontation just between them. If that was a possibility Zhang Dong would have already announced himself and demanded a proper bout between the two leaders.

‘There we go… Bob, be sure to scan for Wang Long, we can’t have him popping out of the blue.’

‘Affirmative’

This was still Wang Long’s faction and he wasn’t sure how far his faction system had been upgraded to. The sect was patched up in a couple of places but it wasn’t being managed that well. Perhaps thanks to this was his infiltration attempt this successful. Now what he just needed to do was to get outside and his way out was just around the corner.

“Wha…”

“Sorry about that…”

A merchant with a few guards was about to pack up and leave. Another victim fell to his body-switching technique as he took out a guard that had just entered an outhouse. Zhang Dong had strategically placed himself on the ceiling before knocking out the man with his pants down.

With his new disguise in place, he just got out and joined the other mercenaries that were escorting the merchant. The carts were filled with some junk that the merchant probably hoped to dump in the outer city where the resources were harder to come by.

“Common move it, we don’t have all day, and remember, none of you are getting paid until you unload the merchandise!”

He could see the regular workers giving out sighs of disappointment. While there were only three carts with goods they contained some spatial treasures with the true items. These would probably need to be removed from inside the treasure and then carried to their proper destination.

Soon they arrived at the checkpoint which contained the large gate. In a few moments, he would be outside and after reaching the outer city he would be safe. Even if he destroyed the outer city gates during his escape it wouldn’t really matter anymore. The massive barriers surrounding everything were already rigged by him, what he needed to do was to get outside and contact his army which wouldn’t take that long to get here.

‘It’s our turn now.’

Even though it looked like the coast was clear he didn’t forget to pay close attention to everyone here. The merchant owner was showing his identification plaque to the guards which would probably allow him to move through the gate. During the exchange, he also saw some blood crystals making their way into the guard's spatial ring which would only allow them to cross faster.

This was quite the normal occurrence even back at the orthodox sect side. Bribing guards at entrances to cities or other territories was a regular expense that merchants counted in before setting out to trade. Here it was more of the same unless the guards lacked a reason or were incentivized to capture people that attempted bribes nothing would change.

‘Warning, warning.’

‘Huh, what is it, Bob?’

Suddenly as they were passing through the checkpoint he could hear his AI blasting loud horns. There was something wrong but even when he spread his senses in all directions he couldn’t see anything.

‘Warning, outer system changes detected, attempting to block the change ….. attempt was unsuccessful, the change will take place in 3…2…1…’

‘Wait Bob, what are you talking about? What changes?’

Zhang Dong continued to move with the merchants through the large gate while his eyes darted around. There was something going wrong right when he was about to step outside of the gate. Only after the countdown was over was he able to see the shift.

“What is happening?”

This was also noticed by the guards and the merchant he was with. A strange device with the logo of the Chaos Sect appeared on it. It was clear to Zhang Dong that this had to have been created by Wang Long and his faction system. Bob quickly confirmed his fears which forced him to drop the guard act.

‘Identification device spotted, warning! The user will be unable to conceal himself from the other faction system!’

For one reason or another Wang Long decided to dump some spirit points into his faction system. This was something that he did frequently to upgrade the structures and enhance others. This might have still been only a coincidence and before he was found out he might be able to escape.

“Hey what are you…”

*BOOM*

While the carts stopped in place he gathered all of his energies around his body. A bright spark of light filled the entire region as he tossed himself towards the exit. Of course, he was still on the threshold of the barrier that would only be removed after he blew up the spirit vein. That part of the plan was still in place but it was too soon for it.

This was a multiple-layered defensive formation and he was right inside of it. While charging through the gate he was forced to bust through it while using a large chunk of his spiritual energy. Luckily the formation needed a second to activate and this gave him enough time to get to the other side.

‘Can I teleport out of here?’

While pushing through he quickly brought up the system window that he was previously hiding. First, he attempted to teleport toward one of his sect members who was supposed to be at the secret camp. Yet a red screen appeared just like he was afraid of, unless he used a huge amount of spirit points he would be unable to leave. These he needed for the long-range teleportation of the golden palace and thus he postponed this option.

With another injection of Qi, he shot out through the other end of the gate. This of course sent all sorts of warning signals through the entire sect. Various masters were forced to take chase along with some guardian beasts that were of similar power. Yet no one was quite as fast as Zhang Dong was, if it was only this much then he would surely be able to escape.

He could already see the exit before him, his speed increased as his body was surrounded by both lightning and golden light. To augment his power he decided to make his spiritual energy take the form of a really fast drill. Even if the barrier stopped him for a moment he would just drill through it instantly.

Finally, the last hurdle was before him as he collided with the barrier while bulldozing through various other demonic cultivators. There were even two nascent soul elders that were just knocked to the side as if they were crash test dummies. The promised land was before him, in a few seconds he would be outside and even if anyone tried to follow him they would be unable to keep up with his speed.

Yet right before he collided with the outer city barrier he noticed a large shadow looming over him. This was followed by a giant spike in demonic Qi. This was above something that anyone from the elders here should be capable of doing. He needed to get out of there and it needed to happen now.

His bones started crumbling as he forced himself to change directions in an abrupt manner. Only thanks to his healing energies and his powerful body were he able to somehow evade a critical injury. This was just in time to not get hit by a torrent of dark energy that collided with the spot he was going for.

When looking towards the source of this massive energy spike he found a familiar-looking dragon that looked a lot more demonic than before. It wasn’t alone though as on top of its head he spotted a certain evil cultivator that was going by the name of Demon King these days.

“Haha, look what the cat dragged in!”

‘Well, shit!”

Wang Long glanced toward Zhang Dong, who had stopped his escape. From all sides, multiple nascent soul masters came swarming in as he quickly found himself being surrounded. His escape route was blocked and the man he was after had arrived, his biggest fear was about to come true.

Chapter 543

“I was just wondering when you would show up, I really didn’t expect you to try to sneak in like a total retard though. What was the plan here bruv? Were you trying to assassinate me during my introduction speech?”

“...”

Zhang Dong was surrounded by around ten nascent soul masters and multiple other demonic cultivators. Most of them were floating on swords but some were using flying ships or other treasures. Yet even with all of them here the only real problem was the man that was leading them, Wang Long.

“Assassinate you?”

“Hah, are you going to play dumb? But you did come alone so perhaps you aren’t the brightest!”

Wang Long was up in the sky on his demonic-looking dragon. This creature had gone through a drastic change of form on power. It looked like some kind of charred zombie dragon, it had exposed flesh sticking out everywhere that looked as if it was decomposing. Some of its bones were also sticking out but even when it looked like a corpse it didn’t look weak.

‘The creature is surrounded by evil energy, I can feel the corruption from all the way here… but I might be in luck, he doesn’t seem to realize that I was actually escaping before he arrived…’

From the monologue, Zhang Dong could tell that Wang Long had only discovered him just now. He was unaware of any forces gathering outside of his new domain. The change to the gate was probably something he did recently and it wasn’t anything planned. It seemed that Wang Long didn’t know about the barriers being rigged and ready to collapse.

‘Even though he is dumb and conceited, he still is strong…’

While his enemy wasn’t the best tactician one thing was for sure, he had leveled up since their last run-in. It was a monolithic change, if Zhang Dong didn’t know that his opponent had the system it would have been a stunning turn of events. If his power eclipsed his own was still up to debate as none of them were showing their cards right now.

Yet he could not just attack him, the other nascent soul masters might have not been strong or that dangerous but they would sway the fight. He was also missing his own dragon that was left behind at the secret encampment. After he was discovered his whole system had been jammed from peeking outside and he was still unsure if he should fork up the spirit points to run. For all, he knew Wang Long had more of them and could block his escape anyway.

“Weren’t you more chatty the last time we met or are you stumped that your system won’t let you teleport out? I’m not like you, I actually have a functioning brain! If you weren’t just a goober you’d have done the same back at your faction, haha what a noob, and you’re supposed to have been longer than me!”

It was strange to hear a villain monologue from the only person that was supposed to have come from the real world. Yet there he was, berating Zhang Dong for not taking into consideration that he wouldn’t be able to escape once he entered his faction area. However, the only reason he did not prepare last time was because he was unaware of the existence of a second system user.

“You sure talk a lot for an incel.”

“... what did you call me?”

‘I guess that hit the spot.’

To shut up his enemy he jabbed at something that was probably the truth. Wang Long overvalued his sexual life to a fault. This was probably something that had to have been a focal point in his previous life. The most probable cause was probably the lack of the man’s experience with the fairer sex. He went out of his way to have as many sexual acts as he could as if he was making up for his past inefficiencies.

“You heard it, who else but an incel would act as you do? Still trying to fill the void in your heart because that one girl in high school didn’t want to look your way or something?”

In reality, he was unsure what this would help him with but he needed to stall. Before he was discovered he did notice one thing, Bahamut his familiar was a lot closer to this city than he was supposed to be. Did he somehow know that his master was in trouble or was there another explanation?

“By how red you are getting I’ll assume that I hit a bullseye on that one. Hey, if this is just a game like you make it out to be, does it even count?”

“Huh?”

Wang Long was giving off quite the chaotic aura that was even making the people here cover in fear. He was clearly still thinking that everyone here was an NPC and not a real human being. This could be used to Zhang Dong’s advantage if he poked at his opponent's insecurities.

“It doesn’t count, you are still and always will be a virgin and an incel, right? These people are just NPCs bots with no emotions, no matter how much you do it with them it will never count!”

“You fuck! Stop calling me an incel, I’m not a virgin!”

“Are you sure? If it looks like a duck, swims like a duck, and quacks like a duck then it’s probably a little virgin just like you!”

He burst out in laughter while inching away, the uncomfortable demonic aura wasn’t affecting him as much as it was the people that were trying to keep him from escaping. The negative emotions infected the demonic corpse dragon as well. It was corrupting the air around it causing even the nearby nascent soul masters to cower in fear.

It was a simple battle tactic, getting an opponent angry always worked in favor of the one that could keep their mind cool. They would get aggressive and easy to read. It was a lot better to fight someone that couldn’t control their emotions than someone that mastered them and Wang Long was certainly the former type.

“You fucker, I’ll cut off your balls and feed it to your bastard kids!”

Just as planned he had lost it and began his assault without carrying for the people around him. While the man had gotten a lot more powerful his personality didn’t change. He certainly still had a big chip on his shoulder and Zhang Dong was a person that could remind him of the old world they left behind. He would desperately try to destroy the only link to his old unfavorable past even if that meant killing his own people.

“D-demon King w-why…”

After propelling himself to the side to evade the huge breath attack of the corrupt zombie-like dragon one of the nascent soul masters that was behind him was hit. Even though he was a nascent soul master at the pinnacle his face started to instantly melt from the corrosive and poisonous cloud that escaped from the dragon’s maw.

However even when Wang Long was going berserk and some of his troops were getting massacred, Zhang Dong was still in trouble. The only thing he could do was dodge while trying to reach the outer city barrier.

‘Just a bit more, that idiot didn’t realize it yet but I’m not really trapped in here.’

Even though he was a nascent soul master, getting through the outer barrier wouldn’t be that easy. It was reinforced by the hexagram and the creatures that were drained of their energy there. Zhang Dong had done his due diligence to take care of that part of the problem before delving deep into the inner sect. Now it was time to spring his own counter trap that he was hoping to activate only after his troops appeared on the scene.

Luckily for him, Wang Long was far too busy being angry and pointing his dragon’s breath attack at him to notice the strange change in the formation. First, the six towers that were the focal point of this city's outer formation started rumbling, from within the screams of the massive monsters could be heard by everyone.

This was followed by a switch in the formation's color that was more akin to his golden lightning than the demonic gray it was before. The trap was simple, the barrier would work for a short amount of time while the six large nascent soul beasts would be let loose in the city.

Thanks to his knowledge about beast taming that he had lifted from the old expedition secret ground he knew how to insert a little thought into all of those creatures minds. They already felt animosity towards the people that trapped them there but that would probably be focused on the citisens and not the actual people that were responsible.

For that reason, he just inserted a little mind trick. The beasts had already mostly lost their mind and were just a bundle of rage that wanted nothing more than revenge. He just needed to shift that anger towards certain Qi patterns. These would all belong to masters above the nascent soul level.

Thus as the beings emerged from the rubble of the collapsed spires they turned in the direction of Wang Long and the other grandmasters. They were the largest beacons of energy in the area and quite easy to track. They instantly charged toward the floating humans while ignoring anything else. This would somewhat allow the regular citizens to evacuate but would probably still cause some deaths that he needed to contend with.

This was his cue to make a run for it. Wang Long that was raging a second ago was forced to look away towards the crumbling towers. His system was probably showing him all sorts of warning signals at this very moment that would hold him back for a moment.

Zhang Dong turned around to head back to where his troops were at. His tactic of setting the beast on the city only after his army attacked had fallen through but his plan could still be salvaged. Yet as he was about to turn into a shooting star and get out of here he stopped himself.

“Huh?”

“Support the Patriarch, attack with all your might!”

“For the United Element’s Sect!”

“For the Sect!”

“For the Patriarch!”

Instead of him having to rendezvous with his troops they appeared out of nowhere themselves. Only after the outer barrier was lifted did his system start to go back online and he could check his faction window for his people.

“Liena, what are you doing here?”

“What do you think? What wife wouldn’t come to aid her husband?”

“Senior Brother! I see that you have started without us!”

“Dong’er, I see that you managed to return in one piece but it would be smarter to leave these sort of tactics to the spy unit next time.”

All of his friends and family members were there. They had arrived at the scene even after he had ordered them to remain at the base and wait for further orders. They had ignored them but he was not mad but glad about it.

“You guys… we’ll talk about this later…”

While he didn’t appreciate it that his wife was here this was supposed to be the last big battle of his sect. Wang Long was here and he was caught with his pants down it was time to end all of this once and for all.

Chapter 544

“Do you think this changes anything?”

“I think it does but before we start I’ll give you the option to surrender. You’ll just have to relinquish the system to me, I will of course guarantee your safety.”

“Are you serious? Give away my system? Over my dead body!”

While the two leaders exchanged some quick words while the two sides clashed with each other. The appearance of Zhang Dong’s army was quite unexpected. This left the whole demonic city in a state of chaos. The beasts that were used to power the outer formation were loose and attacking the nascent soul masters while the orthodox cultivators were coming from the outside.

Large ships made of spirit iron continued to appear along with more traditional cultivators of beasts and flying swords. This was clearly a planned endeavor but why this attack was taking place wasn’t too obvious to these people.

Orthodox and demonic cultivators most of the time stayed out of their regions. While the former side was considered to be stronger they didn’t really have anything to gain from clashing with the demonic cultivators. The lands here were devoid of spiritual energy that regular cultivators could use and the treasures wouldn’t give them an edge either.

“I thought you would say that, you give me no choice then, one way or another this will end here.”

“Haha, do you think those NPC forces will be enough?”

Wang Long didn’t seem impressed by the flying ships and the army that was quickly appearing. Even the new golden dragon Bahamut that was equal to his soul beast didn’t shake his resolve. In his eyes Zhang Dong made one big mistake, he decided to bring the fight to his faction base where he had the advantage.

“Let me show you how it’s done!”

With a click on his system screen, he activated the buffing function. It was the same one Zhang Dong used when Wang Long invaded the United Element sect. Yet this time around the ones that were getting enhanced were the demonic cultivators from the Chaos Sect. The nascent soul masters could feel their energy circulating, it was as if they were young again and also possessed more power than they ever did.

“You think this is all? I’ve spent a lot of points on toys just to see you eat shit!”

It didn’t look like this was all as Wang Long continued grinning and activating functions on his system. Zhang Dong remained quiet but deep inside he was also smiling. His opponent was not aware that he was showing his cards too soon. First of all the buff wouldn’t last forever and he already activated it before measuring his opponent's full battle prowess.

Then second of all he was showing him another trump card in the form of the Demon King castle that was now slowly floating out of the volcano. This thing was quite similar to the golden castle he had procured from the Long Clan. He wasn’t sure if it was bought with the help of spirit points or if it was just a counter fortress to the one he had. It could have just been a backup for the situation of a system holder going for a demonic route.

The sight of this giant gaudy-looking dark lava castle sent shivers down the demonic cultivators. Everyone could feel that this was a treasure of unfathomable power and probably not something the orthodox sect that was attacking them could combat. Yet their hearts sunk soon after as they felt a spike in spiritual energy in the middle of the assaulting force armada.

In a blink, a huge structure on par with their Demon King’s castle appeared out of thin air. It was a magnificent golden castle with massive walls and huge cannons stuck to them. It was clear that the attackers came prepared to counter Wang Long’s own fortress of doom.

“How did you…”

“You’re not the only one with a castle here incel-boy.”

“Stop calling me that!”

“Make me!”

Zhang Dong peeked behind at his sect members. There he could see or feel his family members like Liena and Zhang Jin. Besides them, there were also his friends and faithful retainers like Huo Qiang and Zhang Zhi that were ready to risk their lives for this endeavor.

In reality, there was no reason to involve them this soon or at all. Perhaps the better way would be to just hang out at the Long Clan and shield himself behind the Azure Emperor that had some kind of backup plan. That might have been the safer route but also one that would endanger the lives of more people inside of the empire. As long as Wang Long remained in power, even the other invaders seemed like a lesser problem.

Finally, it was time for the last rodeo but before the spiritual energy blasts started flying the side belonging to the demonic cultivators encountered another problem. Only the outer city had been breached and the enemy cannons were unable to pierce through the inner city barrier.

While that remained functional their forces could always retreat. The outer city wasn’t really their main base, everything that they needed to survive was where the sect was. They would be able to even survive years there without any support from the outside. With the exposed spirit vein they had an almost unlimited amount of energy to get back to.

Already the barrier was expanding and people were going to the cannons that they would use to shoot down the flying ships in the sky. Their plan was to use the one-way barrier in their favor. They could keep firing their weapons at the enemy while the forcefield would block the barrage from outside.
They were convinced that before they run out of spiritual energy the ships in the sky would be nothing more than rubble. Their enemies had made a stupid decision to come with such a paltry force. In their eyes, they wouldn't attempt a feat like this without at least twice as much firepower.

Yet before the first cannon could fire towards the closest ship or the large golden fortress, a tiny beam of golden light collided with the barrier. It came from the leader of their new enemies and didn’t cause any damage.

“Wait, what’s happening? Why is the grand array flickering?”

The tiny ray of light wasn’t there to cause damage, it was just a trigger for his backdoor entrance to open. The work he went through to sabotage the grand formation bore fruit quite soon as the coast was clear. The surprised demonic cultivators didn’t even have time to react as their cannons that should have been indestructible exploded from a long-range cannon blast.

“Their formations are down, everyone attack with all your might!”

While the whole place exploded into something that looked like a rainbow light show the two leaders continued to look at each other. Zhang Dong was trying to examine the capabilities of his opponent while also getting on top of his own dragon. Both of them were in possession of a system that brought in a certain randomness factor.

‘I should expect him to have a lot of items from that store but he can’t have that much after getting that floating castle…’

The previous encounter with this person wasn’t that tough as he took him by surprise. Not much time had passed and Wang Long probably wasn’t able to learn that many new tricks. His approach was to kill his old faction and use what he gained to artificially inflate his all-around power.

This was a double-edged sword that Zhang Dong expected Wang Long to have ignored. He already proved himself to be lazy and over-reliant on the system. His answer to the previous loss was just to get more spirit points and get better techniques and arts. What he didn’t count in were the proficiencies that could not be increased through the system.

A system user was given the knowledge of the skill or technique but they still needed to use it to get better at it. He expected Wang Long to have been a couch potato just like he was before. Without proper training and moving the body around it was impossible to perform a technique to its perfection even when the system implanted all of the knowledge.

‘His movements are unrefined for sure…’

They quickly clashed with each other. Sparks flew and his golden energy bounced away from the darkened demonic one of his opponents. None of them did any damage to each other but it looked like Wang Long at a base had more energy than even Zhang Dong.

‘The old system is really a giant cheat if you have no issue killing people…’

He was different from his replacement. Killing people never came easy and even now he was unconvinced of his current strategy. Yet his opponent didn’t really give him a choice, the longer he lived the stronger he became and the more people would die. To end all of this madness he needed to put an end to it.

Somewhere deep inside he did blame himself for Wang Long’s appearance. Perhaps all those years ago during the expedition, if he didn’t let his pride slip out then all of this would have never happened. But perhaps the immortal that created that place would have forced him to lose his previous system in another way that he wouldn’t be able to control.

Yet this was not the time to think back to his beginning as before him stood his greatest enemy, Wang Long. To Zhang Dong he was a skewed reflection of the person that he could have easily become if he let this world's morals cloud his own judgment. Instead, he chose to take the harder route of working things out with people if that option arose.

‘I should probably take this fight somewhere else…’

Wang Long clearly didn’t care for the citizens or his faction at all. If this happened inside Spirit Spring City, Zhang Dong would actually start losing points for damaging his own buildings and having the approval rating fall down. Here on the other hand the zombie dragon continued to give out deadly mists that corroded everything and made the building turn to dust.

Luckily after all the comments about Wang Long's insecurities and virgin status, he was truly mad. It didn’t take much for him to give chase as he propelled himself towards the more desolate area to the side. There his plan was to take him out just like the Demi-Human Emperor and end this farce once and for all.

Chapter 545

“The enemy has no defenses, attack now, they are all demonic monsters, show them no mercy!”

Shouted out Zhang Jin who set up camp on the large floating golden palace. While his grandson Zhang Dong would like to take in prisoners he knew that it would be childish to think they wouldn’t backstab them. He was assured that a demonic cultivator could be surrounded while hiding a blade behind his back and just waiting for a chance.

Many good people had died this way and he would not make the same mistake. The demons that resided in this place would do the same to them if they had the chance. It was hard for him to even separate the sect and civilians living here. To him, an old man that followed the old ways after winning would have to be purged.

There always existed a chance that someone from the survivors could return strong and with a vengeance. In a world where one person could turn the tide of battle, this was always a possibility. One such person was on his side, Zhang Dong, the United Element Sect Patriarch. Then there was also the other one, Wang Long the Demon King.

While his grandson was already a being of unimaginable power that he didn’t understand, this Wang Long was even scarier. The old man couldn’t fathom what this demonic cultivator could have done to achieve this much power in such a short amount of time. He single-handedly destroyed an old behemoth that was the Soaring Dragon Sect.

This was not something anyone expected to ever occur. This was truly an age of change that would bring another world order. Zhang Jin was unsure what awaited them after this battle was over but he could barely contain his excitement. If they managed to defeat the man that destroyed one of the old big three then it would mean that they could take their place.

While their leader didn’t seem to be aiming for that title, almost all of the elders in the sect desired this prestige. Their leader would be the brother of the Azure Emperor, he even had the birthright to take the whole Empire for himself. This was however something that still needed debating, the Azure Emperor was not weak and they could not know how much this war would set them back.

“Raise the shield output, ram the fortress into that blasted castle, let's see if it has the same defensive capabilities!”

Zhang Jin was the commanding officer of the Golden Dong Palace. He was not allowed to lose or have this magnificent treasure destroyed by the enemy. They were going against a similar type of fortress which was more suited for offense than defense. It had more cannons and could move faster yet if they managed to get in closer then he believed that their victory was assured.

While the two large flying structures were exchanging cannon blasts more fighting was going outside. Large formations looking like water serpents or other bests like emerald birds were going up against a large number of ferocious demonic beings. At the time the battle looked like a stalemate and Zhang Dong was keeping a close eye on his own faction through his system window.
‘Not yet…’

He didn’t like it but his troops needed to last a bit without his help. The other side wasn’t really stronger but they were under the effect of Wang Long’s faction buff. His enemy was probably convinced that it wouldn’t be possible for him to activate it. This wasn’t true, with the help of his golden bastion he would be able to produce the same effect around it. The area wasn’t as big as the one back at his sect but it would be enough to be victorious here.

“Where are you going? Are you really one of those idiots that can only fight when there aren’t any others around?”

Wang Long flew after him on his zombie dragon while shouting. He was right, the two heavy hitters would produce so much collateral damage that it would be safer if no one was near their battle zone. His enemy had probably watched similar scenes playing out in some fiction concerning heroes. It wasn’t strange for them to bring the battle to a desolate area where they could let loose.

“You really bought into this fake game, haven’t you?”

His opponent was different though, he did not concern himself with his own faction. This he presented by stopping in his tracks and pointing his dragon towards one of the buildings on the edge of the outer city.

“Wait, what are you doing?”

“Does this really bother you?”

Without needing to say anything the dragon’s breath attack collided with the structure. Zhang Dong could only watch on in horror as the people that were trying to hide melted instantly. The poisonous and corrosive breath of this creature was enough to turn the whole area into a sludge.

“Seriously? Dude, you really have a hero complex. These ‘people’ aren’t even from your faction, what a retard. How did you even survive for this long?”

“...”

He remained quiet while looking at the pile of sludge before him. Wang Long was berating him probably in the hopes to make him mad but anger was not the emotion that he was feeling.

“You know what your biggest problem is and why you could never beat me?”

“Huh?”

“It’s because you are just a lonely little fuck with a superiority complex, you don’t even try to improve and use the fastest method to get ahead. Do you seriously think I’ve led you here only to save some lives?”

Zhang Dong Pointed out toward the ground that was under his opponent. During his stay here the outer city accommodated him for a few days. This was enough for an expert like him to lay some traps. He had expected things to go wrong and there were contingencies in place for such an occasion. While he didn’t have to use them as his sect arrived to help him now was the time.

Suddenly a strange array of magical symbols appeared below the spot Wang Long was floating over. It produced a spear-shaped golden construct that shot out towards the zombie dragon and its master. This was one of the traps that he had left over, only when Wang Long stopped was it actually worth activating.

The spear of golden light carried a lot of spiritual energy. It was similar to a full hit from Zhang Dong himself and was quite troublesome to hide within this city. Luckily Bob was there to help him hide this trap from Wang Long’s system. It was surprisingly easy as the systems were certainly not made to hide things from other system holders.

The person that created them probably didn’t expect anyone could do it and at least not at this level of power. Zhang Dong was also just lucky, he didn’t have the abilities to tackle this mystery. The real mind behind it all was the old immortal that allowed all of this to happen. In the future he wished to meet this man, perhaps they could talk about old games.

This golden attack which was a mix of magic and spiritual energy collided with the zombie dragon who was under Wang Long. A shield of pungent mist appeared out of nowhere to protect this beast. The attack was strong but it would probably be not enough to pierce through the evolved soul-beast.

Luckily for Zhang Dong, he wasn’t going against a very experienced opponent. Wang Long was someone that steamrolled through everyone while just using the system. His answer to his first big loss was to just get more power. Thus when against such a trap that seemed more dangerous than it actually was, he lost his composure.

There was no need for him to add more energy to the soul beast's shield. It would have been just enough to last through it, instead Wang Long should have been looking toward the opponent that was already charging at him. His attention was down on the sparkling spear while it should have been on his main enemy, Zhang Dong.

Through this blunder, he opened himself up to an attack that was barely evaded. A nick on Wang Long’s neck appeared and the added holy energy seeped into his flesh. Demonic Qi and Holy one didn’t like each other, this would create a chaotic reaction that would literally make his blood boil.

The pain was intense and not something that spoiled brat was used to. Soon came the follow-up attack as Behemoth the golden dragon collided with the creature with exposed flesh. Both of them went tumbling away while snapping and clawing at each other’s faces. Thanks to the radiant light surrounding the golden dragon it was able to last through the corrosive saliva that the other beast gave out. Soon their masters were left alone and the duel between them could finally start.
“You fucker!”

“Don’t talk or you might bite your tongue, junior.”

While the two monster dragons flew down to the ground their masters continued to the opposite side. Zhang Dong was on the attack as he was unwilling to give Wang Long time to react. To his surprise, it wasn’t as easy as he believed it to be. His trap was successful and he managed to dismount his opponent but even now as he was pushing, producing a mortal wound was hard.

“GET OFF ME!”

Wang Long roared out while producing a gigantic burst of demonic energy. This surprised even Zhang Dong, who had to defend himself from the excessive Qi that could even injure him if he wasn’t careful. A large ball of black energy surrounded the entire area and pushed everything to the sides. It was as if a miniature nuclear explosion went off and even the people that were fighting further away could feel everything.

‘Shit, I lost my momentum.’

Zhang Dong covered his face while backing away. The blast was strong enough to propel him backward. His plan was to overwhelm Wang Long with his quick movement and superior technique before he could activate any of his own. Perhaps he was superior in hand-to-hand combat but he was not too sure about the gap when it involved Qi attacks.

The system allowed anyone to get the best of the best without the need for crafting resources and mixing. Thus he wouldn’t wait, while the blast had happened he was already charging up for the follow-up. In his hand, he was holding a golden sword that at this very moment was already cleaving down to sever anything in its path.

A thin line appeared before him as even the dark clouds above them were severed in half. This produced a follow-up blast that brought all fighting around them to a stop. The powerful masters could only look in shock and awe at the battle that was taking place. To them it looked not like something a mortal should be able to produce, this was the realm of immortals.

Chapter 546

There was a giant explosion, everyone was stunned to see a massive shockwave rocking the entire outer city of demonic cultivators. Luckily everyone had already been evacuating since the first nascent soul master was spotted. Some ran for the outskirts where the poison mists didn’t reach while others went underground where there was a vast array of tunnels that could take them to a separate location.

Zhang Dong was the closest to this phenomenon. He wanted to do nothing else but to charge forward but the spike in energy was even too high for him. One of his strongest sword attacks was unable to cause much damage and Wang Long was continuously growing in power while surrounded by a twister of dark energy.

‘Did he copy my design or is this just something from the system store that he got…’

Before the dark mist cleared up he could tell what was waiting inside for him. It was something that looked familiar and could be seen on some superhero shows that he saw back in his old world. Without waiting he decided to activate his own version of this treasure before he got overwhelmed by Wang Long.

He didn’t have any music to accompany the transformation but quickly his body began to shine white. Soon after a suit of futuristic-looking armor appeared on his body, an improved version of the booster suits that he created for a few of his trusted retainers. His wife in particular had already adorned her own green suit that was further boosting her capabilities.

‘Still feels a bit uncomfortable…’

The suit was made from silvery-white metal. His whole body shivered as a prickly feeling took over. This suit to bring out more potential was somewhat infused into his flesh. Thanks to this it would feel like he was only wearing something like a layer of skin. The white overcoat started turning golden after his Qi started radiating everywhere.

This suit of armor was quite sleek and it hugged his body tightly. There weren’t really any parts that were sticking out and even the shoulder pauldrons were quite minimalistic. It was just there to boost his energies and to provide more defense than even his body refining technique could.

On the other hand, his opponent’s armor was a lot more intricate. As expected for someone that was going for a demon lord, the main color was black with a few crimson-red undertones. It looked similar to some fantasy full-body armors with spikes coming out from the back and pauldrons. The gauntlets had red fingertips that looked more like monster claws with the same pattern on his feet.

‘Did he go for the most edgy-looking one there was? It even has a cape…’

The cape had the image of a dragon on the back that looked similar to the zombie soul beast. Wang Long’s transformation was finished and now besides the bulky-looking armor, he was also holding a giant two-handed sword in one of his hands. The whole sword was longer than its user and would somewhat give him the reach advantage.

‘Hm… I’m not really sure if he knows what he is doing…’

While from the outside the gear that Wang Long looked cool and fashionable, it wasn’t that suited for the fight that they were having. Zhang Dong could already see the glaring weak points that this combo would bring. Yet even with those weak points the power radiating from his opponent was truly immense. The sword he was holding would probably be enough to cleave his body in half.

‘That is if he can get me…’

“Do you think you are the only one with cool toys? Did you really…”

Wang Long pointed towards Zhang Dong with the huge longsword that looked like it was made from a steel beam and then sharpened down. Before he could finish his villain monologue he needed to defend himself. His opponent was here to win, it was not a time for discussion anymore the person that struck first would be victorious.

With Zhang Dong on the offensive, the self-proclaimed demon king was pushed back towards the active volcano in the background. Finally, the battle was able to move to a safer location that wouldn’t endanger any of the two armies fighting.

Both of them created separate impact zones after they forcefully parted from each other. Small knicks and scratches were visible on Wang Long’s black armor and even some of the spikes were slightly bent. Zhang Dong on the other hand remained mostly untouched after they went through the scuffle.

‘If he wasn’t wearing that thing…’

He didn’t want to admit it but this wouldn’t be easy. His opponent received a lot more hits but it didn’t change the fact that the armor wasn’t coming off. Through the continuous exchange of blows he noticed Wang Long slowly improving. While he was lazy now, his background still contained training and improvement.

At least at the beginning of his story here there had to be a time that he diligently trained to get stronger. Gaining power rapidly was quite intoxicating so it wouldn’t be strange if at first, he gave it his all. Only after he beat everyone with the help of his skills and the system did he become the weak-minded man.

‘I have to take in his rate of improvement and finish this fast…’

It was true that with the help of the full system, Wang Long’s power level was above even his. The only reason he was able to produce better results was that he prepared and had more experience. But one wrong move and this whole thing could turn sour rather quickly.

“Fucking bastard!”

Luckily his opponent still had one glaring character flaw, his temper. After receiving so many nicks and scratches to his armor he was pissed. The large sword that he was holding started glowing in a shade-like hue. In a blink of an eye, all color faded from the world and Zhang Dong found himself surrounded by darkness.

It was as if all the light from the area along with sound was removed. He couldn’t even see his own limbs or detect his enemy that was standing there a second ago. This wasn’t good, this was clearly an attack meant to delude his senses. Wang Long was probably already coming toward him for a quick kill.

“This might have worked on others but it won’t work on me.”

Zhang Dong shouted while his whole body shone like a radiant star. Both of them had to clash Dao’s that they had mastered, he had the Dao of the Holy Element while Wang Long had switched over to the Dao of Unholy Darkness.

The flash of light was able to dispel the small area of effect technique that revealed a man clad in dark armor. The huge blade was in both of his hands and he was about to swing it down to cleave Zhang Dong in two. Before this could happen the blinding light was successful in slowing down his movements. The swing collided with the ground and produced another huge explosion.

Earth shattered before the mighty sword struck and produced a shockwave that traveled kilometers in one direction. Soon after lava burst out from this gash that appeared as if the ground had started to bleed. The man who was supposed to die from this strike was not there; instead, he dodged to the right side.

His right fist was clenched and radiating with golden lightning bolts. Right at the moment when the sword collided with the ground he a punch shot out. It collided with Wang Long’s face and also a small invisible barrier made by his Qi. The sound of glass shattering and metal bending followed suit as the strike connected.

Wang Long flew to the side after the clean hit to his face. The punch was strong enough to bend the rare dark metal that the demonic armor was made from. Yet even though the man was flying through the air, Zhang Dong didn’t give chase. He did not manage to fully evade the strike as his left limb which had been covered by the white armor had become exposed.

The pain was tremendous and some of his bones had actually been broken but it was the same for Wang Long. The helmet that was covering his head shot off into the distance. His exposed face showed a broken nose along with a missing tooth.

Yet this was not the time to rest, Zhang Dong gritted his teeth and soon after bolted towards where Wang Long flew. On the other hand, the demon king was quite shocked at what had happened to his face. It was clear that he was inexperienced, his lack of awareness would be his downfall.

Instead of keeping track of his enemy, he was more concerned about the pain around his face. This was only the second time he could remember this sort of pain. The last time was also through a punch to the face by the same opponent yet this time around it hurt a lot more.
His whole face was on fire as the infused holy energy was reacting with the unholy one that was ingrained into his body. Luckily dispersing it wasn’t that hard as he had a lot more energy than the amount that was infused. Even then the pain wasn’t going away, his body was rapidly mending itself but the shock didn’t go away.

While Wang Long didn’t really take a critical hit he was not used to being punched in the face. All of his previous wins seemed to have been gained through the help of his system without many setbacks happening. This reaction was clearly not something a master of this level should be showing. No nascent soul monster was able to go through life without properly being able to take a hit and continue fighting.

Zhang Dong, on the other hand, had gone through many setbacks. Even now while his left hand was healing itself he continued to push. If he couldn’t use this hand then he could punch with the other. If that one became unusable then two of his limbs remained and even without them, there was a myriad of ranged techniques that he could deploy.

Yet even when his hits landed he didn’t seem to be going that far. The unholy energy that was inside this armor and also inside Wang Long’s body was making it difficult to produce long-lasting damage. Masters like them could survive even with the bottom half of their body being destroyed, with time there was always a possibility of it regrowing. The only way to win would be by overpowering the opponent with Qi which damaged the body and nascent soul from the inside.

There was a strange phenomenon though, with each hit that connected his seed that was inside of him continued to react. It was as if the darkness that was inside of Wang Long was being slowly siphoned away and giving him a tiny boost of energy that caused his strange seed to evolve further…

Chapter 547

The clash between the two could be felt by anyone within the vicinity. Each punch and kick caused the air to vibrate and the ground to quake. Their power had reached the apex of what this world was supposed to be able to handle.

In the background, the cultivators continued their fight. Unless one of the leaders fell in battle they would continue. It was a race against time, if one of those beings of power came up on top one of their sides would probably lose. The only hope the losing side had was if both of them defeated each other, then the stronger faction would win and in this case, they seemed to be around at the same level.

The golden palace that hailed from the United Element Sect collided with the dark fortress from the Chaos Sect. People started piling out from both sides and engaging in hand-to-hand combat. Seniors and Juniors were drawing their last breaths as this fight continued. There was only one way to stop this carnage and Zhang Dong was frantically pushing toward it.

“What did you do to me!”

“Luck might be on my side again…”

Wang Long shouted out in anger while pulling up various demonic techniques. Chains of corrosive energy, poisonous mists, and qi absorbing techniques proved to be very effective against all of his other opponents. While all of those powers were strong, Zhang Dong was always able to counter or dodge them in some way. As always, the way that Wang Long gained those techniques was faulty. He did not delve into the way they worked on a deeper level and this was now the result.

Yet while Zhang Dong was barely able to hold on this was not the main reason for his success. During the battle, he noticed something strange, the unique seed that represented his current cultivation was slowly opening itself. With every collision between the two enemies, he was growing stronger and Wang Long was growing weaker.

‘I’m absorbing his negative Qi or perhaps something else? Could this seed be taking in the source of his power, that is the system?’

“Hey, Bob, any input on this? Can I really just absorb the system that he has?”

“Not enough data.”

“Yeah, I thought so…”

“Current probably of success is 26%, need more data to make a proper assessment.”

“26%!?”

Usually, Bob didn’t give him such big numbers when it came to things like this. If he had one in a fourth chance of this working then it was more than enough to make an attempt. This might have been it, a way to sprout this strange seed and go beyond the limits that this world had been created under. For it to happen however, he would need to stay close to Wang Long and let his seed absorb his essence. At this point in time, they were only quickly trading blows which didn’t allow it.

Suddenly Wang Long unleashed a pillar of black light that forced him away. To Zhang Dong’s dismay, he could not actually absorb the Qi directly. Only when he was touching his enemy's body was he able to take in his essence. This made him believe that he was actually taking in the system and not actually the spiritual energy or soul.

“What is this? What did you do?”

“Having some trouble with your system? Is something not working correctly?”

After replying in a mocking tone he waited for Wang Long’s reaction. He wasn’t actually sure what was happening but it seemed that the system window was malfunctioning. What his opponent was seeing had probably changed which meant that he was on the right track. Perhaps after more of the system, Wang Long would start losing the skill that he gained through it or at least the imparted knowledge that allowed him to use them.

“Target is attempting to flee.”

“You won’t be able to get away that easily.”

Zhang Dong expected Wang Long to flee at a point that he started losing but he didn’t think that he would do it this soon. Both of them had scratches on their armor and were bleeding but for masters like them, this was nothing. None of them was near a point of no return so this attempt to teleport away only showed how cowardly his opponent was.

“I just need to farm more points shithead, you might still have the advantage but don’t think that will last forever!”

From his opponent's standpoint, it was all due to numbers. In reality, Zhang Dong never had the number of spirit points that Wang Long did. Even when he had the full iteration of the system he had never managed to kill even one proper nascent soul master. While he could still gain points it was only through spirit stones and other resources, never by defeating others which came easy.

“Is that what you think? Perhaps you will never get it… but you’re not going anywhere, Bob, do it.”

“Activating the directive.”

Wang Long was fast to go towards his system window, his fingers were clearly clicking one of the options there. Either he was going to one of the available save points or to one of his faction members that were far away. His body began to flicker as the teleportation jump was about to trigger but right before the body vanished Bob interfered.

“What?”

“You can’t run from me.”

While Wang Long was confused about his failure to teleport Zhang Dong rocketed toward him without mercy. Instead of dodging, he continued to click the other options but even when he tried it was unsuccessful. His face collided with a full-powered lightning punch and the damage he suffered was true.

This was his chance, while normally his opponent would be sent tumbling into the distance this time around it was different. Before Wang Long’s body could be sent flying away he grabbed him. A barrage of attacks ensued as the dark armor protecting Wang Long’s body started to dent in all sorts of places.

Finally, after all this time, this protective shell started to give. His own gauntlets that once protected his fist had been shredded to pieces but he continued. The pain of his bones being shattered and rebuilt almost instantly was pushed aside as he attempted to end this battle. He could see it, Wang Long had turned into a punching bag and was unable to keep his mind in place. If he managed to knock him out for even a second then grabbing and taking the rest of the system was a possibility.

Then when he could see the light at the end of this pitch black tunnel a loud roar of a beast stopped him. The Zombie dragon that was battling Bahamut appeared out of nowhere. Its huge mouth filled with razor-sharp teeth opened up wide to devour both him and Wang Long.

‘Shit…’

This creature was strong and also a part of his enemy. Even if it devoured Wang Long he would not die, Zhang Dong on the other hand would probably not come out unscathed. After weighing the pros and cons of this situation he decided to retreat. Just as the teeth came down he propelled himself back and saw his enemy be eaten.

Bahamut was not far behind as the moment the zombie dragon ate Wang Long it sunk its teeth into its back. The teeth were used as an infusion point of energy in an attempt to destroy the being made of darkness and poison. While its master was safe the dragon was now injurer, yet this was not over as another burst of demonic Qi caused both Zhang Dong and his golden dragon to fly back.

‘What is it doing? Why is it shrinking…’

The monster dragon was vanishing before them. The flesh was turning into a pitch black liquid that was condensing into something. Quickly Zhang Dong realized that this was also a technique, one that allowed for the fusion between nascent soul master and their soul beast. This was what was taking place here, to alleviate the loss of his previous Qi and to heal from all the damage Wang Long decided to fuse with his beast.

This was not an easy technique and not something that other nascent soul masters would attempt to go through. Unless they had perfect control of their soul beast and the two nascent souls aligned, it could be dangerous. If someone failed they could even lose their life or suffer a decline in their cultivation. Some even thought that a perfect fusion was a way into the immortal stage but no one could confirm this claim to this very day.

“You look different…”

“Grrrr… w-what is this”

The transformation was somewhat successful but it seemed that Wang Long was unable to finish it. His body was larger with webbed wings fused to his back. His body was fully black and his legs and feet had assumed the form of the zombie dragon. There was a tail and even two horns sticking out of his forehead but then a twisted mix of facial features arose.

It was as if someone stuck Wang Long’s handsome face into a blender and then plastered it onto a mannequin. He looked truly horrifying, it was a face that only a mother could love. It was strange to make out what Wang Long was thinking. Perhaps this was due to all of his punches mostly focusing on the face. His holy Qi could have interfered with the transformation and it probably didn’t help that Wang Long’s system was malfunctioning.

“W-what did you do to me, this is all your fault… if… if you didn’t exist I would have had it all! I’m going to kill you!”

Finally, his enemy had lost all of his marbles as he charged. While this fusion of two nascent souls wasn’t fully successful it still gave his opponent a large power boost. Bahamut was also here to help but even when it tried to swing its large dragon claw on the now transformed Wang Long it was easily knocked back. Even the golden scales weren’t enough to protect his familiar from the damage.

‘Normally this would be the part where I combine with my soul beast and win this but I’m not really a nascent soul master…’

No one really knew that Zhang Dong’s cultivation was different. Bahamut was just something entirely separate and even if he was created from a part of his soul, fusing with it would kill the golden dragon. This didn’t mean that he was defenseless, his dragon couldn’t fuse with him directly but could perform an act that was quite similar…

Chapter 548

A change took place not to Zhang Dong’s being like when Wang Long combined with his soul beast but to the white beat-up armor. Instead of combining together into a singular being, Bahamut could enhance the prepared armament that was his full body suit.

All the scratches and dents on the silver piece of armor started mending themselves and changing color. Long gone was the bright silvery hue, it was replaced by a fully golden armor covered in scales. The change in design didn’t only consist of it going from silvery white to golden, it also came with an increase in size.

First of all, there was a set of large metallic wings on Zhang Dong’s back. Each one with a silvery claw at the end. The whole armor looked more like a mechanical suit similar to the golems that he came in contact with in the other world. Its source of power was just Bahamut instead and together with Zhang Dong it was boosted even further.

His familiar was more similar to a summoned spirit and he was actually a mix of spiritual energy and mana. Through some experimentation, Zhang Dong discovered this strange equipment-enhancing effect. The only requirement was that he needed to make the weapon or armor that Bahamut would inhabit. With the correct materials, the treasures would be boosted to a previously inconceivable degree.

Thus on one side stood a mix of man and creature with a face full of distortions. On the other side, there was Zhang Dong whose whole body was draped in shiny metal. The draconic features were noticeable on both and depicted the difference between light and dark quite well.

“I’ll tear you limb from limb and that tin can won’t save you!”

“Quite boisterous for someone that just tried to run away, you can still give up, just destroy your dantian and I’ll let you live.”

“Screw off! Do you really think I’ll believe that?”

Wang Long roared like a beast while producing a breath made out of deathly fog and acid. Yet Zhang Dong didn’t shy away from confronting his enemy directly. The dragon's power armor was equipped with full protection against all poison and corrosive effects.

These deadly techniques that demonic cultivators were proud of were why they usually won against orthodox opponents. During a battle, it would slowly erode away on the enemy making them lose a large chunk of their combat skills. The longer the fight lasted the more likely it was for the demonic fighter to win however, when this type of attack was rendered useless then things could quickly be reversed.

The giant sword that Wang Long previously wielded started glowing with purple energy. Yet even when he was swinging it around Zhang Dong utilized his new suit to fully dodge those swings. There were exhaust vents coming out of those wings that allowed him to move in various patterns that his enemy wasn’t used to.

The two masters had pulled out some of their trump cards in this battle that had only lasted for about ten minutes. Volcanic ash exploded everywhere as the two tumbled into the opening that was already mostly destroyed. Yet even when they were submerged by the magma inside none of them was even taking any damage. It was more of a hot bath than anything else and even when they tumbled through it they could survive.

Another wave of destruction filled the land as a catastrophic chain reaction occurred. As Wang Long and Zhang Dong were clashing in the lava it started a chaotic burst of energy. The magma burst out from the ground and started destroying the demon city. The Chaos Sect’s main area began to be flooded from the underground and whoever was hiding there had to evacuate. The entire place was getting destroyed and it wasn’t looking great for the demonic cultivators.

Back and forth they went but slowly the battle shifted in favor of the United Element Sect. Without a strong leader to hold them in check some of the demonic cultivators took the chance to escape. While this was the minority it did start to affect the morale of the troops that began trying to withdraw into their main sect area or into the flying castle. Even though the protective shields were mostly gone there were still large cannons and beasts they could command to protect them.

“Y-you, why did you have to ruin everything? This was supposed to be my story, I am the main hero, not you!”

“You really need to do something about that superiority complex… or is it just narcissism? Do you think that you can just walk all over everyone without any repercussions?”

“Those are not people, I am the only real person there… that’s right, you’re probably just one of them, after I kill you, the world will belong to me and I’ll be able to do anything that I want, this is just a test!”

Zhang Dong frowned as he looked at the person that was supposedly from his home world. It was clear that he had made up his mind about this place and was unwilling to listen to anyone. Perhaps he thought that he had already died and this was some kind of reward for his troubles? Did he think that if he won this competition of strength that he would achieve true freedom and live as a god?

The man before him was a true despot, he didn’t account for anyone's opinion but his own. Zhang Dong at least tried to listen to his people before making the decision. In the future, he hoped to retire and lead a quieter life but for now, he needed to get this issue out of the way. In the last confrontation between the two, his most powerful skill integrated all of his newly gained dao’s was charging up.

A small star formed in his hand and while expanding was then condensed even further. Gravity, light, and lightning were connecting with each other to form something that resembled a real Pulsar. This small neutron star of unimaginable mass would be thrown at his opponent. In this current confrontation, he had the high ground while Wang Long had landed in a ditch filled with lava.

His enemy wouldn’t just let himself be pushed back, above him a giant sphere of black energy was already being made. This wasn’t all, to top it off a figure of a massive black dragon appeared with its mouth in the middle of that sphere. It made it look like this giant creature that was a lot larger than the zombie dragon soul beast was performing a breath attack.

‘He still had this much energy left?’

“It’s too late if you realized, now die!”

Wang Long shouted, the giant black orb exploded while turning into a beam of pitch black ooze. It traveled forward while colliding with the star that Zhang Dong had created. To his surprise, the beam was holding on and the reason for it was the place where they ended up.

He had been fooled, his enemy that didn’t seem so bright had finally used his head. The battle was in the volcano which had a connection to the spirit vein. This same spirit vein was powering Wang Long’s new attack while putting a giant strain on his body. While he would not come out of this without an injury the attack would be indeed boosted by the large amount of corrupt Qi here.

‘Shit…’

His attack was getting pushed back, even when he included Bahamut’s power into it, there was still some missing. Slowly the Pulsar was getting pushed back, if this continued he would surely be devoured by that unholy energy. Before his eyes flashed the faces of his closest family members. For them, he tried to push himself over the edge.

Suddenly the orb of light that he produced started expanding as he injected more and more of his reserves. Yet this only amounted to creating a stalemate but who would be able to last for longer? The person that was almost out of energy or the one that was injecting himself with loads of corrupted Qi?

“Huh?”

Then as he was at his lowest he felt a hand touch his back. He didn’t even need to turn around to know who it was. A gentle type of energy that felt like a warm summer breeze flowed into his body as he felt empowered. This was not all, from the other side another palm landed on his shoulder. The energy it produced was a lot wilder, like an erupting volcano.

“Senior brother, you are not alone!”

“Did you think I’ll let my husband perish?”

Both Huo Qiang and Liena were standing behind him and lending their strength. If he was not in such a situation he would have replied in joy. Holding this technique in place was all that he could do and with the added energy the stalemate was being broken. This was not the end yet, a mass of spiritual energy attacks erupted from behind him.
“Aid the Patriarch!”

“For the sect!”

The golden fortress emerged from the rubble. Its walls were exposed and most of the cannons had been broken in the fight with the demonic castle. Even then the cultivators that were on it lend their energy to assault the one below. He was not alone, everyone that he brought here was with him and lending him strength. Who was he to deny them? As their leader, he had to win.

Wang Long continued to scream as his body trembled. Even as he attempted to absorb more energy his body started rejecting it. He had reached his limit and no one was there to save him. The demonic cultivators that he commanded were long gone and the city was being abandoned.

His kingdom which was gained by conquest was being destroyed by the same exact thing. This was the law of these lands, the one with the biggest fist ruled. Thus when someone appeared who possessed an even greater power, the kingdom would fall and so would their people.

‘Goodbye Wang Long…’

The man before him looked like a monster, he was something that he could have become if he didn’t lose the original system. However, he didn’t know, was this person evil from the beginning or was he just skewed into this caricature of a person by the results of his actions. He would never know as his death was something that needed to happen. With one last push, he forced his neutron star towards his enemy that would go out in a bang.

Slowly the demonic energy was pushed away and the attack collided. A massive explosion akin to a supernova encompassed the entire area. Everything was covered in white light and everything went silent. Even Wang Long’s screams of indignation couldn’t be heard as his body was slowly purified into nothingness. The battle was over and he had won but was this truly the end of it all…

Chapter 549

Tiny particles of white light gently rose into the sky as Zhang Dong’s mechanical armor started to fade away. His tired face and beads of sweat became apparent as the draconic mask vanished to reveal his tired expression. He was about to fall down to the ground after overtaxing his cultivation yet a gentle hand held on to him from the side.

“Are you alright?”

“Yeah, I’m fine, just give me a moment…”

Zhang Dong smiled at his wife who gave him a shoulder to rest on. Even though everyone had been lending him their power he was doing most of the heavy lifting. Below them, there was a giant hole that looked like an impact area from a large meteor. Slowly it was starting to fill up with lava from the side while the person in the center drew his last breath.

Wang Long was still there but he was barely holding on. Most of his body was gone, his legs and arms had been disintegrated during the overwhelming attack. What was left behind was just his upper torso and his head which were partially melted. There was nothing left of his old face after the combination of beast and man.

“We did it, senior brother, our sect has been victorious and the demonic bastards are running like the cowards that they are! Just give me an order and I’ll finish the job.”

Huo Qiang shouted while beating his chest. His body was all scratched up and even his nose had been broken during the fights but apparently, he still wanted more. Zhang Dong shook his head as this was not the time for more carnage

“That’s good to hear but let them go, there had been enough bloodshed for one day, we need to save our resources for later, we might have won this battle but the threats are still there.”

“My husband is right as always, you should try using your brain from time to time Qiang.”

Liena scoffed at Qiang while the muscle-bound man returned the action with a glare. It was clear that their sect had gone through a lot here. Even the golden bastion had its walls breached and it would need to be repaired. If they spread their troops too thin, they would be opening themselves to an attack.

A few recovery pills made their way into his mouth to help him stabilize his soul and body. Within a moment he regained enough strength to float down before his enemy that was on his deathbed. While the people around him looked to him as a defeated foe he wasn’t willing to ignore the potential of a turnaround. It always happened at these junctures, it wouldn’t be that strange if Wang Long had some kind of backup plan.

‘Bob, get ready to intercept it.’

“y-Y--u-U…”
There was still some fight left in those eyes but it didn’t seem that Wang Long could string together a full sentence. If looks could kill then he would have been dead on the spot. There was so much hate and indignation in those eyes. Zhang Dong didn’t feel that much remorse; the man before him had made his choice, which was now the result. He had tried to reach out an olive branch multiple times and it had been swatted away each time.

‘Affirmative’

This fight wasn’t quite over, even if his enemy was dying this was not the end of his plan. Just like the years before after a system holder was killed he would be replaced. He already knew thanks to the previous owner of the system that released him from the original system that this would happen.

Some kind of signal would be sent out and he needed to intercept it. If the people outside of this world knew that Wang Long had died, something drastic could occur. This world was already in the middle of the war between empires which was supposed to last for many years. A new system holder would be ill-equipped to enter this higher-level event at this point.

Zhang Dong’s biggest fear was that something like in the other world might occur. One of those strange overseers could appear and wipe everything off the face of the planet. This was his biggest fear that all of his friends and family would cease to be. Something like this would be called a hard reset but a soft one could also be an option.

In the case of the other one, instead of everyone dying the scenario would just play out and after the bridges between empires closed life would continue as it was. The new system holder would just arrive thousands of years later to repeat the cycle. Perhaps the beings above had some techniques related to time that would speed up the process even further.

While the second option wouldn’t be that bad he couldn’t risk it. It would be better to just block the transmission from going through. With his hacked system he could act as a dummy so that whoever was out there still thought Wang Long alive. After he was successful he would have some time to deliberate on his next step. Reaching the immortal realm wouldn’t be out of question, perhaps when he achieved that he would have the power needed to comprehend everything.

“y–y-u-u-u…d-DIE!”

Just as he expected Wang Long still had one trick up his sleeve. As he approached him a beam of black light escaped from his mouth. This technique was something that he could recognize, it was a last-ditch effort of a demonic cultivator to achieve victory. To everyone’s surprise, Zhang Dong didn’t do anything, he just motioned his hand toward everyone to signal that it was fine as he took the black energy beam to the face.

The moment the energy made its way into his body Wang Long’s body started crumbling into dust. It wasn’t important anymore as the system always stuck to the important part of its user, which was their soul. This soul was now trying to take over his body and that was something he was hoping for.
“Retard, I will eat you from the inside, and then that slut of a wife will be mine!”

“Is that so?”

“What!?”

Normally demonic possessions like this were hard to counter. These dark arts were studied by the evil cultivators while to the orthodox ones it was taboo. Thus most of the time the demonic expert won over the unprepared one in this confrontation. Zhang Dong was not like that, after his visit to the other worlds his soul energy was truly massive. There was no one in this world that would be able to contend with it and Wang Long quickly started to regret his decision.

The two found themselves in a word created by both of their souls. There wasn’t much there but some light and the void. Soon the world sprung to life and Wang Long found himself looking at gorgeous scenery that looked like paradise. He was not alone there as when looking up he saw a giant and this was Zhang Dong.

“You look different… so this is how you looked before coming here.”

Wang Long’s original appearance as an overweight keyboard warrior was revealed. At this moment he was standing on top of Zhang Dong’s palm and the difference between them was trouly massive. This size disparity was due to the amount of soul energy that the United Element Sect’s Patriarch was in possession of. His enemy looked truly pitiful but his actions had led him here and he needed to be punished.

“Wait, what are you doing?... No, please. Let me live, I give up, you can have that world, just let me live.”

It was finally clear to Wang Long that he had no chance of winning. Perhaps it was due to changing into his old form but the man’s bravado had instantly vanished. Instead, he was now down on his knees and trembling before Zhang Dong’s might. It was quite a pitiful scene but the deed needed to be done. Too many people had been killed by this narcissist and their souls demanded vengeance.

“No please, you c-can’t j-ust…”

Zhang Dong brought both his palms together and Wang Long’s voice vanished. His hands began to glow in a faint light as his energies began dispersing the soul essence of his foe. While Wang Long probably didn’t deserve it he offered him a painless death. It was slow and he would just feel as if he was falling into deep sleep that he would never wake up from.

‘Your time to shine Bob.’

‘Initiating suppression, attempting to suppress the ‘Devouring seed protocol’, please standby…’

Bob went silent while he compressed both of his palms onto Wang Long’s soul that contained the system within it. On the outside, everyone that had gathered was looking in amazement at the strange phenomenon. To them it looked like the black energy that collided with Zhang Dong’s face was forced down into his palms. It was as if he was trying to crush it with his hands.

“Should we do something?”

Huo Qiang asked while unsure if his senior brother was handling the situation well. Liena on the other hand believed in her husband, when he told her that he would handle it, then he would.

“Just wait a moment, I can feel that demonic soul vanishing.”

She was also a nascent soul master so to some degree she could feel Wang Long’s soul disappearing. It was being replaced by something else, something with a lot of power. When looking at her husband's hands she could see them slowly spreading apart to reveal a cube made of some sort of energy.

Before it formed a swarm of strange symbols appeared on top of it before a wave of energy knocked everyone away, including Zhang Dong that was trying to contain it. The cube floated there in place for a moment before dropping down to the ground where previously Wang Long’s corps was and the procedure concluded.

‘Suppression of the other system was successful.’

Zhang Dong gave out a sigh of relief as he gathered himself up. What was left of Wang Long was a nucleus and within it his system was stored. Now he was free to do with it what he wanted, absorbing it or even passing it to someone else seemed to be an option.

‘Finally, it's all over now, perhaps my life can return to normal…’

He smiled at the cube as all the tension left his body. This was finally the end, the other empires didn’t really pose much of a threat, and with this, he would have enough time to think of the next step in peace. However, unbeknownst to him, there was someone with different plans there…

Chapter 550

There it was, the item that would allow him to shed this mortal body. The seed inside of him was already reacting to it. The closer he got the more the feeling inside started to burst forth. Zhang Dong knew that if he used the cube that was created from Wang Long’s soul and body then he would finally reach the immortal stage.

This was something he was afraid of actually doing, it would probably be a point of no return. The history of this place stated that whoever reached the immortal stage would be somehow catapulted out of this world. It could happen to him as well, perhaps this world could not sustain someone at the immortal level or whoever created this place would yank him away.

He stood at a crossroad that went in many directions. The safest choice would be to grab the cube and save it for later. His longevity had not been used as he had at least five hundred years in the tank before he would even start to age. This time could be spent on training and getting ready for what could be beyond this world.

Then there was another reason that he wanted to go with this option and that was his family. Zhang Dong wished to actually spend some quality time with them for once. When he left this place then it could be the last time he sees his son, daughter, and wife. It was already a proven fact that a person could wait it out even into the older years.

His predecessor only ascended after getting too old to sustain his longevity, with Wang Long’s death there didn’t seem to be any rush. The demi-human emperor was strong and the others were probably around his level. This was not something that his improved sect couldn’t handle. The longer they trained the stronger they would become and the easier it would be to defeat the remaining enemies.

Yet the urge to just sit down in the lotus position was strong. The people that were gathered around here didn’t move but they did realize that this item was something special. Perhaps if he didn’t consume this cube now he would not get a chance later. What if someone got to it before he could use it or if it was discovered by the hidden overlords? Maybe he needed to risk it and just try attaining the immortal stage that everyone dreamed of.

His hand reached out towards the cube that started to float up and towards him. The seed inside of him started to instantly react. It started to pulse with life and expand the closer the nucleus containing Wang Long’s system and Dao approached. The moment it touched his body the process might even be started forcefully.

‘No… it’s too soon… I don’t know what might happen, it's best to not use a trump card this soon…’

The cube stopped just a meter before him as he put his hand down. It was calling out to him but he did not want to go through the change yet. Instead, he needed to lock this thing away so that it wouldn’t beckon to him this much. For this he would need to lock this thing away, with his current knowledge that he lifted from his predecessor he knew what needed to be done.

With a wave of his hand, a set of strange symbols started to circle around the floating cube. It was a powerful seal that would help him keep this item hidden from even the overseer that probably resided somewhere in this world. At least that was what Bob’s calculations determined so he couldn’t be entirely sure if it would work.

As the rune-like symbols floated around the aura of the cube became fainter. Previously it was glowing with a bright white light but soon it began to turn gray. Finally, it dropped down to the ground while becoming solid black. Now when it was sealed it would be even fine if he held it directly by his hand. Only with the help of Bob would a person have enough computing power to disperse this seal here.

Now he just needed to reach out and take it. After the item was inside of his spatial ring or spatial treasure he could keep it safe. However, when he tried to reach out with his hand to make the now sealed nucleus towards him, it didn’t react. Did the battle along with the sealing technique take this much of a toll on him? He could have sworn that he recovered a lot after swallowing some high-quality pills.

“Liena could you perhaps… Liena? … Qiang?”

If he was too weak then it was natural to ask for help from his wife but there was a problem. When he turned his head towards her she wasn’t moving. No one was moving, it was as if time had stopped for everyone but him. Then he noticed that the cube was acting up, it floated up slowly before shooting into the distance.

Even when he tried jumping after it, his body felt really sluggish. The connection to his cultivation base had been cut off and even the strange seed that was giving him power wasn’t reacting. He was powerless to stop the item from going away and this only confirmed his previous fear. Perhaps it was better to absorb this thing when he had the chance but now it turned to the worst-case scenario.

‘Is it an overseer?’

While he had no power to do anything his eyes still worked. When he traced the flight path of the cube he noticed a lone figure floating in the sky. To his surprise, it was indeed someone that he knew, a person from the Long Clan. In the previous world the administrator took the form of the King but here it was different.

“... The Azure Dragon Empress?”

“Yes, that is the title that belongs to this body.”

Her reply was almost robotic, it lacked any kind of emotion. The woman that stuck around Long Qing didn’t act like this. She played the role of the gentle matriarch that made life worth living for the Azure Emperor. Was this all a scam? Was the Emperor in on this or was he just a puppet that didn’t know anything?

It somewhat made sense that someone from the Long Clan would be involved. The Empress’ position was only below the Emperor so she could do almost anything without being second-guessed by anyone. Long Qing was in the forefront so she wouldn’t be suspected by anyone, even Zhang Dong had to agree that he couldn’t find anything suspicious with the pair.

“Could you return that? I kind of need it…”

“Return it? I can’t do that, this should not exist here… but this is peculiar, why can you still move?”

“Uh well…”

“The being has a system but it can still move… this has not been planned. It goes against the world order, is it an error? No… the great one does not make mistakes…”

The beautiful woman grasped the cube and started examining it. Her gaze moved toward Zhang Dong, that look that lacked any emotion made his skin crawl. It was as if he was some kind of lab rat. Her monologue at least revealed some more truths and actually confirmed something.

‘So there is a being behind all of this…’

The mention of the great one did raise some eyebrows. It meant that there was one grand being behind all of this madness. The demon lord from the magical world had decided to erase it but this one was different. Even now she was mumbling to herself without even paying attention to Zhang Dong who was listening.

Time had actually stopped for everyone here. He could not hear anyone breathing or any heartbeats, nor was there any wind anywhere. Moving through space was strange but for some reason, he could do it. Perhaps after absorbing some of that nucleus his cultivation had reached a new height. The seed inside of him did become a bit bigger and something wanted to sprout.

“A decision needs to be made…”

To the woman, it didn’t seem that he existed. Her focus was on the cube but to his surprise, she wasn’t able to crack it open. It was strange to see a being of immense power scratching her head while shaking the cube. Perhaps even overseers had limits to their capabilities. Interacting with a system item could be above their clearance.

“The story has not yet ended…”

Was the last thing that escaped from her mouth. The cube she was holding was somehow hidden into her own gown. Her gaze moved back towards Zhang Dong that wanted to ask many questions. Yet instead of answering them, he started getting warning signals from Bob.

‘Mental attack had been attempted… scrambling was successful…the user will not suffer any memory loss… attempting to hide the fact from the administrator…’

“Huh?”
He called out in shock when looking at the prompt. If what Bob was showing him was correct then he had to act the part to get out of this alive. For this he started looking around in a daze as if he was not aware of where he was. His hand moved to his head to play it off as a migraine and to his surprise, the woman that was floating above him took this as a fact.

It was strange but it worked, it was as if the overseer couldn’t fathom their mind-affecting technique ever failing. Within a second of performing it, she vanished and the world regained its coloring. The sight was quite peculiar as everything started moving very slowly before returning to normal.

“Are you done, husband?”

“I uh… yes, we should gather up the injured, don't pursue the demons, we don't have the time for that…”

The whole encounter was quite unsettling but it seemed that this administrator intended to let him ride out this scenario. She referred to it as a ‘story’ that probably included the enemy empires that were still active outside. He had gained another chance in the face of this powerful being but he had also lost his ticket out. As long as the cube was in that woman’s grasp he would probably not be able to reach the immortal stage.

‘I’m back to square one… at least Wang Long isn’t a problem anymore…’

One problem was solved but was quickly replaced by another one. His only option was to get his people out of here first before attempting to figure out his next best option…

Chapter 551

“What is troubling you?”

“Troubling me? It’s nothing, just worried about the direction the sect is heading, that's all”

“Is that it? The sect is just growing but the people revere you, maybe a little bit too much. If they only knew that their leader worried this much~”

Liena smiled while giving her husband a peck on the cheek. It was time for her to head out as the two were quite busy. Now that the danger of Wang Long had ended and their power was shown to the world, they needed to continue to improve.

The lands that they reclaimed during the demi-human invasion were now practically theirs. Other clans and sects that once fled back to the middle reaches continued to swarm back to their homes. What was supposed to be an army for the Azure Emperor was quickly becoming his own faction.

In quite a short amount of time, the United Element Sect had become one of the big powerhouses of the Empire. They were now considered to be part of the big three and a replacement for the Soaring Dragon Sect. Zhang Dong was viewed as a rising star that was perhaps only second to the Azure Emperor. Some even believed that he was stronger as he achieved this much in not even a year.

Zhang Dong and his sect had achieved something that even the previous powerhouses couldn’t. They had successfully infiltrated the demonic island and dealt a lasting blow to the evil cultivators. Their city was in ruins and the demons had fled, while they weren’t fully eradicated it would take them millennia to get back to their previous glory.

It was already enough for Zhang Dong to defeat Wang Long who had destroyed the age-long Soaring Dragon Sect by himself. Not everyone believed that it was done in single combat between the leaders but it was enough to make everyone speculate. Could there be a new world order coming and which side should they join before it was too late?

On one side there was the tried and true Azure Emperor and the Long Clan that had existed for many millennia. However even they didn’t engage in a fight with the demi-humans or the demonic cultivators as if they were afraid of them. One side proved their might while the other one was showing weakness.

Even now in the east, a new battle was taking place and flags of the Emerald Phoenix Empire were being placed everywhere. Where was their great leader the Azure Emperor? He remained back at his castle without sending any kind of aid. The only thing that he did was allow anyone to retreat to his lands. Then when people arrived there they were forced into temporary militia forces and treated unfairly.

On the other side to the west of the Empire, it was different. The Golden Dragon had managed to clear up the bloodthirsty demi-humans and even fixed the issues with the demonic cultivators in the north. People could return to their homes and be free to do anything, there were no forced conscriptions and the sect even allowed them to withhold paying any taxes until they got back on their feet. The sticks of the Golden Dragon were on the rise while the Azure Emperor was beginning to be seen as a tyrant.

“I have to go, there is still much work to do, the barricades at the western regions have been almost fully assembled but the scouts have spotted movement.”

“The remnants of the demi-humans trying to return home?”

“It might be.”

“Maybe I should go instead what if…”

“I can handle myself, I am not a child and if something happens that idiot will also be there, now stop worrying.”

After a little back and forth Liena left him to his own devices. The world moved on but he was stuck on what happened several weeks ago. There he interacted with this world's Overseer and who was the wife of the Azure Emperor. She was under the impression that his memories were wiped clean.

This didn’t give him any solace as the worst-case scenario could happen at any moment. What if she contacted the grand being that was apparently the one responsible for it all? What if she decided that this world was lost and needed to be restarted again? But would she do this now after so much time had already passed?

Zhang Dong thought back to that day when he defeated Wang Long. The cube that he could use to reach the new stage was taken away and he was left with more questions than answers. Nothing really happened after the encounter, she nor the Azure Emperor contacted him in any way. It was as if the even never happened to begin with and that the scenario could play itself out.

‘Bob, are you sure that she won’t do anything with that nucleus?’

‘Affirmative, world overseers are designed to supervise the world, they will only act if they discover an anomaly that can threaten the balance of the world.’

‘Yeah…’

His handy Ai that had all the knowledge of his predecessor kept reassuring him. The administrator of this world would not act unless there was a big enough issue. Even when the whole world was destroyed they wouldn’t act out and instead just wait. Only when something that shouldn’t happen occurred would they act. Thus only after he was about to reach a new stage of being that was alien to this world did she come forward.

‘I guess this confirms my previous suspension, they will probably let the world play itself out and summon another system holder after the war is over and many thousands of years pass… should I just accept this…’

This was the big question he needed to ask himself. Did he really want to continue on this path that could break the cycle but would also endanger everyone he loved? The first time he prodded the beehive he wasn’t stung but if he did it again then perhaps everything would end.

There was no guarantee that things would remain like this. Perhaps the next time the Empress saw him she would realize that the memory-altering attack didn’t work. She would probably not be as sloppy the other time around. The only reason he got away with it the first time around was that she didn’t take him seriously. If he was deemed to be a bug in the system that couldn’t be fixed then he was done for.

‘Bob, is there really no way of getting rid of that time-stopping technique?’

‘Insufficient data.’

This was one of the biggest problems, during the encounter she was able to fully disable his entire cultivation base. Perhaps with enough system points, it would be possible to counter it but his Ai wasn’t sure. The time he spent under the effect was too short for Bob to make an assessment. He would need to put himself under that effect again to know the answer.

‘At least I found another one of these…’

He looked at another cube that he discovered in the demonic lands. It had been around the volcanic region where Wang Long’s castle was. Luckily his enemy wasn’t smart enough to look at his own map to see the strange dark space. It was an entry point for other orders like them and probably for ones that decided to start with demonic arts as a base.

The cube he was holding still had some juice left in it and could be used for an injection of spirit points. For some reason, he felt like it would be better to hold on to it instead of absorbing it outright. Having a trump card like it wouldn’t be a bad idea and he could always get more points in a different fashion.

One of these ways was the corrupt spirit vein that still resided in the demonic region. After taking over the place he decided to slowly siphon it for more points to prepare for the future. While the issue with the overseer was the largest problem there were some others. There were still two hostile empires that needed to be driven back and perhaps a third enemy.

‘Will Long Qing and the Long Clan just remain passive like this? He could also just be a puppet of that administrator, there is no way of knowing what they will do now…’

This uncertainty had already brought him many sleepless nights. Perhaps it would be fine to just dial it down and let this story play out. After a thousand years, he would just die but his life would have been quite eventful. He had a wife and kids, something that he never thought was possible.

But as a father, he could not stop worrying. What if the great overlord above the sky decided it was time to erase it all? What if he reached the immortal stage or whatever the seed let him sprout into? What if perhaps he could challenge that god with that newly gained power? There had to be a reason why it was keeping the power level low and didn’t allow the cultivators to reach heights beyond the nascent soul level. It must have been afraid of potential enemies that could interfere with its plan, what this plan was, he did not know.

‘That administrator let me live for a reason, at least it can’t read my thoughts or could detect Bob that can imitate the true system, to it I might as well have been Wang Long and everything is going according to plan.’

Zhang Dong looked out of the window of the rebuilt mansion. There he saw his two kids playing with the toys that he made. Their smiles were the current driving force behind his actions and probably the only reason that he didn’t go crazy.

For the time being, he would need to play along with the forces that governed this world. The Empress was probably watching his every move, perhaps she even had a way of peeking inside of this very room he was staying in. Two enemy empires and one that he was neutral with still remained.

He needed to gather more power, perhaps there was another way to reach the immortal stage. At least two of the enemy emperors could give him greater Daos. The way towards advancement wasn’t closed off to him just yet. He needed to move forward and guide his people and family toward victory.

“Fine, I’ll play along…”

Zhang Dong nodded before floating out of the window, his next point of interest being the far north where the sea creatures awaited…

Chapter 552

“Where are they taking us?”

“Where do you think? Probably right into a pill cauldron…”

“No, I don’t want to die! Let me go!”

“Hey, be quiet!”

A large group of prisoners was being transported before a large teleportation gate. All of them had one thing in common which was that they had been the residents of the demon city ruled by the Chaos Sect. Now that that faction didn’t exist anymore they were at the mercy of this United Element Sect that they knew nothing about.

It was a mix of actual demonic cultivators and people with no power that had mostly given up on their life. There were some indignant to call it quits just yet, they pushed and tried to run but the chains they were wearing didn’t allow them to gather any spiritual energy inside of their bodies. They were quickly pushed back in line and forced to go through that gate that probably led to their doom.

“So this is how it ends…”

A middle-aged man gave out a sigh while his group was the next one to step through. He had been forced to participate in the war and managed to survive. His power wasn’t small but it was not large enough to matter. His previous master had died during the battle but now he would either get a new one or be turned to cultivation resources. This was something that he had already made peace with but what lay on the other side of the gate was not something he expected.

“Hurry up, we don’t have all day, you’re part of group G.”

“What is this…”

The man called out in shock as the hell he imagined wasn’t waiting on the other side, instead, it looked like paradise. The air was filled with spiritual energy, the grass was green and full of life. In the distance, he could hear the chirping of birds and the people that were there seemed different. They were actually smiling, something rarely seen in the demonic regions.

“Group G, follow me you’ll be taken to your new home.”

“Our new home?”

People from the demon faction looked at each other with puzzled expressions. All around them there were similar groups. They were taken onto floating barges and flown out somewhere. The entire place looked like some kind of strange airfield through which they would be flown to different parts of wherever they were.

“Hurry up and be grateful to our great leader's magnanimity, if it was up to me you all would be turned to fertilizer!”

A rather scary-looking core formation cultivator was responsible for this group. There was no compassion in his eyes and this old man could feel it. There had been an order from someone over them and it seemed to be the sect leader. This man had shown himself during the large-scale battle and his tremendous power could not be denied. Even someone like the demon king was not able to stop him.

Everyone wanted to ask more questions but they were all suppressed by the guards. Time was apparently not something that these people wanted to waste. Soon around two thousand people made it onto this barge and were forced to stand shoulder to shoulder while it took off. The view wasn’t that bad and a spirit shield protected them from the wind so they had enough time to take everything in.

There didn’t seem to be anything worthwhile besides nice-looking vegetation. The beasts that were below them were of the Qi condensation variety which made this old man think that it was the empire's outer region. Even though the ship was fast it took half a day for them to arrive.

“We are here, get ready to disembark, and not a word from anyone, you will get your instructions from your group leaders down on the ground.”

No one dared to speak up or voice any complaints. They all came from the lands of demons where a person could die from looking at the wrong person. Life was cheap and everyone knew that if they actually wanted to live they needed to adhere to the ones in power. The old man could see barren fields everywhere and a lack of greenery. It didn’t take much deliberation to figure out what they were here for.

The instructor took them to a strange blocky looking building. It lacked any characteristics known to them and was quite basic. This was their new living quarters but they weren’t that bad on the inside. He expected it to just be an open space where they would be given blankets at most.

“Divide yourselves into groups of three, fighting is not allowed, the rules are written down on this board so learn to follow them or you will be punished.”

At first glance, this looked to be some type of concentration camp. However, for being one the living conditions weren’t bad. The old man got a room with two other people of a similar age. This room had a strange bed that was soft and blankets to keep him warm at night. They were given new clothes, food, and the only thing that they needed to do was work the fields.

“This isn’t that bad… it’s nothing compared to the work I needed to do at the old restaurant… they don’t even hit you even if you make some mistakes…”

“Right? We even get some free time to chat like this!”

When overhearing conversations between the others at this encampment he wasn’t sure what he felt. The working conditions were good, and even though they couldn’t leave it was better here than it was back in the demonic city where a person's life was constantly threatened.

They treated the old well, if someone couldn’t contend with the weather outside they would be given other tasks like helping around the cafeteria or cleaning. But thanks to the constant food supply even the elderly started recovering from being malnourished. Most of the time these people were discarded and deemed useless, here on the other hand they could be useful once more.

Who was this radiant Golden Dragon that made all of this possible? The man and the others kept asking themselves. At first, they believed that the orthodox sect just wanted to brainwash them over to their side but as the weeks passed nothing changed.

They continued to plant trees and grow food and apparently, if they worked for at least twenty years they would be able to leave. While their demonic cultivation would be sealed they could spend the rest of their life free. There was also a way of retaining some form of their power but no one was sure what to think about it yet…

…

“This is an unorthodox method but it seems to be working.”

“Yes, the Patriarch outdid himself again, who would have thought that we could just use these demons like this?”

“You should all stop doubting the Patriarch, his plans aren’t something that we can fathom!”

“Indeed, it might be best for relics of the past like us to just make way for the new generation…”

A group of elders was sitting around a large meeting room. With new technology available they were just looking at some still slides on a large screen. There statistics of the current demonic cultivator redevelopment plan were shown.

At first, no one knew what they should think of it. Zhang Dong, their leader decided to spare almost everyone from that cult. Only the most heinous criminals that already went too far were given a swift death. The rest was guided out of those lands filled with miasma and death.

It was a mix of commoners and cultivators. They were all taken to undeveloped regions where spirit energy was lower. There they would work the lands as farmers and produce food and herbs. A plan for new villages and cities was also being worked on. After these criminals were done with their sentence they would be given small homes and some land that would be theirs.

“Truly a marvelous idea, by giving them their own land even these hoodlums have something to strive for, and it's all produced from their labor so we don’t need to pay a single spirit stone!”

“That is true, we can use the herbs they produce for pill making and sell them for profit, even the surplus food they create can be used. Even if these people weren’t loyal to us before they will now!”

“It’s interesting, their view of our sect and Patriarch is becoming more favorable with each day. While there will be some bad apples, if we can change the minds of the majority then we can only profit.”

In the end, all of those people were war criminals that would normally die or be worked down to the bone. That was a very shortsighted way of looking at it and the elders here now believed it too.

By taking these people under their wing they would produce loyal servants to their sect. They would probably be grateful for the freedom they were given and a new chance at life. There always existed a possibility of an uprising but with the current disparity of power that wouldn’t be probable.

“Well then, I think we all agree that this has been a success but our Patriarch doesn’t seem to want to take a break.”

“Yes, he has taken an interest in the northern sea, now that we have forces in the demonic lands they can act as a base for our warships.”

The slides changed to something else; it was a new type of ship that had recently begun production. It didn’t look like much as it was shaped like a torpedo and had no sails. This was understandable as it had been created to contend with the underwater currents in the vast ocean.

“This one might be troublesome, our forces haven’t recovered from the last battle…”

The old men and women here looked troubled. They didn’t want to speak up but to them going from one battle to another wasn’t the greatest idea. In their eyes, they needed to bunker up and spread their influence in the Empire. Now was the time for growth and the continuous war would only bring more death and perhaps even weaken their standing.

“We must trust in the Patriarch, he has always been able to see through the veil, perhaps this is a chance to enrich ourselves even further!”

Some people nodded while others continued to ponder the expansion of the current sect. While they had gotten stronger they also drew in the eyes of others. Would the other powers in this empire just allow them to grow without interfering…

Chapter 553

“...”

“Patriarch?”

“Woah… don’t sneak up on me like that!”

“I apologize, Patriarch, please punish this Zhang Zhi accordingly!”

“No… it’s fine… what is the problem?”

Zhang Dong was deep in thought while Zhi approached him from the back. So much that he was startled by even someone like his retainer. The last few weeks had been nerve-wracking on his psyche. Even with the good old tranquil mind technique, he continued to worry and look over his shoulder.

To what extent the Overseer would act was unknown to him. Perhaps she was constantly watching him through some device he couldn’t fathom. There were immortal grade items on the system store that perhaps the administrator could use. What if the brainwashing failure would be figured out sooner than he could gather the power necessary for his ascension?

Thoughts of an inevitable end clouded his mind and continued to drive him towards his next enemy. The faster he took care of the two remaining forces of the empires the better. Only after absorbing the Dao’s they had would he be able to break through. Only with a newfound power could he ever hope to go against someone that broke this world’s rules.

“I just wished to inform you about an unusual sighting at the shore line. A strange object that resembles an island had shown itself along with various sea creatures surrounding it. They are making it troublesome for our spies to approach.”

“I see, they might be trying to establish a foothold to invade the lands.”

“Our strategists are of the same mind Patriarch, they wish to observe further before sending out our forces that had been diminished but if you give the order, I will direct our brothers to battle myself!”

“No that won’t be necessary, just keep watching from afar and I’ll call for you when the need arises.”

“As you wish.”

Zhang Zhi clasped his hands but there was a look of disappointment in his eyes. Zhang Dong knew what the problem was as he was able to overhear some people talking his disciples included. Everyone was feeling that his position as Patriarch should be taken more seriously. The constant engagement with stealth missions was only one of the problems. They feared that one of these days he would put himself somewhere that he won’t be able to escape from.

‘They aren’t wrong… strictly speaking, there is no need for me to join these battles anymore.’
His forces were evolving and advancing at a rapid pace. All the lands that the demi-humans and demonic cultivators occupied were now under his jurisdiction. Not even the Azure Emperor or the Heavenly Crane Sect could demand it back from him. His side had proven that they are capable of competing with the big boys.

Wang Long’s death was a surprise to everyone. Naturally, the sects in power tried to spin it their own way. Either the person that they were fighting was injured or they themselves had become a demonic sect. The invasion of the city of demons and the subsequent absorption of the whole island was somewhat suspicious.

Without proper evidence, they could not pin anything substantial. This didn’t mean that they couldn’t find something to accuse them of. If they really wanted to start a war then claiming that he and his faction had become bloodthirsty demonic cultivators would probably be enough as a reason. It wouldn’t be that easy however, his reputation of a magnanimous being had already spread through the whole empire and could actually benefit him.

“Before you go, were we able to get our fishy friends to talk?”

“No Patriarch, they have proven somewhat resistant to the mind-bending skills, and the more we prod the more their minds deteriorate.”

It seemed that the fish people he had previously captured had some kind of mind-controlling spell cast on them. They were unable to speak whenever asked about their leaders, plans, and forces. The moment they tried to give out this information while under the usual techniques their minds would boil. Afterward, they would not be able to remember anything and their cultivation base was eradicated.

‘Whoever puts such mind blocks on their commanding officers can’t be the soft type, probably all of their forces will turn into berserkers to protect their leaders.’

It was a similar technique to what demonic cultivators used. No one would be able to go against the person performing the spell and if they tried their mind would be fried. Though it was disheartening to see that even the nascent soul-level masters were put under it. Whoever led these sea creatures must have been quite pedantic about them being loyal.

‘It could also be some kind of racial skill, perhaps they have some type of hive mind mentality, like ants or bees?’

The being that he took for questioning had died during the interview and they had examined their body. The nascent soul ones that looked more human didn’t actually have any human DNA in them. It was clear that they evolved from some other creatures entirely which made them different from the demi-humans that were changed through millennia of body refinement.

‘This could be more troublesome but I shall cross that bridge when I get there…’

Now he had to make a decision, would he use his sect for what it was created for or endanger himself alone like he always did? His forces had just gone through some rest and their healing arts were one of the best in the whole empire. The golden palace that was half destroyed was quickly being restored. This was all thanks to the corrupted spirit vein that was slowly being converted into spirit points and repairs.

It wouldn’t be totally out of the picture to continue with his attack. The biggest problem was the field the enemy appeared in. The sea creatures had the advantage over his flying ships and anyone that tried to fight underwater. Some of the battle formations needed some tuning and testing as well.

His forces were growing but it was clear to him that without the Golden Dragon around they wouldn’t be taken as seriously. Even though the number of nascent soul masters had increased thanks to his system and continued to grow, they were mostly only ones in name. It took many years of study to get to that level, battles between such masters would usually go to the one with more experience if the power difference wasn’t that drastic.

‘I might not always be here, they need to learn to take care of themselves without me around.’

He might have been looking at it in a pessimistic way but he had no idea of knowing what would happen in the future. The last time he vanished for five years his sect was almost destroyed by Wang Long. Even if they eradicated all the invaders the Azure Emperor or the Heavenly Crane Sect could begin to see them as an eye sore. It was important to secure the safety of his children and allies, for they needed to take some of the responsibility off his hands.

The recent attack proved that they were able to contend with powerful beings themselves. There were many masters under Wang Long’s influence that were world-class fighters. Perhaps if the army was more tightly knit they could have pushed for a stalemate. The moment their leader was down for the count they just fled the scene and were in hiding even now.

‘A slower approach might be in order, if I rush into it then that woman might come for me…’

A decision had been made and growing his forces came first. He would not totally abandon the rush for power but some concessions needed to be made. The people that showed the most promise needed to be gathered up and further groomed into proper warriors. This batch would include some of the nascent soul masters while also some core formation experts that did well, his disciples included.

‘I should give Kuo a call…’

Thankfully he didn’t really need to go through much to find people that were talented. His faction part of the system would do that for him. He could even order it depending on potential and loyalty towards him and the sect. Only trustworthy people would be helped to reach a new height. It would take some time but even both of his disciples could soon reach the nascent soul level as long as he retained the system. While his dependency on it never went away it was a necessary evil.

‘It won’t help me that much with understanding the Dao though, without that cube I might have to get it myself.’

The world here was not made with the intention of giving the system holders that much insight. Just as Wang Long proved it just injected the base knowledge that the user most of the time didn’t fully grasp on their own. Perhaps if he went through this journey the correct way he could even skip battling the remaining two or three Emperors.

But such an endeavor required time and probably a lot of it. Luckily with Wang Long’s death came some peace. Locking himself in a cultivation chamber at this point in time could do him some good. He had been going through the motions of rushing towards the next big battle without really understanding what he was sitting on. Understanding the power that was slowly budding inside of him could be very beneficial.

The fighting within the Empire was also dying down. The sea people were trying to establish forward bases which he was planning to counter. To the east where the Emerald Phoenix Empire had invaded people had already either submitted or fled to the lands of the Long clan. Even without him interfering that area would probably be fine.

Lord Lucius and Argus didn’t come along for the demonic extermination but were still looking for the holy weapon parts. They weren’t true enemies and didn’t really push into the cultivator-owned cities. It wasn’t a given that they would remain neutral but for now, it was safe to assume that they would.

He had already allowed them access to the lands that were under his new jurisdiction. It wasn’t that hard, they just needed to imprint the characters of the United Element Sect onto their armor. This way they would not be attacked and everyone would be fine with cooperating with their relic searching efforts. If they wanted to delve into the other side of the empire then they would need to face off against the other invaders, which was all up to them.

‘I guess taking a backseat for once won’t be such a bad thing…’

After glancing at his faction window that could be used as a hub between his faction members he decided to head out towards the sea region. He would at least see what the ocean people were up to before fully deciding on his next action.

A note from Kuropon

Thank you for reading!

Don't forget to follow, favorite, rate.

Donate | Discord |

Chapter 554

“So that’s it… do we have any information on their movements?”

Zhang Dong floated high in the sky while looking into the distance. Even with his enhanced sight, he could only see a tiny speck of land. It was a lot smaller on the outside but its size expanded exponentially when going underwater. This was something similar to an island or at least something made to look like one. Anyone below the nascent soul level would be unable to tell it apart from any other tiny mass of land.

“Our scouts aren’t versed in underwater travel, the dummy ships we sent with the wooden puppets had been quickly destroyed by the sea creatures. We confirmed six nascent soul-level beasts in the vicinity; the core formation ones number around a hundred but there is also a swarm of weaker ones.”

“They sure have a lot of meat shields…”

He rubbed his chin while using his own spiritual sense and system screen for scanning. The number was around the same but he also spotted one stronger monster in the vicinity. It made the other ones look like sardines but it wasn’t clear if it was actually an enemy yet. The beast in question was actually the island itself. The mass of dirt and corals that was encasing it kept it from being seen as anything other than a small island.

To his knowledge, there were more of these monster islands floating along the shoreline. They were quickly spreading these strange creatures through the area. There were a few theories that he had about them but two were the most probable. Either they were there as a means of protecting the sea and their new lands or to act as some sort of springboard to infiltrate the lands.

‘Can those things be used to flood the mainland or something, or is it just supposed to be some kind of underwater fortress…’

There was a lack of information he was working with. Normally this would be the time for him to sneak over to the closest fake island to check it out. However, there was no need to rush, without Wang Long there or any other system users he could take his sweet time. The administrator was out there but at the moment he could not do anything about it.

It was more important to build up his faction to its fullest before the confrontation. His system was somewhat different to the old one but it had its strong points. At least when it came to his sect he could continue to upgrade anyone that met the criteria. If they had him in a favorable light they could directly affect their progress by spending points on them. It was probably a better system than the fear one Wang Long was using for his people.

He could not directly affect his own cultivation base anymore thus spending points on his closest family members and retainers was the next best thing. Even in the fight with Wang Long they had helped him close the gap at the last second. Perhaps when facing off against the other emperors and the Empress they were the key to victory.

Zhang Zhi

|

Nascent Soul [ Early Stage 85% ]

Main Dao:

|

Water [ 57 % ]

Main Weapon:

|

Katana [ S - Grade ]

Favorability :

|

Revered [ 97 ]

When looking over Zhang Zhi’s stats he looked at the favorability ranking which was one of the more important statistics. Thanks to it the conversion from points to cultivation base would be higher and impartation of techniques was also boosted. It wasn’t fully maxed out but when it came to elders then Zhi was the one that saw him in the most favorable light. In contrast, both his disciples and his wife had this stat already maxed out. Huo Qiang on the other hand was a bit lower.

At the moment both Zhang Dong and Zhi were floating in the sky but soon they descended towards the temporary encampment in an abandoned city. It had been discarded during the demi-human wars and the people had not returned here yet.For the time being his sect was trying to prepare a stationary teleportation gate through which their forces could keep going through.

Large ships like the Argonaut had these types of gates built in but it was always better if one remained on the ground. The teleportation formations used up a truckload of spiritual energy which a flying vessel needed for its defensive shields. Most of the time it would be only used to transport smaller forces or masters of the nascent soul variety instead. It was always a more economical solution to establish a gate on the ground.

But he had not come here to just watch as the base was established. Zhang Zhi was close to reaching the middle stage of the nascent soul level. There was another reason why he ordered his number one retainer to be here. He wanted to make a spectacle of his ascension to a new realm. Through the tassel with Wang Long, he had actually gained something he couldn’t do before.

The reason for this new upgrade was either due to his contact with that cube he dropped or the expansion of his current seed. Nevertheless, there was a function that he gained and only people with a favorability ranking of ninety and up could be given it. This function would give the person a special title along with sharing some of his own Dao with them. In short, it was an upgrade through the system that would enhance his most loyal retainers.

At first, he wanted to instantly apply it to his wife or Huo Qiang. However, using untested features on his loved ones was probably not the best idea. Zhang Zhi was the perfect test subject. While he did feel bad about trying to use an untested method on someone like this he was also in a somewhat panicked state. Before the attempt, he had consulted with Bob on multiple occasions and there didn’t seem to be any drawbacks to the transition.

‘The only one was the increase in favorability…’

It was the only reason that he was withholding from using it on everyone was the forced increase in favorability. Normally this stat would be increased in a more natural way. It was a reaction to people gaining help from him. Here on the other hand it would boost it up and perhaps forcefully change it.

‘But in this world where power and cultivation is everything, it is a given that the favorability would skyrocket…’

The same thing happened after he removed the impurities from the core formation experts and then helped them achieve the nascent soul level. The favorability rating jumped up drastically, there was no one below a seventy favorability rating in his sect who was given direct help. In a way, it wasn’t that hard to influence these people that believed that rare techniques and cultivation materials were more precious than life.

So would he actually be affecting their relationship in any way or was it just a normal reaction to be given power. At this point in time Zhi’s fascination with him bordered on god worship. There was probably not something that would shatter the image of the perfect Patriarch. Perhaps only if he started acting like a demonic cultivator would this favorability rating go down.

Though this was mostly not due to what he was doing but the alignment of the person. People still kept their own characteristics and not many were fine with wanton slaughter. However, if he started eradicating sects under a ‘righteous’ pretext then probably Zhi would have nothing against it. With a good enough excuse, it was possible to wiggle around everything.

The time had come to give it a try. Part of their sect was already here and most of the base had been established. Now was the time to give everyone a small morale boost by increasing their command officers' prestige. He wanted to show what could happen to someone if they were deemed worthy by the Patriarch. The people here were hand-picked through the system and would be boosted the most by it if their favorability rating rose even more.

“We greet the Patriarch and the elders!”

“That’s enough, raise your heads.”

Zhang Dong called out to the people gathered here. Other nascent soul masters that he helped established were here but they were nowhere near Zhang Zhi in skill or favorability. They needed to see one of their peers be given even more power. This would give them the urge to show what they were made of in the coming battles.

“Today we have not gathered for me but for our sect brother, Elder Zhang Zhi. His accolades have not gone unnoticed to me and I wish to reward him, if you show me the same determination you might gain the same chance as him.”

“Patriarch, your words are enough, I do not need any rewards!”

Zhang Zhi clasped his hands while lowering his head. It was clear that the man didn’t really want anything and his loyalty was unshaken. He was not the type of person that required treasures or powerful techniques as a reward. If he was noticed and appreciated for his actions by his superior, then it was enough.

Most of the people in the sect weren’t like this, without seeing something worthwhile they wouldn’t give their all. For this reason, Zhang Zhi would act as a reminder to all of them. After reaching a new stage of power his victories would be a beacon. Everyone will see what they could become if only the Patriarch noticed them.

Perhaps this was just dangling a carrot in front of them but there was a need for them to improve. Without a proper army of high level masters, he was unsure of the longevity of his sect. Partially he was doing this to increase his own power base but also to leave behind trusted retainers that would protect his family if he ever vanished like before.

“Nonsense, you have done well and you will be rewarded. Just relax, this could feel strange like the last time…”

The grandmasters that were here all recalled the stench and weird feeling they were put through during the previous ascension. It was a rather pleasurable feeling but now with so many people gathered here, they started feeling pity for Zhi. He might have been getting power but if it was anything like the last time, then it would be something to remember.

“Like last time, Patriarch? P-perhaps we should do this in a more private place… I uh… I’m sure we could use some of the new gathering halls for this instead.”

“Nonsense, this won't take long, just bear with it.”

“I uh…. ohh…WOoooaaaHHH…”

A strange moan escaped from Zhang Zhi as Zhang Dong moved his finger towards his system screen, it was not something anyone would forget for a long time…

Chapter 555

“That glow… it’s entering elder’s Zhi’s dantian… his power is rising!”

“I can feel it too, he… he is reaching the middle stage before our eyes!”

The group of nascent soul masters that were all in the early stages of the nascent soul level gasped in awe. Before them a strange transformation was taking place, their sect brother Zhang Zhi had been chosen by the Patriarch and was moving past them in the spawn of a few moments. To people that took centuries to push their levels by a tiny fraction, this was a truly astonishing sight.

From their perspective, it looked like Zhang Dong gave a poke to Zhang Zhi’s forehead before utilizing a strange technique. His finger was tracing a strange path in the air that probably had some deeper meaning. Not soon after the aura of the cultivator exploded and started pushing towards the middle stage of the nascent soul level.

However this was no simple nascent soul level, its quality overshadowed anything that came before it. It was more similar to the radiance of the Patriarch himself or the great two other elders Huo Qiang and Zhang Liena. The three were a notch above the rest and it seemed that other people could actually reach this pinnacle realm.

Zhang Zhi’s body, which was filled with water energy, started releasing blue light. This light somehow started moving up into the sky to form the water dragon soul beast that he was known for. No one knew what this meant but soon enough they witnessed a slither of golden light jumping from Zhang Dong’s finger and being absorbed into the blue energy.

This is when it all actually started, the blue water dragon started changing. Its size increased twofold and the blue scales turned into a more radiant hue, not quite blue and also not quite golden but something in between. Some people here realized that what was happening was that the holy Dao that the Patriarch was famous for was somehow mixing with the soul beast and making it stronger.

It wasn’t only the soul beast that was getting stronger, Zhang Zhi’s whole presence changed. A cultivator usually possessed a unique spirit energy signature. The elders that were gathered here were already used to it. Thus when this pattern was switched to something entirely new they knew that Zhang Dong made it so. It was as if the Dao of Holy light was being injected into Zhang Zhi and upgrading his whole being.

“How is this possible…”

“Can the Patriarch share his knowledge with others just like that?”

“Be quiet, the ceremony isn’t over yet!”

The people were abuzz with speculation but after one of the elders shouted they went silent. Zhang Dong on the other hand wasn’t even really paying attention to them. The strange finger movements that he was performing were just his scrolling through the system window. There were several options that he could click that would affect Zhang Zhi’s cultivation.

This was the main reason why the favorability rating had to be over ninety for this to work. The person was opening up their cultivation to his system and this could be only achieved with almost blind trust. The subject would have his core cultivation method altered by spending spirit points gained from the faction system or spirit stones.

Everything also depended on Zhang Dong’s own knowledge and power level. He could not boost anyone past his own level of cultivation. At most the skills could be at the same rank as his but even that would use up a boatload of points. Yet Zhi here was a trusted retainer who would even offer his life to protect the sect or Zhang Dong if the need arose.

Thus he would not skimp out on any upgrades that he could give to his number one elder. First of all, he needed to decide on what he could add to Zhang Zhi’s repertoire. His body refining skill wasn’t quite up to par so it was quickly upgraded to allow him to take a beating. This was also augmented by adding a smidge of the recovering abilities from his holy dao. With that combination, Zhi’s vitality and stamina would be comparable to great circle nascent soul masters.

Zhang Dong’s own knowledge of the Dao of water wasn’t that great but he added whatever he could to Zhi’s to boost it a bit further. Knowledge of his sword skills would be far more useful and with the increase in body refinement, Zhi would be a force to be reckoned with. Adding a third Dao like the lightning one and gravity one wasn’t really an option and would muddle the current balance between water and holy.

The biggest change that everyone was witnessing was the soul beast. With the combination of gold and blue, it looked quite shiny and green. The Emerald coloring was quite breathtaking and was also something he could customize on his side. There was an extensive beast modification screen on which he could input some changes. It even showed him a warning signal if he made the soul beast too strong. It would then weigh on the user’s nascent soul and diminish the fighting capability which needed to be avoided.

‘That should do it…’

“Calm down and let the power flow through you, I will help you circulate your spiritual energy, for now, you will need to get used to it as fast as you can.”

“Yes, Patriarch.”

Zhi went down to his knees and assumed the lotus position. The transformation had taken place but even now one mistake would cause cultivation deviation. Elders that were watching knew this and quickly surrounded the two masters to protect them. Luckily Zhang Dong was sure to scan the whole region for potential threats and even some defensive formations had been prepared. Soon the soul beast started fading away and returned into Zhang Zhi’s body, the process was over.

“Congratulations on reaching the middle stage, how do you feel?”

“Is this really only the middle stage?”

Zhi was stunned by the amount of progress that he made. He knew that he wasn’t that far from maxing out on his early stage but reaching a hundred percent in it didn’t actually guarantee progress. It only opened up the possibility of reaching the next stage. That would always depend on the practitioner's luck and skill, it was never this easy but thanks to Zhang Dong it had happened without even one misstep. During the whole process, he could not feel even a single problem, it was as if something was guiding him through everything.

“I feel… sensational… it’s as if I have become a young man again!”

“Well… you do look a bit younger.”

Zhang Dong smiled as some wrinkles disappeared from Zhi’s face after the middle stage had been reached. His hair had also started to turn blond after the transformation took place. This was a stark contrast to his disciples that had pure white hair. It seemed that the Dao of Heavenly Lightning that they had practiced beforehand was responsible. If the holy dao was inserted without the other one it would transform people's hair golden instead.

‘Hm, would adding the gravitational Dao make someone’s hair dark purple?’

That Dao’s energies were of the dark purple coloring and sometimes close to black. He had not heard of people's hair color changing due to the Dao a person followed. Perhaps it had to be one of the greater ones and it needed to be understood to a high degree. His disciple's hair needed some time to reach the white coloring similar to his.

“I hope your wife doesn’t mind the change in hair color but I’m sure she could find some tinctures to get your old one back.”

“My hair color Patriarch?”

Zhang Dong just smiled and with a wave of his hand produced a mirror. Through it, Zhang Zhi could see the long golden locks that sprung free from his head during the transformation. It looked like the samurai was going through a rebellious phase and didn’t really fit his kimono and katana look. Nevertheless, the transformation was done and while Zhang Zhi was panicking over the new looks he decided to take a peek at the status screen.

Zhang Zhi

|

Nascent Soul [ Middle Stage 0% ]

Main Dao:

|

Water [ 65 % ] Holy [ 50% ]

Main Weapon:

|

Katana [ S - Grade ]

Favorability:

|

Worship [ 100 ]

‘Worship huh?... the kids have adoration at a hundred points which is a bit different…’

He was not sure what to make of it but Zhang Zhi would probably be a lot less troubled in carrying any type of orders. If he worshiped him as a higher being or something like that then what came out of Zhang Dong’s mouth would be the truth. He would need to watch to not have his number one elder take his words literally.

It seemed that the favorability was different depending on the relation. His wife that was also at a hundred points instead of worship or adoration had devotion there. The words were all somewhat similar and described strong emotions. He had not yet seen the number drop after going over a hundred so he was not sure if it was possible. Some other favorability ratings did drop during the five-year break when he vanished and were only restored when he returned.

“This Zhang Zhi will be loyal to the Patriarch and the bloodline that it carries, this I swear on me and all the descendants that I bring to this world!”

“You don’t need to bring your kids into this, they can make their own decisions…”

“Nonsense, they will follow your line for all eternity!”

“Ah yes…”

Zhi recovered from getting his hair bleached quite fast and was back to his old self. He kind of promised that every offspring that he produced would be under Zhang Dong’s line. It wasn’t strange for this to happen so for now he just waved it off. Most of the time such a promise would be forgotten within a few generations but it did somewhat guarantee help to his children if he vanished yet again.

‘For them, it is an equal exchange but it still doesn’t make the whole thing any better.’

This was something that he was aiming for. The overseer that might be looking at him from the shadows was constantly on his mind. If something happened to him then his children and wife would be in danger. Perhaps not now but after many years when new experts arose, it could become beneficial to them to have allies. This was one of the reasons that he wanted to produce more people like Zhi that would feel grateful to him for giving them power.

Everyone was looking at him with pleading eyes already. They clearly wanted to be the next one to advance further and they would work tirelessly to show that they were trustworthy retainers worthy of praise. With this the seed had been planted, now what came next was the assessment of the enemy army and how his new improved general would handle it.

Chapter 556

‘Whew, it's always strange to see old farts looking at me with those puppy dog eyes…’

Zhang Dong removed himself from the gathering area after enhancing Zhang Zhi's cultivation. The other elders had sparkles in their eyes and if he allowed it they would probably start kissing his feet just to get some help. This was not that strange of behavior as after hundreds of years of failing in cultivating the old farts were desperate.

This procedure that Zhi had gone through was a limited bonus he was given after getting in contact with Wang Long’s system. Under his faction window, Zhi was the first one to make it over to his prestige units. There was a limited number of five people that could go through this changing process and he already had decided on the next two.

First of this was a little test to see what this function entailed for the one going through with it. While his favorability rating was enhanced it didn’t seem that Zhi had really changed much. Now he could move on to his family members like Zhang Liena that would be next in line. After her came Huo Qiang and then on the next two he had not fully decided on.

One of the possible candidates was Zhang Jin. His grandfather was loyal and a trusted member of his inner circle. The only problem was that he had only recently achieved the nascent soul level. His power wouldn’t get as much of the boost unless he really dumped all the spirit points he had to get him to the middle stage. With how he was planning to get Qiang and Liena into the late stage this would be quite costly.

Both of his disciples were also potential targets of the boost. While they were still core formation practitioners this could open up the future for them. Considering that he might have to play the long game it might not have been such a bad idea. The two would not become nascent soul masters instantly but would be closer to being half-step into the higher realm.

With time they would certainly develop into powerful figures, the only question was if they had enough time. If the Azure Emperor came knocking and his wife joined in then his disciples wouldn’t be that helpful. However, they would be a great choice if he needed his kids to retreat. Zhang Xue and Liu would be perfect bodyguards and caretakers. Perhaps it was the wrong kind of motivation to entrust more power to people in hopes they return the favor but there wasn’t much he could do here.

‘Besides Qiang and Liena there aren’t that many elders worth mentioning, I guess I’ll gather enough resources for them before making a decision.’

For the time being, he made the choice to wait. Zhang Zhi needed to be monitored as well before he truly decided to fiddle with his wife with the help of his system. It should not be able to fiddle with the thoughts of people but there was always a risk. There were already techniques in this world that could be used to control others, it wouldn’t be strange if whoever made this world had access to stronger ones.

These prestige ‘units’ that the one affected became came with a boon. They were supposed to become loyal to the faction leader. This meant they were reinforced against any mind-affecting spells and techniques. They also shared in the power of the faction leader which after the run-in with the overseer would come in handy. His wish was that the Empress would not be able to affect them as much just as he wasn’t affected by the time stop.

“Well then, I should try this new monitoring feature.”

After his speech, it was time to return to the Golden Dong Palace. With a quick teleport, he appeared in his private chamber. No one would be the wiser if he was or was not in his personality floating castle which also improved the workflow.

The room he was in had been slowly plastered all over with various monitors and another holographic map replica. Thanks to his cultivation it wasn’t hard to look at multiple screens at the same time. There, on all of them, he could quickly check the state of his sect and the state of the empire.

‘Best if I color code everything first… Let me see… I guess my faction can go with white or yellow…’

It was turning into a strategy game. His golden cultivation and the whole Golden Dragon persona inclined him to choose yellow as the color for his side. The Azure Emperor would of course be blue and the Emerald Phoenix Empire was green. The Heavenly Crane Sect had become pink and that left Argus and his faction as a holy white. Then the fish people with brown color so as to not coincide with the other blue.

‘I guess it's muddy water? Their color patterns kind of clash with each other…’

After inputting everything into the mapping device he was given the state of the current war. The West border region was all yellow and it pushed into the north side where the demonic lands were. The center of the empire was blue with the coloring becoming fainter before being taken over by other colors.

‘That Emerald Phoenix Empire took quite a chunk from the east side, their territory is almost as big as mine…’

After a few glances, it was clear that the Long Clan still had the largest section of land. They were highly concentrated in the middle though with the rest just being faint blue with a questionable grasp. The pink coloring pushed into the east side which clashed with the green side. Then in the south, there was a small white encampment that belonged to Lucius.

The faction system even introduced a hostility rating that he could place on the interactive map that was now connected to his system. Only after being reassured by Bob that the administrator couldn’t access the system he had was he willing to continue using it like this.

‘It’s a bit strange but perhaps that great goldy figure above doesn’t want the overseers to fiddle with the system? If that’s true then perhaps this broken system is the greatest weapon I could have against it.’

There could be a few reasons that the administrators didn’t have access to the system holders' system. One of them was to make it fair for the system holder but that didn’t really make much sense as the administrator was there to steer the scenario in one way. Then if something went wrong they could even erase people's memories and probably even kill the system holder.

After going through his predecessor's files he was still unable to find anything to help him with the administrators. That man had to be aware of the whole structure of this world and that included the overseer. Was it also the Empress even two hundred thousand years ago or did these people die as the rest?

The world had a limit on power and even when that woman was a lot stronger she didn’t feel like a fully-fledged immortal. In the previous world, the demon king also had a power level going above the heroes but he was still only within the confines of power that Zhang Dong was at.

Taking that into consideration it should be possible to take out the Empress if he only got a bit stronger. Something like a half step into the immortal realm should be more than enough. His main plan was to absorb the Dao’s of the two other Emperor-level enemies, perhaps they would be enough to push him in the right direction. If that didn’t work he would need to do it the hard way or utilize his faction system in some other way.

It was easy to bring his people closer to his own level but it wasn’t possible to go beyond it. There was a possibility of gaining some insight from his own faction members but as it stood for now they were all behind him.

The only two that were slightly above were Qiang in the ways of fire Dao and Liena in the wind department. However, this was not something he couldn’t cross by himself if he just delved into the study himself. All the base techniques they were given were created through the system and what they were doing was just perfecting them.

‘I guess if we three lock ourselves in seclusion for a few hundreds of years then we might gain insight into several more Daos without needing to fight but can I trust the admin to not figure out that my system is busted at some point…’

The Azure Dragon was a big problem, he always brought his wife over for any type of occasion. It would be a slap to the face of the Long Clan if Zhang Dong refused any invitations or didn’t invite his own brother to some more serious events. At some point in time, they would need to meet and when that happened he needed to be ready.

With the map before him, he could continue to monitor the fishy invaders in the north and the more traditional cultivators in the east. Regretfully this map didn’t really tell him anything about the strengths or weaknesses of his enemies. At most, it could warn him of surprise attacks or secret hiding places if they had a powerful enough defensive force.

But this was not the reason for this setup, he was attempting to change it from an action game into a strategy for now. From this chamber with the screens, he could perfectly direct all of his forces to places he seemed fit. He had built up his faction to be part of the great three and it was time to use them as such.

‘I need to get stronger and they need to get stronger if we want to survive this together, I can’t cuddle them or play the hero forever, if they can’t take care of themselves then after I’m gone it won’t take much for the entire sect to implode…’

While giving out a sigh he looked towards the top part of the map. There he saw a small yellow dot where Zhang Zhi and the current forces were stationed. After the scouts came back it was time to prepare the offensive. This time around he would be taking a backseat and his sect members would have to fend for themselves to gain more experience.

‘They should be fine…’

He hoped that he wasn’t making a mistake and was also ready to jump in if things got too hairy for Zhi. But while the offensive was taking place he wouldn’t be fully passive. There were other ways of supporting his troops than directly being there on the battlefield.

‘I guess I should prepare some items worth for true grandmasters.’

Chapter 557

“Hear me out brothers and sisters of the sect, the Patriarch put his trust in us and we will make true on it. As you might know, the demonic menace is done with but another enemy on the level of the demi-humans remains. We will organize a task force to get to the bottom of that island, failure is not an option!”

Zhang Zhi was performing a speech at a gathering of commanding officers. The Sect had a similar ranking system to the army which was decided mainly by a person’s cultivation and skill level. However, this didn’t mean that the most potent fighter would always be giving the orders. Everything was run through a special brain unit that brought out the best strategies and the one in charge had to finally decide on one.

“Has the intelligence unit prepared the information?”

“We have, Commander Zhi.”

“Very well, I’ll leave it up to Elder Changpu, she will present us their findings.”

“Thank you, Commander Zhi.”

A woman that looked to be in her fifties took a step forward toward the stage. There a large screen flickered on to present the findings of their scout units. There were photos of the strange island from all sides that they could.

“As you can see the island is but a reproduction and its true size is hidden under the deep water. Without the proper equipment, we were unable to gather information about the true size of it. These beings are aquatic in nature and our people had to retreat.”

“Elder Changpu, aren’t the new underwater ships ready to set out? As I recall the armory unity called them submarines?”

“Ah yes, the new products from the main sect that the Patriarch helped to design, it's truly a blessing that he is with us.”

The elders nodded in agreement. The underwater ships and weapons had been produced at the main sect and then transported through the teleportation gates. With them to aid them they hoped to be able to close the gap between the person and sea creature. They were equipped with various projectile weapons that should even be able to harm a nascent soul master and were designed to be especially deadly in underwater combat.

“Trouly, it wouldn’t be possible without the Patriarch’s knowledge, it is a mystery why he is so wise!”

“It must be because he is the Golden Dragon!”

“Indeed, if it was up to me he would be sitting on the throne and not that Azure Emperor… what has he done for us or the people?”

“That isn’t wrong but… should we be saying these things…”
“Why not? We are the United Element Sect, we are not inferior to any of the other sect or the Long Clan!”

“That’s right, as long as we have the Patriarch we need to fear no one!”

The room burst into cheers after the conversation shifted toward the sect leader. Everyone here didn’t try to deny this fact, their leader was in their eyes at least on the same level as the Azure Emperor. With no point of reference, they assumed that he would be victorious in a fair fight and for now it seemed that Long Qing was remaining silent.

There could be many reasons why he wasn’t interfering with the United Element Sect. The most reasonable one being that they just had other things to worry about with the invaders everywhere. However the sect loved Zhang Dong, to them, it must have been another reason. Long Qing was just afraid of a direct confrontation and losing face against his brother, the Golden Dragon.

“Please calm down brothers and sisters, this is not the time we must discuss our plan, otherwise we will bring shame to the Patriarch if we are forced to seek his help again.”

Zhang Zhi brought everyone's attention back to the screen. It was important to him that they are able to confront the enemy by themselves. Most if not all of the main battles were victorious thanks to Zhang Dong being involved. Zhi as well as the other elders knew that this couldn’t continue. They needed to show to their Patriarch and also to the world that they could win even without their strongest fighter getting involved.

“Aye, the Long Clan rarely involves the Azure Dragon in their dealings, we must do so as well, otherwise no one will take us seriously without the Patriarch's direct involvement…”

Soon the conversation returned to tackling the strange island. On the screen, they placed the diagrams of the sea creatures guarding the whole place. The weak spots had been found and would be used to bring victory to their next war expedition. After all of the equipment and personnel were ready they would begin their mission.

…

‘They do that a lot, maybe it's because my favorability rating is too high?’

Zhang Dong had left his people to their own devices but kept an ear out. Thanks to his faction system and Zhi that was now a prestige unit being at the gathering he could easily hear what they were talking about. It was embarrassing to hear them praise him every second that they could. Some of the praises were true but others were just trying to crawl up Zhang Zhi’s posterior by praising the man he adored.

The praises that he received were fine but some parts were problematic. Long Qing was brought up and disrespected by his own people. If the Long clan ever got wind of it then it could cause some friction. It wouldn’t be strange if people from his faction got into a dispute with the Long Clan over things like this. His side was clearly disrespecting the current Emperor, it was as if they wanted Long Qing to be replaced.
‘This isn’t good but their faith in me borders on fanaticism already, after Wang Long died my name began to be spread even more…’

Zhang Dong knew that this was all problematic. The only reason there was no friction on the surface between the Long Clan and his side was due to the war. If they started killing each other then the invaders would only profit from it. For the time being an uneasy truce had been established but when all of this was over then it would explode.

‘The sooner we get rid of the Emerald Phoenix Empire and those underwater beings, the sooner I might have to clash with the Emperor…’

He was not afraid of battling Long Qing, his power was vast but it wasn’t above his. The biggest problem was the woman that would be there. What would the overseer do after his victory over the Long Clan? Would she not notice that the mind control didn’t work?

‘What is her plan… if Long Qing dies then so will she and her family if we consider the usual rules of this world. At best I would need to imprison them somewhere to ease the minds of the people, two Emperors can’t exist at once and their kids would have a right to the throne…’

The administrator had some kind of mind-affecting skills. There were also ways of producing clones and flesh puppets. Perhaps after Long Qing was killed or imprisoned she would exchange herself for another person.

‘Wait… would she do something like that?’

Zhang Dong, who was in the middle of crafting a new sword, almost dropped his hammer. The crafting abode was still in his possession and it was one of the places where no one could bother him. During his crafting session, he continued to overthink and a terrible thought entered his mind.

What if that Empress exchanged the Azure Dragon for the Gold Dragon after all was set and done. What better place to examine the system holder than being at his side constantly. If he thought about it more it did make sense. When all was said and done the system holder would become the new Emperor of this empire. To monitor everything she would need to remain close to the people in power and switching from Azure to Gold would be the easiest method.

Now, this was a true problem, his mind raced to rationalize this possibility. He had planned to take it slow, as long as he didn’t give himself away then perhaps the Overseer would remain passive through all of it. Even if it took him a thousand years he might finally be able to achieve the immortal stage himself and break this cycle. Could he sacrifice his dear wife for all of it though or anyone else? She could replace anyone and he would need to watch, even if it was not a close family member could he just let something like this happen?

‘Shit… I might have been overestimating how much time I have…’

While his plan was to get stronger he now needed to keep his family members away from the Azure Emperor. If a war broke out between them then perhaps it would be better to prolong it as much as he could. This didn’t change the fact that he needed to take care of the current problem which was the fish people in the north.

“I need to finish this thing first…”

In his hand, he had a long piece of metal that was slowly taking shape. His spiritual energy flowed into it while he continually delivered hammer strikes. Crafting in this world was a lot different, the hammer was only used to inject his Qi with more force but in general, this force was used to mold the item into shape.

With time a curved blade with one sharp edge started to appear. This would be the new weapon that Zhang Zhi would use in battle. The highest heaven grade weapon that he could produce would belong to his first prestige unit.

‘Think they used to call these blades Odachi.’

It was infused with both water and holy energies. With the water elemental infusion that went above the norm, he hoped to bridge the gap. The battles that would be taking place would be fought near large bodies of water. This blade should be something that took his enemies off guard and boost Zhi’s current power level to someone at the great circle.

“It’s quite long but it shouldn’t break that easily…”

After giving the sharpened edge a poke he could feel his flesh being injured. It was even able to injure him who had a powerful body refining skill. With this, the blade would be able to deliver damage to even an Emperor-level threat now it just needed a few finishing touches before the battle started.

“I still need to make those gauntlets for Qiang and that new fan for Liena, who should I start with first…”

Chapter 558

“The sword is finished.”

In his hand, he held a razor-sharp blue blade elongated katana. It was on the longer side and reminded him of the weapon of choice of a certain white-haired villain. This blade that could boost water-based attacks and control would make it to the hands of Zhang Zhi.

“I better just send it over, if I personally deliver this thing to him he’ll make a fuss about it…”

During the years spent in this world, he never got used to the way people treated him. To some extent, he saw himself as the thirty-something loser from his old life. Even after achieving all of this success it was still hard to see himself as someone above the rest.

His people saw him as some kind of deity able to bring them towards the promised land. If he bought into it all it would be a very slippery slope. He could see himself becoming something similar to Wang Long that lost it. The man actually thought that he was some kind of chosen being and everyone else was an NPC in his story.

From Zhang Dong’s perspective on the other hand everyone wasn’t that different. The amount of power and even their intelligence was highly dependent on their environment. If someone was lucky enough to be born in the higher regions of the empire their life trajectory would be wholeheartedly different from that of someone that started in the lower region.

Perhaps after all this is over he could establish a new and fair regime where at least people had a chance to reach their true potential. It was of course impossible to make everyone happy and corruption would always exist. His aim would be to at least make the world around him a bit fairer and to guarantee baseline living conditions for people that were dealt a bad hand.

“Before that ever happens I need to finish all of these repairs and enhancements.”

While the sword was finished this wasn’t the only piece of gear that needed to be created. On a large workbench that he was looking at, his own white armor was being reconstructed by a peculiar-looking machine. There were several mechanical arms on the sides injecting spiritual energy in short bursts which made it look as if it was being welded.

His crafting abode upgrades had been reset down to zero after he made his way back to this world. After taking care of Wang Long he was finally able to put some spirit points into enhancing it once more. However for some reason after getting in contact with Wang Long’s system this place had also shifted.

Previously it had the feel of a medieval smithery. The old dancing system that was implemented in one of the earlier models was luckily gone. Through his faction window, this place could now produce items en masse. He just needed to throw the required resources into a large furnace that was ten meters high and twenty meters wide.

The scenery was more modern now, it looked like a giant car factory with various machines. He didn’t quite understand it all but it did do the job for him and supplying his forces with powerful weapon replicas wasn’t hard. What he needed to do was just design a model that would be then multiplied by the machines.

For the time being the assembly line was in full swing. They were creating battle armor for the soldiers that would boost their fighting power to an extreme level. With all this gear on his soldiers would be able to easily combine into grand battle formations that were on the level of nascent soul masters. Now even some of the weaker practitioners could be of use in battle.

“Even though I’m here it's still hard to comprehend that such a place exists and whoever I might be going up against next can just make things like this, what is this immortal realm?”

Zhang Dong had come a long way since his journey started. At that point, he didn’t really think about the system he was equipped with. However now it was different, it was something that could affect the world to a high degree. Even at his current level, he would not be able to perform most of the acts this system could.

Creating small subspaces wasn’t something that was above him anymore but materializing equipment just with spiritual energy was not something he could do. It would take quite some time for him to examine every machine in this factory and then recreate it with the correct materials. Some of the intricacies inside of them were somewhat a mystery.

His knowledge was still limited and he needed more of it. Perhaps there were other ways of building up his power than defeating the enemy emperors. His best bet was still his predecessor that managed to counter the old system programming.

‘If only those records weren’t so old, most of the information had been lost and Bob would need more computing power to scavenge through what was left.’

While this was true he wasn’t left with anything. There were still bits and pieces here that he could reverse engineer back. Even the nuclei that were scattered through the empire along with treasures like the dimensional regalia could aid him in ascending to the next level. He just needed time to comprehend what it took to become a true immortal. If he wasn’t able to retrieve the cube the Empress stole it would be the only way.

“It will be hard to go against something that made this system possible…”

He opened up the system screen where Zhang Zhi and his prestige unit section was. There he saw an equipment panel that reminded him of old MMORPG games. The sword that he created first was placed down on a special bench. When it was there an icon of the sword appeared on the inventory screen. Then by dragging this item towards Zhang Zhi’s right hand he could drop it to equip it.

The moment the pixelated version of the sword made it to the right side weapon square, the real sword vanished from the bench. This was a first try at the new mode of equipping his closest warriors. Zhang Zhi would be quite surprised when the sword appeared on this side as if it belonged to him. To make the blow to his senses easier, Zhang Dong attached a little note to the sword hilts with the explanation.

Thanks to the faction's latest enhancements he could actually monitor Zhang Zhi. Just as the weapon was equipped he could see a rather confused Zhi almost falling over. He was just on his way to a military facility where the new soldiers had arrived as the weapon appeared strapped to his side. A few other people were walking behind him so the light of teleportation caused them to jump away in fright.

However the weapon carried something with it that Zhi could recognize. Zhang Dong’s holy aura was all over it so the fright and confusion quickly changed to interest. The little letter that he attached to it was red with haste and was followed by bowing.

“Look at them go…”

It was a strange sight to behold. Without him being physically there, the people were starting to prostrate themselves to thin air. They must have thought that he was somewhere close by and trying to pinpoint his position. The sight of them bowing in all cardinal and intercardinal directions was truly interesting.

“This is a handy feature, I’ll be able to supply him with new weapons and items even during battle…”

Zhang Dong could already imagine it. If Zhi found himself in danger he could quickly drag over an item to resolve the problem. There was a limit to what it could be as this only worked with specific items that the faction system approved off. He could only drag things like weapons, armor, and pills.

He could not for instance shove a flying treasure through it, there was no designated spot for flying mounts. At most he would need to create something that could perform both functions of a weapon and a means of transportation. The only downside was that he would actually need to do it by hand. Monitoring what Zhi was up to 24/7 would be hard even for him and stall his current crafting.

‘I should be able to equip him in power armor though, I just need to finish it first…’

His own power suit had been mostly restored after the tussle with Wang Long but it also needed to be improved further. His own safety came before that of his men, at the moment he could only give them limited support. The long Odachi sword that was handed over would need to suffice for now.

“Well then, while they prepare for their own battle I need to get back to work.”

With his hand occupied with a large hammer, he descended into the improved crafting area. There more generalized furnaces and smelters were already heating up the crafting materials. Not everything could be done by the robots and the factory setup. He needed to actually create the blueprints and the item in question by himself.

The next one on his agenda was Liena’s battle fan. This item would need to be even better than the one that he gave to Zhi. He was clearly biased towards his wife and would even dive into his secret stash of rare materials to push this fan over the limit of nascent soul. His aim was to create something that could go beyond it.

While the world didn’t allow for the creation of immortal grade items they still existed. The flying golden bastion was one of those items that had been left behind and another was the dimensional regalia. Both of them were quite versatile in their function and had a similar feature of becoming stronger by absorbing spiritual energy.

The regalia was a small world in itself and the inside was comparable to a large continent from his old world. The golden palace continued to become larger and the arsenal it was equipped with could not be stopped by normal means. Even he himself would probably be unable to burst his way through the defenses easily.

Yet they were not directly weapons at the immortal level. Something like a proper sword or other type of weapon would make things easier. Instead, he would need to somehow study these two items and finally emulate the thing that made them go over the heavenly grade.

‘This might take a while but before Zhi and the others make their move it will be some weeks, let me get to it!’

Chapter 559

“Commander, we are ready to begin the operation, please give us the order to depart.”

“Very well, we shall commence with the operation, we will depart now and be victorious!”

“As you wish!”

Zhang Zhi pulled out his new sword and pointed it toward the artificial island in the distance. Some time had passed since they were given the order to take that place over. They had been preparing for weeks and finally, all was ready to take the fight to the fish people.

It was not a grand operation like the one during the demonic island incident. However to the people gathered here it had even more meaning. Many of them were put into leading positions while in the previous event they were just following the Patriarch.

In their eyes, they didn’t feel like they did much during the last battle. The two grand elders and the Patriarch took out the strongest enemies. They were just along for the ride and even had trouble battling the regular demonic army that was now missing. This was their moment to show their true worth, they needed to prove themselves to the sect and pave a path toward immortality.

The commanding officer for this battle was Zhang Zhi. Currently, he was floating above ground while looking toward the sea. The underwater ships that were tailor-made for this attack started revving up their engines. Out on land large dragons made from water started to from. Each one of them had a core nascent soul member and multiple core formation experts inside of its body. These grand battle formations moved next to the large underwater ships.

No one really knew what to expect but they did believe in one thing, the sect, and their leader. If the Patriarch thought that they would be able to conquer this new enemy by themselves, then they would. There weren’t any second thoughts, only victory and honor were on their mind.

Soon the large underwater armada was making its way towards the floating island near the shoreline. Their enemies were not surprised and met them head-on as under the sea a different spectacle was taking place. Many sea creatures of varying shapes and sizes tossed themselves at the invaders.
Zhi spread out his senses and could feel a swarm of living beings approaching. Their numbers were tremendous and a stark contrast to the demi-humans that came in a smaller number. Luckily they all weren’t that powerful the many sea beasts were mostly at the Qi condensation but they also had a lot of foundation establishment troops mixed in.

This was not the time for him to act, he was the leader. While the Patriarch liked to delve into battle by himself he was not allowed the same leisure. There was a vast difference in their power levels and Zhi was aware of this. If he made a mistake his skills would probably not be high enough to help him out of trouble.

For the time being, he allowed his troops to pave a path forward. First came a tidal wave of small creatures, fish with sharp teeth and the size of sharks were very prevalent. Yet they would not come far as the underwater ships were quick to launch their armaments at the monsters.

It was the first time for him to see the ingenious weapon that the Patriarch created. Spiritual energy bullets weren’t as effective underwater as above it. Instead, the ships launched specialized shells that had a propeller at the end. It would continue to spin and add speed to the projectile.

Zhi was quite captivated by the large quantity that was made by their sect in this short time. The scientists and blacksmiths informed him that the vast majority was procured by the Patriarch himself. The ways of manufacturing them at this scale were unknown to them but they were trying to keep up.

With this much ammunition on their side, the swarm of underwater creatures was defenseless. The large numbers were actually a detriment as they couldn’t maneuver out of the way. The moment a torpedo collided with one of the beasts it produced a huge explosion. Blood and guts soon riddled the sea while continuous explosions produced gassers of bones.

The sect submarines were able to take out the vast majority of the initial beasts but some of them still made it through. This was just a testament to their ferocity and sheer numbers that even a huge amount of explosive rounds couldn’t clear out.

Zhi wasn’t worried though as the more modern ships had guards around them. The moment some of the monsters made it too close to the submarines they were attacked by sea serpents made from water energy. With the vast quantity of water here it was easy for the masters to keep these water serpents working.

Most of them had come from the Zhang Clan and were still using one of the core formations that were created and later improved by the Patriarch. Thus most of the swarm of fish ranging from Qi condensation to foundation establishment were dealt with by the underwater ships. However, this was not over yet, the real test of their might still remained.

Massive underwater monsters were still waiting for them. They surrounded the fake island that was a beast in itself. The closer the armada of ships belonging to the United Element sect got the harder it became. The defending army was quite relentless and without any fear for their life.

“It can’t end with these mindless drones, the people in charge must come out eventually, otherwise we will surround them.”

Zhi along with some other elders and support flying ships moved in tandem with the underwater submarine squadron. He did not believe that the underwater creatures were the only line of defense. Zhang Dong had informed all of them about the enemies and they had even examined the trident and their physiology beforehand.

Just as he thought as they got closer the nascent soul sea monsters started to move. Their size was truly tremendous and it didn’t seem to slow them down at all. The top part was more humanoid in shape while the underside consisted either of tentacles or fish tails. They weren’t unified in shape or size but all of them started moving.

At first, the monsters just waited there but suddenly a strange wail escaped from this island monster. The sound wave produced a massive tsunami which would cause a lot of damage to the seashore. Under the waves, the massive blast of sound waves collided with the formations and the ships to push them away.

Right on cue, the army activated various defensive measures to disperse this wide area attack and continued to push forward. They continued firing the torpedoes but from within the island structure blasts of sound energy continued to repel all of these projectiles.

Finally, the large monster revealed itself, the head sprung forward and it was quite tremendous. Even the huge sea monsters that were equal to nascent soul masters were like mere ants compared to this behemoth.

“Is that a turtle beast? But how can it have grown to this size…”

Only a tip of the giant monster's shell was sticking out and it already looked like a small island. The creature had to be several kilometers in diameter but was still able to keep itself afloat. It was clear that this was done with the help of some spiritual energy as nothing this big wouldn’t sink.

This was their true target, the massive creature that was the size of a city. But it wasn’t their only opponent as the nascent soul level creatures that were guarding it started to move forward the underwater ships that couldn’t fire their torpedos anymore.

To add to the injury the giant turtle beast started revealing its head further as before it was hidden away in its shell. There was something off about this turtle though. Even though it had a giant head, the orifices where its legs should be remained empty. Instead of large limbs, strange humanoid-looking underwater beings started pouring out.

“Are those the underwater dwellers? They look like the sub-species type that takes orders from those mermen…”

The patriarch came up with the names of mermaids and mermen for these underwater creatures. However, they had not come across any female versions of them yet. There was a possibility of them not existing but the males of this species did have all the organs required to be considered male. One of the theories was that the women were not as violent and stuck tending to the children but perhaps soon that conclusion would prove faulty.

“None of the leaders are showing up though, considering that they are using their beasts like this…”

Zhi mumbled to himself while also unsheathing his long blade. The moment it left the sheath a humming sound was produced. While the monsters were pointing their fangs at the vast armada of ships and the sea serpents he used this chance to approach.

The flying ships in the sky remained stationary but also moved into a firing formation. The large cannons at the helm started charging up spiritual energy and aiming toward the part of the turtle's shell that was revealed. Soon a barrage of energy bolts rained down from the sky and uncovered the fake ground that occupied the turtle's back.

It didn’t seem that this monster turtle had anything to counter this air attack. However, the shell that was covering it didn’t budge at all. Even when it was pelted by a swarm of energy attacks they weren’t producing any damage. Probably with such a defensive monster on their side the mermen didn’t feel threatened.

Zhang Zhi didn’t think that they would remain passive for too long. They were inclined to use their beasts first but after their troops were shaved off enough they had to show their hand. When the time came then he would be ready for it.

Playing the waiting game was a bit new to him. Usually, he just delved into battles as one of the soldiers. On this occasion, he had to hold himself back, if he fell then this whole operation could fail. The commanding officer needed to remain tall and be a beacon of hope to their troops. At least that’s what he thought after seeing their leader in action so many times.

“Commander!”

“I know, get ready now the true battle starts…”

Finally, the turtle released another wave of sound that even caused him to recoil in pain. From the holes on the sides, something was coming out. The spiritual energy signature was similar to their previous prisoner and aligned to the powerful trident weapon and there were multiple, it was the time for him to delve into battle and show what he was made of.

…

“They are doing alright for now… let’s see what he does next…”

Zhang Dong stopped working and looked at the large set of screens on the side. There he could see the entire force Zhang Zhi was leading and the moment the underwater beast leaders finally showed themselves.

Chapter 560

“So the giant turtle isn’t really meant for combat?”

Zhang Dong had decided to remove himself from the crafting chamber and moved to his secret room in the golden bastion. There he could monitor the movement of the current army that Zhang Zhi was leading. The diagram of the massive turtle could be thrown onto a holographic map along with the space surrounding it.

It really felt like he was looking at a strategy game. He could see his troops trying to surround the giant beast while the sea creatures pushed back. It was all going well until the larger sea monsters started moving. It was the same exact ones that he was able to easily dispatch while hiding his true identity.

If he wished he could have just teleported there and probably cleared out everything by himself. This was not the reason that he was letting Zhang Zhi be the leader though. Only when put into stressful situations could his people rise to the occasion. While he didn’t want anyone to get hurt, this world they lived in was not fair or lenient. Everyone needed to learn to take care of themselves and only when clashing against people on the same level could they improve.

“By the calculations, they should be able to win this battle…”

Bob analyzed the situation and came out with a winning percentage. He was of the same idea that this was a very winnable scenario. If his armies believed in their power and all of the commanding officers did their job then victory was assured. However, problems and unforeseen events could always transpire. He was ready to go into battle the moment something out of the norm happened.

‘Well then, how will those attacking formations prove against the nascent level monsters… each one of them has one to contend with.’

On the holographic map he could see the sprite that represented one of the sea serpent formations moving towards the nascent soul beast. If he looked from here he wouldn’t be able to tell what was happening. There were no stats on the units he was seeing or any health points as a reference. What he could do though was access his prestige unit that was Zhang Zhi.

The bulk of spirit points he spent to enhance his cultivation allowed him to see things through his eyes and his senses. What Zhang Zhi felt he could also somewhat feel and see through his eyes while spending a minor amount of spirit points. Thus he continued to monitor the fight as if he was watching a boxing match on TV.

When the two clashed at first it seemed that the nascent soul monster would win. It was at the level of a late-stage cultivator with a body fit for it. However, the attacking formation was fueled by many cultivators which gave it an advantage when it came to Qi and also lessened the weak points that this creature didn’t seem to be aware of.

The monster attempted to claw at the body made from spiritual energy and water Dao. Yet the sharp teeth and talons that it was proud of didn’t amount to much. The initial attack dug into the flesh made from energy but even when it was torn apart, the serpent made of energy quickly reformed itself back. Unless the creature killed the people that were fueling the formation it would continue to mend back into its main shape.

This might have sounded like a critical weak point that could be easily exploited. However, hitting the correct spot that was buried deep into the huge serpent wasn’t that easily achieved. The people hidden in the spiritual flesh weren’t visible to the naked eye and there was a vast range of similar spots set up as dummies.

The sea serpent formation’s strength was in its random movement. The body could contort in many different ways to avoid the other creature’s attack. Then when close enough it went for an entanglement attack. By wrapping its elongated body around the huge monster it went for the kill. Not by means of force but by electrocution as this attacking formation was not just versed in the ways of water but also lightning.

‘Water does conduct electricity well.’

Zhang Dong nodded to himself as he was the one that came up with mixing his lightning Dao with the attacking formations. It was a change that required some support items where he injected some of his own power. The cultivators on the inside just needed to supply their own spiritual energy which would then turn the sea serpent into a heavenly lightning eel.

Electricity and lightning were not something underwater creatures were that resistant to. Even though massive storms pelted the sea with lightning bolts the power would be quickly dispersed on the giant surface area of the water. It would only deliver damage to the surface of the water but never reach underground where the stronger sea monsters resided.

He could not test out his theory last time but now he could see that it was working. The monsters were being entangled by the attacking formations and slowly getting the electric chair treatment. They weren’t going down quietly though as some of the creatures even managed to slip out of the death hold.

‘They are making a lot of mistakes but it's working in a general sense, the big question is if the enemy leaders will come up with a counter for the lightning attack.’

There was an actual way to counter the electric attack. Water didn’t conduct electricity if it was pure and without any additives. Pure water was an excellent insulator and did not let electricity through. However, they were in the sea which had a lot of salt in it and this made the current tactic hard to counter. The master would need to cleanse all of this water and produce pure H20 if they wanted to protect themselves with the help of the DAO of water.

The huge creatures here weren’t the smartest and they were also being controlled by the mermen. Perhaps if they were free to think for themselves they would be able to counter this attack but as it stood now they were quickly succumbing to the jolty constriction.

‘There they go… is that turtle hollow or something?’

Finally, as the heavy hitters were getting suppressed the denizens of the turtle started pouring out. They used the four holes that should have the huge turtle's limbs as an exit point. First came the humanoid fish people that were around the later stages of core formation. They were quite vast in numbers and were also carrying spears and some were even wearing armor.

In the back, the mermen with tridents arrived. This time there was more than one and each was riding on a chariot pulled by large fish that resembled large sharks. The display he was seeing through Zhang Zhi’s eyes became quite detailed as the man finally decided to move into battle.

There were four mermen at the middle stages of the nascent soul and a fifth one that remained closer to the turtle's head. He really did look like some kind of king from an underwater city. His beard was quite long and he was wearing golden-green armor made from some type of scales. This was Zhang Zhi’s next opponent, the other four merpeople would have to contend with some of the new elders that joined the war effort.

This time around Zhang Dong’s side had the number advantage when it came to them but they were not comparable when it came to cultivation. There were four of them against eight early-stage masters with the addition of the attacking formations that were taking out the large creatures his side was able to make up for the lessened quality.

‘How will this pan out…’

Zhang Dong was somewhat concerned about his people. Watching the bloody battle wasn’t so good for his heart. Both sides were losing their fighters but his side was clearly pushing forward. Even when someone got critically injured there was a special unit to rescue them before they died. Cultivator bodies were quite resistant and with the help of body refinement, it was possible to last through a lot.

While other sects discarded people that fell in battle he had a different philosophy. It was a dog-eat-dog world but it didn’t have to be. Having a person go through years of training just to fall in battle was in a sense a giant loss in resources. One was a moral problem but in saving people he would produce a vast quantity of veterans that were grateful.

Everyone would also risk a lot more if they were convinced that their sect members would do their utmost to rescue or help them in their time of need. Thus as the army on the other side discarded their vast number of creatures and soldiers, his side was constantly pulling their fallen away into the medical ships and defensive formations and evacuating them to a safe location. Later they could use the experience from this battle to better themselves and produce better results when the time to fight came again.

This was the same for Zhang Zhi, his battle with the enemy leader wasn’t going all that well. Even though he had increased his cultivation level and received a new weapon he was having trouble using it against this new foe. The location of the battle was clearly disadvantageous for him and the giant turtle that continued to blast him with sound waves was very troublesome.

The man like the other mermen was using a trident, with it he was producing strange waves of water energy that continued to chase after Zhang Zhi. In return, Zhi had to burn through his spiritual energy and create quick slashes with his sword. These sword energies clashed with the watery currents and dissipated each other.

‘It doesn’t seem that he will win if it goes on for much longer…’

Zhang Dong rubbed his chin while watching over the fight. While the difference in skill wasn’t that big, the other man just had more spiritual energy to delve into. Unless Zhi managed to deliver some kind of critical hit in one hit, the battle would be lost.

‘I guess it's time to test out that new feature…’

He looked towards his system menu where Zhi’s profile was. Currently, he was the only prestige unit that he had here. Besides the boost in cultivation and the possibility of teleportation items there was another technique that was usable.

‘Manifestation of skill, is it?’

Before the battle was decided he pressed the button to activate this feature. The moment it was active Zhi noticed a strange phenomenon. He was given knowledge of DAOs and techniques that he never practiced and an illusory figure of a certain Patriarch appeared behind him…

Chapter 561

Zhang Zhi went into battle with high hopes. He had a lot of things going for him, a giant boost in power and a new sword that was given to him by the leader in a mysterious way. This boosted his morale and made him make the mistake of engaging this monster on his own. He was now in a losing battle with his spiritual energy being drained.

His biggest mistake was not taking the enemy's huge turtle into consideration. It seemed to not be able to do much besides its massive head, this was however enough to keep him on his toes. The enemy did make mistakes and there were a few opportunities where a devastating blow could be delivered but he was unable to follow through.

Whenever he tried using this high-quality weapon of his to slice the merman in half, a wave of sound energy would knock him back. Then the opportunity would be gone and his enemy would be back to thrusting that strange trident his way. If not for his new weapon his death would have been assured, only with it could he hope to counter the water Qi that his enemy was employing.

He needed to find a weak point and do it fast, if he didn’t then his life was at risk. This was not even the worst thing, what he was worried about the most was that if he fell that the tide of battle could turn in the merman’s favor. How could he face the Patriarch or his sect brothers and sisters if he lost? Dying was better than letting the sect's name be dragged through the dirt.

Zhi was entrusted with this mission and retreating was not an option, thus he decided to give up his flesh so that he could cut bone. The next time the sound wave came he would take the hit and commit to the strike. His internal organs would take a beating but he would be able to slice through his enemy. If everything went right the other side would be injured far worse than he would. However, if he made a mistake then his life would probably be over and inside his chest, he would find the trident of his enemy.

‘W-what is this?’

His mind was resolute and both his hands were on the elongated katana. Before he could go through with his suicide tactic a familliar aura washed over him. The Qi cleary belonged to the Patriarch but he was not here; it was as if it was coming from within his own soul.

‘It’s as if the Patriarch is guiding my hand with his own superior swordsmanship…’

The knowledge and skills that he needed to win this clash entered his mind. A burst of energy that was unfamiliar yet familiar filled his entire being. The thought of risking his life left his head as he knew what to do. It was as if the path became clear to him and he just needed to follow the Qi trail before him.

With all his might he charged forward, the merman that he was facing looked surprised by the boost in power and speed. The turtle produced another blast of sound energy but just at the right moment, he slashed with his sword to open up the way towards victory. The protective barrier was cleaved apart and he found himself before the enemy leader.

It all happened in a fraction of a second, before the trident could even reach his throat his sword went through. The speed was trouly something he was not fully used to and so he found himself tumbling forward in an uncoordinated fashion. Yet he did not panic, the deed was already done, his sword had gone through and his enemy was already dead. His body was slashed in two from his neck down to his waistline.

When looking back he could swear that he saw the illusory figure of the Patriarch fading away. It was as if he was there as a teacher guiding his hand and lending his power to him just for that one sword strike. Just as fast as the knowledge and Qi was given to him it faded away. It was not clear to him how this had happened but he knew that if he wanted this technique would be open to him.

‘My whole body is screaming in pain… my bones almost shattered…’

There was a big drawback though, his whole body had been almost critically injured after performing this attack. It was clear that his body refining needed a tuning if he ever hoped to master this strange technique. This was obviously something that the unfathomable Patriarch had left behind during the ceremony.

He could feel a massive surge in holy and lightning energies that he was not that familliar with. During his ascension to the middle stage, some of the Patriarch’s healing properties had been given to him but it was nowhere near that power that just exploded from his fingers. Now after it was all said and done he was feeling a bit dizzy but his strength was returning to him. Perhaps if he mastered this new art he would be able to touch Zhang Dong’s heels.

…

‘This skill does burn through a lot of Qi.’

Zhang Dong leaned back in his chair while giving out a relieved sigh. Everything seemed to have worked out just as planned and the commander of the underwater creatures had been killed. Zhang Zhi’s Qi had fallen to only ten percent after using the special prestige class ability but with its help, he would be able to combat people above his level.

‘I didn’t expect this added feature though, I actually gained some spirit points from Zhi killing that merman commander, is this only limited to the prestige units from my faction or can I increase the number?’

He had a limit of five prestige units and had decided on the first three. Perhaps giving the next one to Qiang would be better after making this discovery. His friend was a battle junky and probably had the second biggest kill count from the whole sect. He was only second to him that had been putting himself in a bit more danger than a Patriarch should.

‘It’s not even a small number, It’s not quite as much as the old system was giving me but not that far off either.’

The system went through some changes along with changing the spirit point gain in general. When trying to compare it to the old points he would receive for killing a nascent soul master this gave him a bit above thirty percent. This meant that if his five prestige units started going through enemy numbers he would be given quite a large chunk of change.

‘This means that if I can get four of them to kill four early stage, nascent soul masters, I should get more points than if I killed one myself…’

While at first, it didn’t sound that great, he could probably go through nascent soul masters as a warm knife goes through butter at the moment. However, if he considered that the old system started to give fewer points to the weaker enemy he fought, this might be even more efficient. Then he also had the numerical advantage with the prestige units and perhaps other options would open up in the future.

‘This must be the effect of Wang Long’s system I came in contact with but can I really keep relying on this workaround…’

Zhang Dong was unsure if he should continue using the altered system too much. It all felt too easy but there weren’t that many options left to him. The spirit points were nothing more than an intricate way of gathering cultivation resources. He could spend them on almost anything, even for forcefully pushing his cultivation level forward.

Bob never mentioned any problems and it seemed that all the effects of the old system were countered. In theory, it had become an integral part of his oversized soul and would not be affected by any external powers. However, he did not know how powerful this superior being actually was, perhaps even after reaching the immortal level he would not be able to contend with it.

‘It might not even be malicious though but I’m not sure if something like the devouring seed protocol would have been developed by a good god.’

After going through some research and now after interacting with Wang Long’s system he had become more knowledgeable about that thing. It had been removed during his pseudo-death and it was also almost activated when Wang Long was defeated.

In theory, Bob explained that this thing would send out the very being of the system user somewhere. This he was not sure about as Bob remained vague. It was as if every experience, technique, spiritual energy, and even memory would be forcefully transferred somewhere. What someone would want with the memories of a system holder was above him, was the god just bored and wanted to live life through these ‘players’?

There was some hope at the end of the tunnel. It made the being that was at a different realm of existence more humane and with more flaws. In a way, it meant that it still needed something from the mortals that these worlds were created for. Perhaps it was not as omnipotent as things seemed, it could have just been a very powerful cultivator that was trying to delve into the mysteries of the universe.

‘I’m getting ahead of myself, this system is probably the only way I have a fighting chance, it’s the only thing that kept me from succumbing to that overseer.’

If the system was evil or trying to control him then he would have probably had his mind wiped after killing Wang Long. Without knowing that it was the Empress and without Wang Long’s cube his only way of moving forward would have been the enemy emperors.

‘Though that overseer doesn’t seem to be doing her job properly, perhaps they don’t get that much work and aren’t that good at it?’

The job performed by the Empress was indeed quite sloppy. She should have been able to tell after examining him that there was something wrong. However, she didn’t really go into detail or even try to get him to talk about his experiences. This would only make his victory more probable as he knew that his opponents were underestimating him, or not even taking him seriously at all.

“Well then, Zhi should be able to wrap it up and that turtle doesn’t seem very dangerous after the leader is dead… time to move the plan ahead.”

While nodding to himself he brought up Huo Qiang’s faction window, now with the added points from the kill he would be able to create his next prestige unit a bit faster than he had planned.

Chapter 562

“So they were hiding a small city inside?”

“Yes Patriarch, our forces have gone through this Turtle beast, it’s a bizarre amalgamation of flesh and technology, the beast looked fully alive from the outside but we have found many artificial structures on the inside, one of them being this large chamber.”

“I see, good work I’ll be there soon, try not to touch anything that might look like it could be cursed.”

“Of course!”

Zhang Dong from the comfort of his secret office looked through Zhang Zhi’s eyes as he strolled through the inside of the turtle. The battle was over and after the five nascent soul masters from the sea-people were defeated, the rest followed suit quickly. Some of them perished while others even fled and were in disarray.

“Can you give me your thoughts on those sea dwellers compared to the demi-humans?”

“They seem to have a somewhat hierarchical structure just as the demi-humans did. The ones that are lowest are the sea beasts, even the strong ones that could devour a large ship seem to answer to the higher caste.”

Zhang Dong nodded on his side while looking at what was inside the turtle. It was actually possible to go into the creature that was partially hallowed out from the inside. The top part of its body where the head and brain was had remained mostly untouched. However when going lower a lot of things were missing.

First of all, it didn’t have a lower body at all. The organs were dispersed into strange sections. One for the lungs, another one for the heart, and then the digested system was somehow connected to a strange chamber. The sect members were combing through it as it was something akin to a meat grinder for garbage.

It seemed that the sea creatures threw away various types of biomatter that they didn’t need, even dead sea creatures and decomposing plant matter. All of it was minced into a fine paste and then shoved into this creature's digestive system that would keep the head alive. The loss of limbs didn’t affect the travel speed as this was covered by spiritual devices that used the Dao of water.

“The next in line are the workers, they are the humanoid creatures that faintly resemble us but are covered in scales, they show intelligence and carry out the orders of the mermen that are their masters, those seem to be the ones in charge but their similarities are, peculiar.”

“Peculiar in what way?”

“They seem to be exact replicas of each other, all the workers and the mermen look the same from the outside as well as on the inside.”

“Are they clones?”
“That’s what our researchers concluded as well, the only one that was unique was their leader, all the rest must have been cloned by some strange technique.”

“That’s certainly peculiar.”

Zhang Dong answered while trying to remember how the nascent soul mermen looked. The ones that battled with the ships and formations did look similar to the ones he collected. The worker drones on the other hand were a dead giveaway. If this was true then these people were producing battle clones to do their battles for them. Even the leader of this turtle could have just been another clone.

“The researchers have also discovered several strange chambers.”

“Strange chambers?”

“Yes, they seem to be for beast-birthing purposes, this could be the source of their large army. Many of these chambers are spread through this turtle beast and even now more underwater beasts are being produced.”

‘So is that why they have so many minions to spare? They just grow them en masse in these turtle islands? I probably should go check it out myself, watching the screen through Zhi’s eyes will only give me secondhand information’

“Good work, keep monitoring the situation, I’ll be right to see everything with my own eyes.”

“Thank you Patriarch but you don’t have to…”

Zhi was hoping that Zhang Dong would leave everything to him. The mission was successful but he still didn’t want to bother the leader with every tiny detail. This was a good chance to show his leadership skills and the knowledge of their research department. Yet before he could even finish the sentence he felt a change in space and suddenly a white-haired Patriarch appeared out of thin air.

“Patriarch!”

“No need to bow, just give me a tour of the place I won’t take long!”

“As you wish.”

Zhang Dong knew how Zhi felt but he needed to be on top of everything. This was the first big find concerning the sea creatures and could be a focal point in their war. First of all, he noticed that the place was very damp and fully filled with water. Only thanks to specialized techniques could he remain here without drowning.

However, there were spaces without water that were probably only accessible by the ones in power. The merman and the ones that were caught this time around had two forms. One was similar to the fairytales which left them as a person with a fishtail but they could also turn into something that looked like a human with fins instead of ears.
These people could breathe air and also walk on land without that much of a problem. Their spiritual energy would react negatively to places with high concentrations of fire Qi. Which was probably why they were slowly trying to increase the sea level. Perhaps creating all these sea monsters and the island turtles was part of this plan.

“That’s a lot of eggs.”

Zhang Dong made his way into one of the birthing chambers. There wee a lot of tubes in this one that was pumping out strange-looking eggs. It reminded him of one of the old movies that he once watched. Now if something similar to a crab popped out of one of these it wouldn’t even be surprising.

‘The eggs have living creatures in them, they are growing really fast…’

Instead of crabs, these eggs had monster fish that were part of the sea monster army. There were other rooms like this and each of them produced a different type of beast. They were clearly just clones of each other, probably the strongest version of their species that was possible to breed.

“So this is the secret of their numbers but is this only a matter of difference of warfare or is there a deeper meaning?”

“What do you mean Patriarch?”

“They chose to put so many resources into these replicated soldiers, there could be many reasons for it, one of them being fear of engaging in war themselves.”

The sect members around him started to wonder while he continued to tour the inside of the turtle. In another area, they even discovered a room that created the worker drones that were at core formation level at birth. Instead of eggs, they were in transparent tubes made of some kind of crystal. Everything looked like a biological science lab with the gruesome half-made clones everywhere.

‘Well, if we could produce mindless soldiers we would do it too, cloning technology on this level has not been seen within the empire, the few techniques that allow a person to make a clone of themselves are mostly just used as a precaution. When the user dies their soul gets transferred to their clone but no one really uses them at a scale like this.’

These monsters weren’t that strong but if this continued they would certainly have the number advantage. These moving turtle islands were slowly moving toward the shores on the entirety of the northern side of the empire. This was quite concerning as if they continued to multiply the entire northern sea would be quickly overrun. Then after they had a foothold they could start pushing in.

‘This depends on what their goal is and these mermen don't seem to be able to speak, this explains a lot if they are just clones.’

At first, everyone thought that the fish people were just compelled to silence by some technique. However, with this information, it was clear that it was all due to being clones. They were manufactured by someone and this someone installed blocks into their minds. Whenever anyone was pushed from the outside their brains would be turned to mush and their souls destroyed.

‘Even these fish people have souls so this cloning technology is quite robust, perhaps their creator is using that as a controlling mechanism…’

After going through the entire facility he started inspecting the developed and underdeveloped clones. It was faint but there were parts of their souls that were similar to each other. It could have originated from some kind of technique and could be used for various reasons.

‘The big question here is… who is controlling all of them? At least the leader types seem to be able to function as regular people and give out orders, they do have a pyramid structure with the human-looking mermen at the top, who is above them though?’

The leader of this turtle island was not as strong as a horned demi-human tribe leader. Zhang Zhi even with the boost from the system wouldn’t be able to defeat a demi-human tribe leader. Perhaps Huo Qiang with an added boost and some armor would be closer to achieving this feat.

This could mean that there were more powerful foes hiding somewhere in this deep ocean. Now after one of their turtles had been claimed they might actually show their faces. It wasn’t strange for them to think that they should have been able to conquer at least the sea region. However, when he and his people arrived they were pushed back which went a bit against the scenario of this world.

‘This incident could force their leader to move faster or at least send some kind of mini-boss to clear things up.’

With this revelation, he knew that more fighting would be upon them. The next enemy should be around the demi-human tribe leader's level of power as it was too soon for an emperor to move out.

“Good, bring this turtle to shore and keep it from dying, use the sea creature clones to keep it alive if you have, have the research department go through everything, and take everything that is useful.”

“Yes, Patriarch.”

‘I guess this is when the fun starts, what will they do now? Will this be enough to lure them out or do I have to grab a few more turtles before they react?’

Zhang Dong decided to go back to work, his people would take the bounty back to the shore and examine everything thoroughly. Perhaps he could use cloning technology to create his own beast unit. Not needing years of taming for the beasts to be useful in war times was a big bonus.

‘I guess it's their move now, time to prepare.’

Chapter 563

A vast underwater utopia filled with families of fish, clear water, and colorful coral reefs started rumbling. In the distance, a grand emerald and golden palace of never before seen brilliance was lighting up the place. It radiated a bright emerald-like light that forced the darkness out of this deep sea location. Without it there the murky depths would have surely taken over.

Small fish that could be considered delicacies and materials for illustrious elixirs were everywhere. However fish wasn’t the predominant species here, people with the upper bodies of humans and the lower bodies of fish were seen everywhere. Half-women half-fish of bottomless beauty could be seen everywhere.

They seemed to be at peace, most of them were either resting and looking at the nice scenery or having fun. Their singing voices would make the greatest human songstress blush in shame and their dancing performance underwater was second to none. However their peaceful faces filled with joy quickly turned sour as they noticed the rumbling.

“T-the Empress is angry! What could have happened?”

One of the beauties called out while quickly swimming away along with the other mermaids. They were all clearly spooked by the trembling palace which caused them to hide in the nearby homes. Yet even when they were filled with fear their curiosity was even higher. With all their might they peeked out of their hiding places and listened. With a bit of effort, they could hear their leader shouting in displeasure and her target was one of the lesser ones.

“How could this be possible? How could one of our brood hatcheries have been captured? Who is responsible for this? Is it you?”

“T-the one responsible has been captured by the land-dwellers.”

“Captured?”

A man quite similar to the one that had been defeated by Zhang Dong’s sect was kneeling before a beautiful woman. Her long emerald-sapphire hair swayed along in the faint watery currents while she rested in a huge seashell. Her size was closer to a killer whale than that to a regular human, her gaze was cold and piercing. The shivering man on the ground dared not to look up as his life was on the line.

“Yes t-they…”

“Useless!”

Before he could give a proper answer his body began to shrivel up. His mouth was not used to speak words as the merpeople communicated by telepathy. His pleading thoughts didn’t get through to the empress that could not be appeased. When looking to the people that were in this room they all turned away, everyone knew that if they spoke up they could be next.

“M-my Empr…”

The powerful warrior that could topple mountains was no more. His body shriveled up and turned into a tiny little fish that could fit onto a regular-sized pan. For a moment the little fish wiggled around but soon it regressed even further and turned into a pile of green goop. This stuck to the palace’s floor and quickly dissipated as if the person that was there had never existed, to begin with.

“That one was faulty, it came from the same batch as the failure that lost the hatchery.”

The beautiful Empress seemed bored but somehow knew exactly how this merman was connected to the rest. Her bored eyes sprung to life a bit after looking at the empty spot where her subject had been. A strange feeling gathered up in her chest that she didn’t remember ever feeling.

“How long has it been since someone defied me? … This might become more interesting but defiance will not be tolerated!”

For a moment a strange smile crept onto the woman’s face and quickly another merman appeared before her. Replacing her forces was easy as breathing underwater for her, even if one hatchery was captured she could endlessly produce more of them. Even if her enemies were strong they would succumb to her forces, they always did and that’s how she became the Empress.

“Bring one of the Generals over, I have work for them!”

“It will be done, Empress!”

The merman quickly removed himself from the chamber and headed for a section outside of the palace. While it was the focal point of the scenery and dwarfed anything else besides it there were four smaller ones behind it.

Even though each and every one of them was like a separate city on its own there weren’t that many beings living here. A very small number of the mermen were allowed to be granted access into the main palace where the Empress resided and even the Generals were not allowed to enter without being called over first.

The man was instructed to call one of the generals but the Empress didn’t specify which one. This was quite bothersome as all four of them were as menacing as her. Thus the easiest way to go about this was to make them decide among each other. He was just the messenger and could deliver the news to each one. The quartet was powerful but there also was a hierarchy, probably the weakest one would be forced to tend to this matter first…

…

“That’s enough, stop!”

‘When looking at it now, it really is a poor creature, who would do such a thing to a living being…’
The battle was over and the large turtle island was pulled closer to the shore. The beast that had its innards removed was making Zhang Dong feel bad. Without some of the strange contraptions inside this beast would be in constant pain. Normally he would put it out of its misery but they needed to go through what was on the inside to learn more about their enemies.

Besides them having no regard for life not much was known yet but before the next clash, they needed to discover their weakness. For this he had a tip already, in theory, there would be a way to tip the scales in his favor and do it almost instantly.

“Patriarch, here is the research data you requested on the subjects.”

He was temporarily at the base where Zhang Zhi resided. While he didn't want to involve himself in the main battle too much there was no problem in deciding on the next strategy. Knowing how the enemy operated was paramount to winning this battle. One interesting piece of information that could turn the tide was already discovered he just needed to use it.

“So brainwashing is out and so is soul contracts, then the only one that remains is… bloodline techniques.”

“That is correct Patriarch, all of these merpeople stem from the same bloodline and the control is probably still in place.”

“Then does this mean that their ancestor is alive?”

“That’s possible Patriarch, if not then someone with an extremely pure bloodline to their ancestor must be controlling them.”

“I see, good work.”

The information was passed to him through a jade and flowed into his head. It was surprising how much information his noggin could hold now. All the books he absorbed through the system were compartmentalized inside of him. It was as if he was a bottomless pit of knowledge at this point able to pull from his ever-growing library to analyze everything. Then there was also Bob who had access to the same library and more, through both of their effort they could quickly go through this data to see what needed to be done.

‘So I could be up against some kind of ancestral being that these fish people are all related to, as long as that ancestor is alive they can’t go against their bloodline. It can be a blessing and a curse depending on the situation…’

Bloodline techniques were something that beasts were known for. The beast needed to have a certain amount of power to use something like bloodlines. After spreading its seed it could share its knowledge and strength with its descendants. Its family line would be a lot stronger as it would tap into the ancestor's power but it was a double-edged sword. They could not go against the ancestral being and sometimes it could even affect their minds.

‘This explains why their brains melted when they were being interrogated, breaking a bloodline link isn’t easy and most of the time will just kill the host. Instead, the only way of breaking apart from such an ancestor is to achieve a similar level of power. I can’t be enhancing the enemy troops in hopes of getting more information though…’

This was troublesome, the demi-humans were already bad but these people could be even worse. They would probably do their utmost to defend their ancestor that was probably the Emperor of the sea creatures. The Demi-humans at least weren’t controlled and fled from battle on some occasions. Here on the other hand he needed to expect them to fight until death, taking prisoners was quite difficult if they didn’t care about their own well being.

There was however a light at the end of the tunnel. Even though it would be impossible to remove the brainwashing if he took care of the enemy Emperor then the battle would be over. The forces here were bred for battle and forcefully conscripted. They would probably revolt instantly and maybe go after each other when they were set free. He wouldn’t be surprised if they just abandoned everything and just ran.

‘There should also be some ways to at least momentarily disperse the bloodline curse, I might be even able to temporarily remove it without even killing their leader but for that, we will need better bloodline specimens.’

The warriors that were bred for battle weren’t worth that much, he needed some people from their group that were closer to their leader’s bloodline. These would either be their strongest masters or someone from the closest family. Considering that he was expecting a counter-attack soon the chance to capture one of these targets could present itself.

‘Time to play the waiting game instead, luckily the Azure Empress hasn’t noticed anything, or at least I hope.’

While the enemies scrambled in the background he would return to his workshop. Zhang Zhi received a new sword but Huo Qiang’s new weapon remained unfinished. Soon he would have a battle maniac on his side that gave him free experience points and the underwater creatures would be the target.

At first, he intended to make a new set of gauntlets but soon the idea was dropped. Qiang used his entire body for battle and not just his fists. Instead of a single piece of weaponry, he would fashion him a new suit of armor that would offer the brute newfound strength.

‘Of course, the color should be crimson and black.’

He chuckled to himself while teleporting to his workshop where the new piece of equipment was already partially made. With some finishing touches needed he hoped to be able to finish it before the next round with the fish people.

Chapter 564

“They really did follow through, this is becoming more and more predictable. I recon the other Emerald Phoenix Empire will be a stereotype as well.”

Zhang Dong’s hammer connected with a crimson piece of metal. The tool he was holding exuded a jolt of golden lightning that arced into the other item. The moment the electrical Qi seeped into the armor he was working on a few strange runes appeared that quickly faded away and left behind a shiny red outer shell.

While he was working on the new armament for Huo Qiang the system window to his faction was open. Through it and a few other monitors that were in his crafting abode, he could monitor everything.

During the last few weeks, they had continued attacking the turtle islands that were in range. All of them had identical numbers of defenders which they used to their advantage. The beasts that they were producing still needed some time to develop. It was the perfect time to take over more of these hatcheries with the exact same tactic and forces.

Through this second test, he saw one big flaw in these invaders, they were too similar to each other in every shape and form. They would constantly fight in the same fashion and use the exact same tactics. With so little variation in their troops, it was very easy to form a counterattack.

Even the leader that Zhang Zhi almost lost to turned into a predictable enemy that he could win against if following the correct tactic. So they continued to take over the turtles one by one and finally after the fifth one had fallen a new group appeared from the north.

‘Considering that they took so much time to react there could be a couple of reasons…’

He thought to himself while hammering away. One of the causes could be a lack of information flow between their forces. Perhaps a word about them being attacked took a long time to travel to the one making the decision. Another possibility was that they just weren’t prepared for this kind of resistance and just needed some time to form a proper army.

‘Another one could be distance, the ocean is vast it could be bigger than the whole empire, and no one has been able to chart it out even to this day… or the leader could be incompetent and just took their time.’

“Well, it doesn’t matter, they will fall one way or another… and this thing should be good to go.”

The armor was created and he looked at the shiny dark and crimson tint. He had been inspired by demon lords from works of fiction. Huo Qiang was in possession of a soul beast that looked like a devil so this was quite fitting. Instead of proper armor with angles, it looked more like a bodysuit with horns.

The metal it was made from had interesting properties. It was very resistant to attack and could channel fire energies quite well. However, its biggest strength was flexibility. When wearing it Huo Qiang should have no problem performing all his favorite moves, it would not constrict his movement at all while pushing him up another level.

“Hope this will be enough to take out the next opponent.”

Zhang Dong had decided to build up the people around him. Zhi was the first and now came Qiang. The biggest reason for doing this was that he had no other choice. The enemies that he was facing were large in number and the system he was using was focusing on the faction side of things.

His only real way of getting the system points was through his people and their approval rating. Zhi had gone through the leaders and also some other opponents since being given the new sword. Thanks to this he was sitting on a lot more spirit points than he expected.

He used those to upgrade this armor and also fully repair the Golden Palace which was now going to go into battle. Their opponents came in vast numbers that Zhi and his smaller army would never be able to contend with. They needed more firepower and the bastion that helped them against Wang Long and his forces would be what they needed.

‘Gramps has gotten used to calling the shots there, didn’t he start calling himself the Golden Elder or something now…’

Just as his forces continued to win more and more battles so did his name grow in fame. Not his original name Zhang Dong but more the Golden Dragon persona. Everyone wanted to be part of this popularity boost and his grandfather took this as a chance. Now he started wearing golden robes that were embroiled with golden dragons. It was as if he was the Golden Dragon and not Zhang Dong who continued to use the usual white robes that fit his hair color.

‘Well as long as he does his job right, he can call himself the Golden Dong for all I care.’

After shrugging to himself he grabbed the piece of armor and headed out. Now with the increase in spirit points, he didn’t feel as bad about teleporting all over the place. With more prestige units he could also use them as relay points as it did cost him less to get to them.

He had been using the feature a lot more lately as he needed to get to his bastion for work and monitoring purposes. Upgrading it to the next level wouldn’t take that much longer and perhaps the next iteration would allow him to combat these sea creatures. For the time being, it had one main flaw, it would lose a lot of its capabilities if it tried to go underwater.

The base of the new invaders would probably be somewhere underwater. There was a limit to how far the flying fortress’ armaments could shoot. It was fine when going against flying creatures and masters but the torpedoes he mass-produced in his crafting abode were better than the spirit cannons the castle had.

‘Need it to have some underwater feature and also increase the reactor size, it will need to hold its shields stead for the whole time if it bursts underwater people could die… have to consider the water pressure and how it will work on my people, not all of them had the body refining skills to last through it, quite troublesome.’

There were a lot of ways to improve his fortress, first of all, it needed to be waterproof. The problem was that the shields would react to stress by draining a lot of power. He needed to conserve power and only use the minimal amount that would keep the water away.

‘Best to make the shields react to force from the outside on the part that is getting attacked and not on the entire surface area.’

This problem could be alleviated with spirit points but his engineering department was also gaining some ground. Through this war, many geniuses arose from the ashes and were working with no rest to get everything going. Slowly but surely the people from his faction were becoming self-sufficient.

Perhaps in a couple of years, he would be able to just hang back and enjoy the fruit of his labor but for that to come he needed to first take these invaders out. Then the last enemy he needed to face would be the overseer but perhaps that battle wouldn’t need to be fought if he played his cards right.

She left him alive and didn’t destroy the world either, there was still a chance of a peaceful resolution. However this also depended on the purpose of it all, if the being that created this world turned out to be malicious in nature then he would need to endanger his life again.

“Qiang is probably impatient, I’ll head over to him first.”

For the time being, he was in the golden palace that was making its way from the demonic continent down to the northern shores. There it would rendezvous with Zhang Zhi’s forces and the rest of the elders that would be taking part in the coming battle. This time Huo Qiang needed to shine and for that, he needed to be promoted to a prestige unit.

“Senior brother, you came!”

“I did say I would, didn’t I?”

“That is true.”

“You do seem rather excited, Qiang.”

“Why wouldn’t I be excited? Words of what happened here reached the sect! You also mentioned a gift?”

Zhang Dong wanted to laugh when looking at Huo Qiang and how he was behaving. The man that was a head taller looked reminded him of his son whenever a new toy was promised. The new armor was mentioned in passing and everyone had seen Zhang Zhi ascend to a new level. New weapons and gaining a new realm were cultivators' biggest dreams and Qiang was still one at heart.

“You are really impatient… Hm, I was thinking of presenting it in front of the sect members, I’m sure it will give them something to strive for.”

“In front of the sect? Um… like the time with Zhang Zhi?”

“Yes, it would be just like that, you did your homework.”

Zhang Dong laughed to himself but Huo Qiang didn’t seem as happy for some reason. This was a bit strange, the usual loudmouth of the sect that liked to show off would normally jump at the opportunity. He would be getting a new powerful treasure and getting his cultivation potential enhanced, there was nothing more a cultivator could ask for. Everyone would see his moment of glory just like they saw Zhang Zhi ascend to new heights.

“Um, senior brother could we perhaps do that part in private instead?”

“That part?”

“You know… the thing you do when you infuse your knowledge into people…”

“Infuse knowledge?”

He thought back to the time with Zhang Zhi, Huo Qiang probably meant the moment he turned Zhi into a prestige unit. That point seemed to make him a bit uncomfortable for some reason. His memory was quite good so he thought back to it. Most of the time he was paying attention to the system screen and somewhat to the rest.

“Oh… you mean that… Fine, we can do that in private.”

“Thank you, senior brother, I knew you would understand!”

Huo Qiang quickly reverted to his cheerful self after knowing that he wouldn’t need to go through the strange procedure. Even now the recordings of that day were circulated among the sect. Zhang Zhi’s moaning face was plastered everywhere and strange stories started circulating among the younger female demographic. He did not wish to be part of them as that would have been truly a disgrace.

“Well, we are a bit short on time… there aren’t really that many people here so let's do it now.”

“Wait what….ohhhhh….”

The screams of a particular firey elder filled the corridors of the base. Not many people witnessed the spectacle but some rumors continued to spread even into the later years of the sect's existence…

Chapter 565

“Have you heard?”

“Heard what?”

“You know, the situation around the Patriarch and Grand Elder Qiang!”

“Shhh, do you want to get us in trouble!”

“But… their relationship… isn’t it interesting?”

“Well it certainly is but…”

“Hey what are you two doing, get back to work, we will be given our next assignment soon and Lord Qiang will also be participating!”

“Y-yes Senior sister!”

A pair of chatting women were interrupted by a superior. A particular nosy Patriarch also overheard their conversation. The place they were staying was a flag ship that was even larger than the old Argonaut and a new model with some enhancements. Currently, all of them were heading toward the open sea to confront their next enemy.

‘Why did these strange rumors start spreading about me and Qiang? Do girls like stuff like this or something? I guess guys fantasize about two girls getting it on, so it would be normal for the reverse? But me and Qiang…”

His mind wandered into a certain place but he quickly stopped as he did not want to imagine himself and Qiang hugging each other while naked. Instead, he focused back on the problem at hand which was the new armament for his wife and the next battle that was before Qiang and Zhi.

It was somewhat unfortunate that he had to split his attention between the two tasks but at the level, he was at it wasn’t that hard. While multitasking in his old world was nothing more than a myth in this, a person was actually able to split their mind and compartmentalize tasks. Thus he was able to focus on tidying up the design for his wife’s weapon and armor.

Zhi received a new weapon and was granted the middle stage of the nascent soul level. Huo Qiang was given a new armor that made him look like a demon lord and had been boosted to the late stage. His wife on the other hand would get both, a new set of clothes that she could wear and also a set of twin fans to go with it. This of course required more materials and spirit points which he hoped to receive after the confrontation between his forces and the underwater creatures finished.

For the past few weeks, he had been cooped up working and watching the screens while his forces expanded through the empire. It was quite the change of pace as he usually was the one going out on adventures to solve every problem. Now that his sect had been built up this much there was no need for that. Perhaps it was even possible to wait the hundred years out instead of putting himself in danger.
‘I don’t think my guys can handle the Emperor-level threats, Qiang would have to get to the great circle stage before even having a chance.’

Huo Qiang was his strongest combatant but even he was at most powerful enough to fight off one demi-human tribe leader at this point. Perhaps with time, he could boost him up to that level but even at it the chance of victory wouldn’t be great. Perhaps if he brought a full squadron of nascent soul masters and taught them some better attacking formations it would be possible.

‘Hm, if 100% would be the power level limit that can be achieved in this world then these emperors occupy around 90-95% and the rest is probably the wiggle room for a system holder.’

This was only in a one-on-one scenario as the Qi numbers could always be boosted above a hundred percent. This happened with his fight against Wang Long who himself was probably above Emperor-Level. At this point in time, he could not see himself losing to someone from that class.

Wang Long was stronger than the Demi-human Emperor and Zhang Dong had gone even further. This didn’t mean that he was invincible however if caught in a trap or against multiple strong opponents he would still lose. Only if he reached a new realm could he really become invincible.

‘Would be nice if I could get into one of those in-between realms, but this world’s setting erased them from existence.’

He got reminded of the Overseer that might have been in a stage between the immortal and nascent soul level. If he ever hoped to confront that being he would need to either bridge the gap or get some help. The current plan was to elevate his entire sect to such a level, as long as he could keep them from being frozen in time he might have a chance.

‘Oh, think they are confronting the leader…’

While thinking about the future he was brought back to the present. Huo Qiang was floating up in the sky and looking down at his next opponent. This battlefield was not very in favor of his flame Dao which didn’t contend with water as much. However with great enough knowledge and practice his flames could evaporate all liquids.

On one side his troops floated up in the sky on magnificent-looking mechanical ships. The materials used were all top notch and also acquired thanks to the current war. The demi-humans only cared about their hunt. While going through other sect territories they did raise the cities but they never cared about their treasures. After his forces swept through everything they uncovered a lot of raw resources that could be used.

While at first, he wasn’t sure what to do with all of them he was convinced by Zhang Jin and the others to just use them for the current war. These lands were now the sects as they had been reclaimed by combat which was a valid means in this world. The previous owners were either dead or fleed which by law relinquished their ownership over the materials. In short, mighty meant right and his forces could do with the land how they pleased until a stronger force arrived to conquer it.

He did not quite see it like this but he also believed that the sects and the old farts ruling them wouldn’t really use those resources well. With his people in power, he could at least put focus on rebuilding the cities and spreading wealth. The sects and old clans that ruled there would suffer but the general populace would see him in a favorable light.

With a high enough approval rating from each city he conquered, he would receive more and more system points which would further aid his conquest. He could not spend it on buying things from a system store but he could use them on improving the floating palace and for manufacturing purposes. Soon he would have an army outfitted with at least earth-grade treasures as a basis, no one from the old sects would ever be able to stand up to his faction.

‘The big question here is… will my dear old ‘brother’ just sit back and wait for me to outgrow him?’

After the last time, he left he didn’t hear a word from any Long Clan member. Long Qing who he remembered, felt like a person that didn’t take things all that seriously. This was probably brought on through a life of leisure. He was the strongest master in the empire, no one could compare to him, it wouldn’t be strange if he just accepted this as a fact. Perhaps he didn’t believe that Zhang Dong could ever overtake him but news of his conquests continued to flow into his ears. It wouldn’t be strange if with time he took the threat more seriously.

‘The big deciding factor is that wife of his, she can make him do whatever she wants, what if she decides to test me? She could probably whisper something in his ear and he would come running… and what should I do if he asks me to come to the Azure Palace, declining an invitation would be seen as disrespectful…’

While contemplating and working on Liena’s battle dress he could see the sea actually opening up. From within a man holding a much more robust-looking trident emerged. He was around the same height as Qiang and just as muscular. It was the enemy commander but his behavior was a bit strange considering the enemy forces usually used their many beasts as cannon fodder.

“I am Tritton, General of the Deep sees, trusted soldier of the Cerulean Empress! I will give you land dwellers a chance to lay down your weapons or surrender! “

The man in golden armor that looked like it consisted of fish scales spoke up. His voice was aided by his cultivation level which was quite tremendous. Zhang Dong and his forces had no reason to surrender but this at least gave them some information about their enemies. The name of their leader was revealed and surprisingly it belonged to a woman.

‘Cerulean Empress? I guess that’s just another shade of blue…’

Zhang Dong didn’t send any orders out as he watched. This was Huo Qiang’s and Zhang Zhi’s operation and the two had the power to make a decision. Naturally, the stronger of the two made his move first. A blazing ball of crimson flames started making the seawater evaporate. The hot steam turned the whole place into a sauna and forced a large chunk of the underwater beasts to scatter away in fright.

The massive spike in temperature was actually raising the temperature of the ocean to one that the enemy army wasn’t used to. They had probably gone through millions of years of evolution while living down in the cold dark deep sea. Their skin and scales was certainly not prepared to take in all the hot water.

“I am Huo Qiang of the United Element Sect, I challenge you to a duel Tritton! How about we decide everything through it, winner takes it all!”

‘Yeah, Qiang would do such a thing… but will the fish man agree? It wouldn’t be such a bad idea considering that his opponent is presumably only a late-stage cultivator…’

Even though with his armor on Huo Qiang could go beyond the late stage his enemy didn’t know that. His qi was at the late stage and so it would seem. People in this world weren’t really able to ascertain the quality of the Qi that someone was using. What they could tell is the unique signature a cultivator at a given level produced. This was also why a lot of Zhang Dong’s opponents thought he was much weaker than he actually was.

“You wish to challenge this Tritton? You must be a fool but I do not run from a challenge, first I will deal with you and then the rest of you will follow!”

‘I guess I couldn’t have asked for a better chance to see my product be tested…’

Both of the armies started inching away from each other while their leaders got ready for a brawl. Each side believed that their general would be victorious but no one quite knew at what cost.

Chapter 566

“When are you going to get home? You haven’t been seeing the children much lately, your son misses his father, you should come back when you can.”

“I know and you’re right as always my beautiful wife but I have to finish a few things, I’m sure you won’t be disappointed when I come back.”

“Daddy come back soon, I learned a new technique!”

“Oh, did you now? I’ll be sure to see it the next time.”

“Me too, I learned the basic feather steps already!”

“Oho? The feather steps? You are becoming quite the martial artist, soon you’ll be able to start learning the basics of the Thunder Movement Art.”

“Mhm.”

While Zhang Dong wasn’t home he could see his kids on the screen. This wasn’t the greatest way of speaking with his kids but it was better than nothing. Usually, he came back every few days to spend some time with them before returning to work. Making the advanced treasures took a while and required some precision. Some parts took days of concentration and Qi infusion and would actually require any lesser craftsmen months or years instead.

“Well, daddy needs to go, remember to listen to your mother and your senior sister and brother, I’ll be sure to see what they taught you when I return.”

Zhang Xiu and Jun were at the age that martial practice could be started. Xiu was already a qi condensation practitioner and would probably be able to reach the foundation establishment level in her early teens. Jun started a bit later but he was making quick progress that was even above his sister.

Previously he didn’t show that much promise as he did have a meek personality. Yet after Zhang Dong returned and showed off his power before his son, Jun started finally aspiring to become a cultivator. It was a strange feeling to have a son that was looking up to him this much. To not disappoint him he needed to also strive for excellence and pave a path he could follow.

He wanted nothing more than to get back to his home and relax but for now, he needed to watch over his troops. The battle between Huo Qiang and the man called Tritton was about to start as they were speaking. After saying his goodbyes the image of his family vanished and was replaced by two burly men looking at each other with victory in their eyes. It seemed that these two were somewhat similar to each other as he did not expect this king of resolution to be possible.

‘Could it be possible to reason with them if people like this exist?’

Tritton the enemy general kind of went against what they had unearthed about their new opponents. They were supposed to be nothing but drones, some kind of mass-produced soldiers that needed to follow orders. However this person was different, he seemed to go against the grain.

‘Or was this an order from their leader? Maybe they want to test our strongest fighters before committing to a full assault?’

That was also a possibility and danger could be lurking around. Perhaps after this fight is over another general would peek their head out. Huo Qiang was strong but he was somewhere around the level of this Tritton. The fight could go either way at this point and they were fighting in an area with a lot of water qi.

Normally this would be an instant loss to Qiang as his fire techniques would lose a lot of their effects here. There was one ace in the hole though, Zhang Dong’s prestige unit system that Qiang was now part of. Just like he had shared his holy Dao with Zhi to add to his power the same was given to his new retainer.

“You think that this watery wall will help you to win? Think again!”

Huo Qiang roared out while his body was shrouded in a purple haze. After the battle started the opponent dived underwater to start pelting Qiang with watery serpents. To counter this the new Dao that he was capable of using, was utilized. Just as a moon could cause water to shift away, so could the gravitational Dao be used here. The water didn’t need to be evaporated away to make way, instead he could create a large sphere of energy that wouldn’t let any water close.

‘That’s it, get in close range and finish it.’

The plan was quite rudimentary, Huo Qiang’s biggest strength was his sturdy body and powerful fists. He needed to close the gap and take the fight to Tritton who was utilizing the vast quantity of water around him to douse Qiang’s flames. When close to the gravitational shield that pushed things away, those flames could not be put out.

This made the fight a bit hard to follow as both of the combatants dived underwater. Tritton probably reasoned that he would be given a simple victory. Fighting a fire user underwater usually meant that the water user would win. However, when Qiang dived under a large hundred-meter area around his body pushed all the water away. It looked as if he was in some kind of giant air bubble.

This of course took Tritton as a surprise as even the water serpents that he produced with the trident couldn’t pierce through this defensive measure. The would-be somewhat able to enter it but would then be dispersed by the immense heat inside along with gravity. It was as if the inside was a star, immensely hot and filled with powerful gravitational forces.

Huo Qiang was working against the clock though. Even though the technique he was using was powerful it had a large weakness. It burned through a lot of Qi and sooner or later would collapse. Before it did he needed to get in close range to deliver a critical strike. Tritton on the other hand seemed to know this and was keeping his distance. The way he moved through the water was astonishing, a speed that Qiang could hardly keep up.

“Fight me you coward!”

“I Tritton am no coward!”

“Then stop squiggling around.”

“I Tritton am also no idiot.”

The quick exchange between the two masters could not really be heard by anyone else besides Zhang Dong that was listening in. He was ready to teleport there on the spot if anything happened to his friend but he wanted to keep his presence hidden for now. If there really was a trap then he would rather have the other side spring it first. If there were other generals waiting around then it would be better to capture them together. If they began escaping even Zhang Dong wouldn’t be able to catch them underwater.

‘Hm, I guess it’s about time that he used it now…’

Just as he thought, Qiang firstly tried to achieve victory through his own power. The armor that was given to him was already equipped but he wasn’t really utilizing it well. Only when he realized that his enemy wouldn’t engage in close-range combat did he use his trump card.

His soul beast which had been right with him through the entire chase started glowing red. It turned into something that looked like a miniature sun and surrounded his entire body. When the armor was soaked in all of this pure fire energy it began reacting. Various glowing runes appeared on it and started sucking in all of this energy.

The boost in energy was clear and Qiang’s power level shot up to a level never seen before. Everyone from the United Element Sect held their breaths as they saw a giant pillar of flames erupt from the murky depths. It spun around like a twister and caused a giant part of the sea to spread apart instantly.

“There you are, you will not escape!”

Tritton was quite surprised as the watery pathways that he used to evade his enemy were not there anymore. With so many fire Qi everywhere he was having trouble with controlling all the water Qi. This slowed him down quite a bit and allowed Qiang to finally close the distance. His trusted trident was used as protection from the giant dark crimson fist that connected with it.

The merman’s entire body felt like it was evaporating before him. He had never felt something like this before, two energy types that opposed each other clashed within his body and he caught up blood. His mind was telling him to instantly flee but he wasn’t sure if he could. The only thing left was pushing his opponent away with all the might he had left.

‘They are going at it… didn’t expect that General to be able to last through it… that trident must be of better quality than the rest…’

If Qiang was going against the merman that Zhang Zhi faced then it would have ended right there. The weapons that these fishermen held were very similar to each other but they certainly did vary in quality. Perhaps the trident Tritton was using was one of the original ones while the other ones were just lesser replicas.

It was quite interesting to see his own armaments going up against other treasured items. The battle couldn’t last forever and just like Zhi had used a special prestige class skill to win the first encounter with a merman, so would Huo Qiang.

The illusory image of Zhang Dong appeared behind Qiang and augmented his fists striking power even further. There was no possible way for this general to last through it, the various protective measures and treasures he activated to protect himself from death broke almost instantly. The massive fist connected with his chin and threw him right up into the air with half his face missing from the impact.

This victory didn’t come easily, however almost instantly after the hit went through Qiang’s body started spasming around. He had burned through far too much Qi in a short time frame. Even though he was in a world of pain his fist was raised high, he could not show weaknesses in front of his allies and enemies. The victory needed to be burned into both sides, they needed to know that the United Element Sect elders could not be messed with.

“Long live the Sect!”

He shouted and everyone that was watching on top of the ships repeated everything. The bout was won and the enemy general was flying through the air while half-dead. The moment of joy was short lived though as a strange sight unfolded before everyone.

The merman that was a powerful cultivator at the great circle instantly shriveled up and turned into a fish. His trident, on the other hand, stopped in mid-air, turned itself toward the sea, and shot off as if it was a rocket. The speed was quite tremendous and not something Qiang could catch up to after draining his energies this much.

‘Was the trident the true source of power and not the merman?’

Zhang Dong pondered this possibility, the item was long gone before his troops could catch up but the victory was there. Now the only thing that he was thinking was if those fish people would honor the deal or not…